Okay. Uh hello everyone. Um and welcome
好的，大家好，欢迎。
Okay. Uh hello everyone. Um and welcome to our PyTorch uh 2.14
好的，大家好，欢迎参加我们的 PyTorch 2.14……
to our PyTorch uh 2.14
参加我们的 PyTorch 2.14……
to our PyTorch uh 2.14 uh release live uh Q&A. Um uh let me
参加我们的 PyTorch 2.14 版本发布直播问答。我先……
uh release live uh Q&A. Um uh let me
版本发布直播问答。我先……
uh release live uh Q&A. Um uh let me scroll back up to my uh my comments
版本发布直播问答。我先往上翻找我的评论。
scroll back up to my uh my comments
往上翻找我的评论。
scroll back up to my uh my comments here. Um this session will start with uh
往上翻找我的评论。这场活动将先……
here. Um this session will start with uh
这场活动将先……
here. Um this session will start with uh with introducing our experts um and then
这场活动将先介绍我们的专家，然后……
with introducing our experts um and then
先介绍我们的专家，然后……
with introducing our experts um and then a short overview of the key updates in
先介绍我们的专家，然后简要介绍……
a short overview of the key updates in
简要介绍主要更新……
a short overview of the key updates in PyTorch uh 21.14 followed by um the fun
简要介绍 PyTorch 21.14 的主要更新，然后进入有趣的……
PyTorch uh 21.14 followed by um the fun
PyTorch 21.14，接下来是有趣的……
PyTorch uh 21.14 followed by um the fun part which is an open Q&A covering your
PyTorch 21.14，接下来是开放问答，回答大家关于……
part which is an open Q&A covering your
接下来是开放问答，回答大家关于……
part which is an open Q&A covering your questions about this release. Um first
回答大家关于这次发布的问题。首先……
questions about this release. Um first
关于这次发布的问题。首先……
questions about this release. Um first I'll introduce myself. I'm I'm Chris
关于这次发布的问题。先介绍一下我自己，我是 Chris……
I'll introduce myself. I'm I'm Chris
我先介绍一下自己，我是 Chris……
I'll introduce myself. I'm I'm Chris Scott. I'm your moderator for today's
我先介绍一下自己，我是 Chris Scott，今天的主持人。
Scott. I'm your moderator for today's
Scott，今天由我主持……
Scott. I'm your moderator for today's webinar. I've been involved in the
Scott，今天由我主持这场线上研讨会。我一直参与……
webinar. I've been involved in the
这场线上研讨会。我一直参与……
webinar. I've been involved in the PyTorch community for about eight years
这场线上研讨会。我参与 PyTorch 社区已有大约八年。
PyTorch community for about eight years
我参与 PyTorch 社区已有大约八年。
PyTorch community for about eight years focusing on focusing on product and
我参与 PyTorch 社区已有大约八年，主要关注产品和……
focusing on focusing on product and
主要关注产品和……
focusing on focusing on product and marketing uh type angles. Um these days
主要关注产品和市场营销方面。现在……
marketing uh type angles. Um these days
市场营销方面。现在……
marketing uh type angles. Um these days I run a consulting practice uh focusing
市场营销方面。现在我经营一家咨询机构，专注于……
I run a consulting practice uh focusing
我经营一家咨询机构，专注于……
I run a consulting practice uh focusing on emerging AI technologies and I'm
我经营一家咨询机构，专注于新兴 AI 技术，也……
on emerging AI technologies and I'm
专注于新兴 AI 技术，也……
on emerging AI technologies and I'm delighted to welcome a panel of three
专注于新兴 AI 技术。我很高兴欢迎三位……
delighted to welcome a panel of three
很高兴欢迎三位……
delighted to welcome a panel of three absolute PyTorch experts. We have Andre
很高兴欢迎三位顶尖的 PyTorch 专家。我们请来了 Andre……
absolute PyTorch experts. We have Andre
顶尖的 PyTorch 专家。我们请来了 Andre……
absolute PyTorch experts. We have Andre Talman uh Joe Spizac and Nikita Schulga.
顶尖的 PyTorch 专家：Andre Talman、Joe Spizac 和 Nikita Schulga。
Talman uh Joe Spizac and Nikita Schulga.
他们是 Talman、Joe Spizac 和 Nikita Schulga。
Talman uh Joe Spizac and Nikita Schulga. Uh and they're here to answer your
Talman、Joe Spizac 和 Nikita Schulga。他们会回答大家的……
Uh and they're here to answer your
他们会回答大家的……
Uh and they're here to answer your questions about PyTorch and generally to
他们会回答大家关于 PyTorch 的问题，也会……
questions about PyTorch and generally to
关于 PyTorch 的问题，也会……
questions about PyTorch and generally to you know spread the word. Um so Andre is
回答有关 PyTorch 的问题，也借此介绍 PyTorch。Andre 是……
you know spread the word. Um so Andre is
也借此介绍 PyTorch。Andre 是……
you know spread the word. Um so Andre is a release engineer in the PyTorch Dev
也借此介绍 PyTorch。Andre 是 PyTorch Dev 团队的发布工程师。
a release engineer in the PyTorch Dev
PyTorch Dev 团队的发布工程师。
a release engineer in the PyTorch Dev Info team here at Meta or at Meta. I'm
他是 Meta 的 PyTorch Dev Info 团队发布工程师。我……
Info team here at Meta or at Meta. I'm
Meta 的信息团队，或者说在 Meta。我……
Info team here at Meta or at Meta. I'm sorry. I used to be at Meta so that just
Meta 的信息团队，或者说在 Meta。抱歉，我以前在 Meta 工作，所以……
sorry. I used to be at Meta so that just
抱歉，我以前在 Meta 工作，所以……
sorry. I used to be at Meta so that just rolls off my tongue. It's no longer
抱歉，我以前在 Meta 工作，所以顺口就这么说了。现在已经不是……
rolls off my tongue. It's no longer
顺口就这么说了。现在已经不是……
rolls off my tongue. It's no longer accurate. at Meta. Uh he drives uh the
顺口就这么说了。现在这么说已经不准确了。他在 Meta 负责……
accurate. at Meta. Uh he drives uh the
这么说已经不准确了。他在 Meta 负责……
accurate. at Meta. Uh he drives uh the release process and keeps uh the
这么说已经不准确了。他在 Meta 负责发布流程，并让……
release process and keeps uh the
发布流程，并让……
release process and keeps uh the continuous integration and continuous
发布流程，并让持续集成和持续……
continuous integration and continuous
持续集成和持续……
continuous integration and continuous development infrastructure humming. Uh
持续集成和持续开发的基础设施顺畅运转。
development infrastructure humming. Uh
开发基础设施顺畅运转。
development infrastructure humming. Uh Joe um is the uh VP of product uh and
开发基础设施顺畅运转。Joe 是产品副总裁，也是……
Joe um is the uh VP of product uh and
Joe 是产品副总裁，也是……
Joe um is the uh VP of product uh and head of open source at Reflection AI. Uh
Joe 是 Reflection AI 的产品副总裁兼开源负责人。
head of open source at Reflection AI. Uh
Reflection AI 的开源负责人。
head of open source at Reflection AI. Uh he's one of the PyTorch core maintainers
Reflection AI 的开源负责人。他也是 PyTorch 核心维护者之一。
he's one of the PyTorch core maintainers
他是 PyTorch 核心维护者之一。
he's one of the PyTorch core maintainers and among the strongest advocates that I
他是 PyTorch 核心维护者之一，也是我认识的最坚定的倡导者之一，
and among the strongest advocates that I
也是我认识的最坚定的倡导者之一，
and among the strongest advocates that I know of for open source, open models and
也是我认识的最坚定的倡导者之一，倡导开源、开放模型，以及……
know of for open source, open models and
倡导开源、开放模型，以及……
know of for open source, open models and open infrastructure across the AI
倡导在整个 AI 社区推广开源、开放模型和开放基础设施。
open infrastructure across the AI
在整个 AI 社区推广开放基础设施。
open infrastructure across the AI community. Uh and always a fun uh fun
在整个 AI 社区推广开放基础设施。而且听他说话总是很有意思。
community. Uh and always a fun uh fun
在社区里。而且听他说话总是很有意思。
community. Uh and always a fun uh fun person to to hear from. Nikita is a
在社区里。而且听他说话总是很有意思。Nikita 是……
person to to hear from. Nikita is a
听他说话总是很有意思。Nikita 是……
person to to hear from. Nikita is a PyTorch core maintainer uh and a key
听他说话总是很有意思。Nikita 是 PyTorch 核心维护者，也是重要的……
PyTorch core maintainer uh and a key
PyTorch 核心维护者，也是重要的……
PyTorch core maintainer uh and a key contributor and reviewer really active
PyTorch 核心维护者，也是重要的贡献者和审查者，活跃于……
contributor and reviewer really active
贡献者和审查者，活跃于……
contributor and reviewer really active across just a bunch of areas uh in in
贡献者和审查者，在许多领域都很活跃，包括……
across just a bunch of areas uh in in
在许多领域都很活跃，包括……
across just a bunch of areas uh in in the core area of PyTorch. So you
在许多领域都很活跃，包括 PyTorch 的核心领域。所以你……
the core area of PyTorch. So you
PyTorch 的核心领域。所以你……
the core area of PyTorch. So you probably see his name on on lots of
PyTorch 的核心领域。所以你可能在很多地方都见过他的名字。
probably see his name on on lots of
可能在很多地方都见过他的名字。
probably see his name on on lots of things. Um I'll give a brief overview
可能在很多地方都见过他的名字。我先简要介绍一下……
things. Um I'll give a brief overview
很多地方都见过他的名字。我先简要介绍一下……
things. Um I'll give a brief overview now in a in a moment here about the
很多地方都见过他的名字。接下来我会简要介绍一下……
now in a in a moment here about the
接下来我会简要介绍一下……
now in a in a moment here about the release uh for a few minutes and I'm
接下来我会花几分钟简要介绍这次发布，我也……
release uh for a few minutes and I'm
花几分钟介绍这次发布，我也……
release uh for a few minutes and I'm would encourage you if you're in the in
花几分钟介绍这次发布。我建议现场的各位……
would encourage you if you're in the in
我建议现场的各位……
would encourage you if you're in the in the audience uh to to use that time to
我建议现场的各位听众利用这段时间……
the audience uh to to use that time to
各位听众利用这段时间……
the audience uh to to use that time to think about what questions you might
各位听众可以利用这段时间想想自己有什么问题。
think about what questions you might
想想你可能有什么问题。
think about what questions you might have um for our experts. uh you can put
想想有什么问题想问我们的专家。你可以把问题发到……
have um for our experts. uh you can put
想问专家的问题，你可以发到……
have um for our experts. uh you can put those in LinkedIn and and the and the
想问专家的问题，可以发到 LinkedIn 和……
those in LinkedIn and and the and the
把问题发到 LinkedIn 和……
those in LinkedIn and and the and the YouTube tools. Uh we'll uh we'll cue
把问题发到 LinkedIn 和 YouTube 的提问工具。我们会把问题……
YouTube tools. Uh we'll uh we'll cue
通过 YouTube 的提问工具。我们会把问题……
YouTube tools. Uh we'll uh we'll cue them up for our experts to answer. We
通过 YouTube 的提问工具。我们会把问题交给专家回答。我们……
them up for our experts to answer. We
交给专家回答。我们……
them up for our experts to answer. We will we'll also have a few seed
交给专家回答。我们也准备了几个引导性问题……
will we'll also have a few seed
我们也准备了几个引导性问题……
will we'll also have a few seed questions up uh on our you know prepared
我们也事先准备了几个引导性问题……
questions up uh on our you know prepared
事先准备了一些问题……
questions up uh on our you know prepared uh based on ongoing community
事先准备了一些问题，依据的是社区正在进行的……
uh based on ongoing community
依据社区正在进行的……
uh based on ongoing community discussions which you can join by uh
依据社区正在进行的讨论，你也可以参与……
discussions which you can join by uh
这些讨论，你也可以通过……参与。
discussions which you can join by uh looking them up in uh discuss.pytor.org
这些讨论，你可以在 discuss.pytor.org 上找到并参与。
looking them up in uh discuss.pytor.org
到 discuss.pytor.org 查找这些讨论。
looking them up in uh discuss.pytor.org and dev discuss.pytor.org or hopping on
可以到 discuss.pytor.org 和 dev discuss.pytor.org 查找，或加入……
and dev discuss.pytor.org or hopping on
也可以到 dev discuss.pytor.org，或加入……
and dev discuss.pytor.org or hopping on PyTorch Slack. Um those are just here to
也可以到 dev discuss.pytor.org，或加入 PyTorch Slack。这些问题只是为了……
PyTorch Slack. Um those are just here to
加入 PyTorch Slack。这些问题只是为了……
PyTorch Slack. Um those are just here to to kind of keep things flowing and make
加入 PyTorch Slack。这些问题只是为了让讨论顺畅进行，并确保……
to kind of keep things flowing and make
让讨论顺畅进行，并确保……
to kind of keep things flowing and make sure we touch on some important topics
让讨论顺畅进行，确保我们谈到一些重要话题。
sure we touch on some important topics
确保我们谈到一些重要话题。
sure we touch on some important topics but it's more fun really to answer the
确保谈到一些重要话题，但回答……其实更有意思。
but it's more fun really to answer the
但回答……其实更有意思。
but it's more fun really to answer the questions that come in from the
但回答来自……的问题其实更有意思。
questions that come in from the
来自……的问题。
questions that come in from the community. So, please don't be shy.
社区提出的问题。所以请大家踊跃提问。
community. So, please don't be shy.
community. So, please don't be shy. Okay, so an overview of the release. Uh,
社区提出的问题。所以请大家踊跃提问。好，下面概览一下这次发布。
Okay, so an overview of the release. Uh,
好，下面概览一下这次发布。
Okay, so an overview of the release. Uh, this actually seems to me to be a pretty
好，下面概览一下这次发布。我觉得这次发布相当……
this actually seems to me to be a pretty
我觉得这次发布相当……
this actually seems to me to be a pretty significant release despite, you know,
我觉得这次发布相当重要，尽管……
significant release despite, you know,
这次发布相当重要，尽管……
significant release despite, you know, the the numbering 21.14 makes it seem
这次发布相当重要，尽管 21.14 这个版本号让它看起来……
the the numbering 21.14 makes it seem
21.14 这个版本号让它看起来……
the the numbering 21.14 makes it seem small, but it's not really, I don't
21.14 这个版本号让它显得规模不大，但我觉得实际并非如此……
small, but it's not really, I don't
看起来规模不大，但我觉得实际并非如此……
small, but it's not really, I don't think, at all. Um, uh, it really moves
看起来规模不大，但我觉得完全不是这样。它确实推动了……
think, at all. Um, uh, it really moves
我觉得完全不是这样。它确实推动了……
think, at all. Um, uh, it really moves the needle on like compilation, uh, with
我觉得完全不是这样。它确实推动了编译方面的进展，带来了……
the needle on like compilation, uh, with
推动了编译方面的进展，带来了……
the needle on like compilation, uh, with some new concepts in compilation, fault
推动了编译方面的进展，涉及编译方面的新概念、容错……
some new concepts in compilation, fault
编译方面的一些新概念，以及容错……
some new concepts in compilation, fault tolerance, uh, and, uh, platform
编译方面的一些新概念、容错，以及平台方面的……
tolerance, uh, and, uh, platform
容错，还有平台
tolerance, uh, and, uh, platform support. As always, it's a huge
容错和平台支持。一如既往，这是一项庞大的
support. As always, it's a huge
支持。一如既往，这是一项庞大的
support. As always, it's a huge community left with almost 3,000 commits
支持。一如既往，社区贡献巨大，提交近3000次
community left with almost 3,000 commits
社区贡献巨大，提交近3000次
community left with almost 3,000 commits from almost 500 uh different uh
社区贡献巨大，提交近3000次，来自近500位
from almost 500 uh different uh
来自近500位不同的
from almost 500 uh different uh contributors, 487 this year or this
来自近500位贡献者，这次是487位
contributors, 487 this year or this
贡献者，这次是487位
contributors, 487 this year or this time. Um they made improvements all
贡献者，这次是487位。他们做了各方面的改进
time. Um they made improvements all
这次，他们做了各方面的改进
time. Um they made improvements all across PyTorch and I encourage folks to
这次，他们改进了PyTorch的方方面面。我也鼓励大家
across PyTorch and I encourage folks to
涉及PyTorch的方方面面。我也鼓励大家
across PyTorch and I encourage folks to look at the release release blog and the
涉及PyTorch的方方面面。我也鼓励大家查看发布博客和
look at the release release blog and the
查看发布博客和
look at the release release blog and the release notes for uh for more detail to
查看发布博客和发行说明，了解更多详情
release notes for uh for more detail to
发行说明里有更多详情
release notes for uh for more detail to supplement this uh this Q&A. A few of
发行说明里有更多详情，可补充这场问答。其中一些
supplement this uh this Q&A. A few of
可作为这场问答的补充。其中一些
supplement this uh this Q&A. A few of the most spec uh most significant
可作为这场问答的补充。其中最重要的几项
the most spec uh most significant
最重要的几项
the most spec uh most significant changes this time around are uh NV gym
本次最重要的变化包括NVGEMM
changes this time around are uh NV gym
本次变化包括NVGEMM
changes this time around are uh NV gym from Nvidia brings cute DSL uh generated
本次变化包括：NVIDIA的NVGEMM将CuTeDSL生成的
from Nvidia brings cute DSL uh generated
NVIDIA的NVGEMM将CuTeDSL生成的
from Nvidia brings cute DSL uh generated cutless kernels to inductor. So this is
NVIDIA的NVGEMM将CuTeDSL生成的CUTLASS内核引入Inductor。这是
cutless kernels to inductor. So this is
CUTLASS内核引入Inductor。这是
cutless kernels to inductor. So this is like a performance uh improvement uh for
CUTLASS内核引入Inductor。这能提升
like a performance uh improvement uh for
这能提升
like a performance uh improvement uh for uh modern uh GPUs uh with epilog fusion
这能提升现代GPU的性能，并支持尾处理融合
uh modern uh GPUs uh with epilog fusion
现代GPU上的尾处理融合
uh modern uh GPUs uh with epilog fusion scaled uh NV FP4 gems and grouped uh
现代GPU上的尾处理融合、缩放型NVFP4 GEMM和分组
scaled uh NV FP4 gems and grouped uh
缩放型NVFP4 GEMM和分组
scaled uh NV FP4 gems and grouped uh reduction epilogues autotuned alongside
缩放型NVFP4 GEMM和分组归约尾处理，并与
reduction epilogues autotuned alongside
归约尾处理，并与
reduction epilogues autotuned alongside Triton and ATIN.
归约尾处理，并与Triton和ATen一起自动调优。
Triton and ATIN.
与Triton和ATen一起自动调优。
Triton and ATIN. We have a preview of our uh some really
与Triton和ATen一起自动调优。我们还预览了
We have a preview of our uh some really
我们还预览了
We have a preview of our uh some really deep changes in our in our um uh
我们还预览了分布式后端的一些重大改动
deep changes in our in our um uh
分布式后端的一些重大改动
deep changes in our in our um uh distributed backend. So rewritten nickel
分布式后端的一些重大改动：重写的NCCL
distributed backend. So rewritten nickel
分布式后端：重写的NCCL
distributed backend. So rewritten nickel backend for PyTorch. This is ported from
分布式后端：为PyTorch重写的NCCL后端，移植自
backend for PyTorch. This is ported from
PyTorch的NCCL后端，移植自
backend for PyTorch. This is ported from sort of a an area where we've been doing
PyTorch的NCCL后端，移植自我们一直在做实验的
sort of a an area where we've been doing
我们一直在做实验的
sort of a an area where we've been doing some experimentation called torchcoms
我们一直在做实验的项目叫torchcomms
some experimentation called torchcoms
我们实验的项目叫torchcomms
some experimentation called torchcoms implementing uh the full collective
我们实验的项目叫torchcomms，它实现了完整的集合通信接口
implementing uh the full collective
实现完整的集合通信功能
implementing uh the full collective contract uh with non-blocking
实现完整的集合通信接口，包括非阻塞通信
contract uh with non-blocking
包括非阻塞通信的接口
contract uh with non-blocking communication communicators and advanced
包括非阻塞通信、通信器和高级功能的接口
communication communicators and advanced
通信、通信器和高级功能
communication communicators and advanced features such as fault tolerance and
通信、通信器，以及容错等高级功能
features such as fault tolerance and
容错等功能
features such as fault tolerance and windows uh designed as drag and drop
容错和窗口等功能，设计成可直接替换
windows uh designed as drag and drop
窗口，设计成可直接替换
windows uh designed as drag and drop replacements for existing nickel C10
窗口，设计成可直接替换现有的 NCCL C10
replacements for existing nickel C10
替换现有的 NCCL C10
replacements for existing nickel C10 backend. Um, so this I think is really
替换现有的 NCCL C10 后端。我觉得这确实
backend. Um, so this I think is really
后端。我觉得这确实
backend. Um, so this I think is really uh the fault tolerance I think is going
后端。我觉得容错确实会
uh the fault tolerance I think is going
我觉得容错会
uh the fault tolerance I think is going to be is going to be a big uh thing as
我觉得容错将是一件大事
to be is going to be a big uh thing as
将是一件大事
to be is going to be a big uh thing as we uh go forward and I think this is
随着我们继续推进，这将是一件大事，我觉得这
we uh go forward and I think this is
随着我们继续推进，我觉得这
we uh go forward and I think this is really laying really strong uh uh
随着我们继续推进，我觉得这确实打下了坚实的
really laying really strong uh uh
确实打下了坚实的
really laying really strong uh uh foundations for that. Uh fault tolerance
确实为此打下了坚实基础。容错
foundations for that. Uh fault tolerance
为此打下了基础。容错
foundations for that. Uh fault tolerance also becomes a first class citizen in
为此打下了基础。容错也成为
also becomes a first class citizen in
也成为一项核心能力
also becomes a first class citizen in the C10 uh D uh with in place process
也成为 c10d 的一项核心能力，包括原地进程
the C10 uh D uh with in place process
c10d 中的原地进程
the C10 uh D uh with in place process group reconfiguration, one-sided RMA
c10d 中的原地进程组重配置、单侧 RMA
group reconfiguration, one-sided RMA
进程组重配置、单侧 RMA
group reconfiguration, one-sided RMA windows and a flight recorder that works
进程组重配置、单侧 RMA 窗口，以及一个适用于
windows and a flight recorder that works
RMA 窗口，以及一个适用于
windows and a flight recorder that works for any backend rather than only for
RMA 窗口，以及一个适用于任何后端的飞行记录器
for any backend rather than only for
适用于任何后端，而不只是
for any backend rather than only for nickel. Uh Apple silicon also got a lot
适用于任何后端，而不只是 NCCL。Apple 芯片也增加了许多
nickel. Uh Apple silicon also got a lot
NCCL。Apple 芯片也增加了许多
nickel. Uh Apple silicon also got a lot more u functionality with more native
NCCL。Apple 芯片也增加了更多功能，支持更多原生
more u functionality with more native
更多功能，支持更多原生
more u functionality with more native linear uh algebra operators including ig
更多功能，支持更多原生线性代数算子，包括 eig
linear uh algebra operators including ig
线性代数算子，包括 eig
linear uh algebra operators including ig uh QR and Cholski alongside uh fast
线性代数算子，包括 eig、QR 和 Cholesky，以及快速
uh QR and Cholski alongside uh fast
QR 和 Cholesky，以及快速
uh QR and Cholski alongside uh fast production operations and further uh uh
QR 和 Cholesky，以及快速归约运算和更多
production operations and further uh uh
归约运算和更多
production operations and further uh uh MPS graph to metal uh kernel migrations.
归约运算，以及将更多 MPSGraph 算子迁移为 Metal 内核。
MPS graph to metal uh kernel migrations.
将 MPSGraph 算子迁移为 Metal 内核。
MPS graph to metal uh kernel migrations. So performance improvements uh in many
将 MPSGraph 算子迁移为 Metal 内核。因此，很多地方的性能都有提升
So performance improvements uh in many
因此，很多地方的性能都有提升
So performance improvements uh in many places on Apple um torch switch
因此，Apple 平台很多地方的性能都有提升。torch.switch
places on Apple um torch switch
Apple 平台的性能提升，以及 torch.switch
places on Apple um torch switch generalize uh the torch cond to
Apple 平台的性能提升。torch.switch 将 torch.cond 泛化为
generalize uh the torch cond to
把 torch.cond 扩展为
generalize uh the torch cond to multi-way branching. So this is like a
把 torch.cond 扩展为多路分支。这就像一种
multi-way branching. So this is like a
多路分支。这就像一种
multi-way branching. So this is like a language improvement in the way you can
多路分支。这是一种语言层面的改进，让你能
language improvement in the way you can
语言层面的改进，让你能
language improvement in the way you can think about um uh uh expressing uh
语言层面的改进，让你能思考如何表达
think about um uh uh expressing uh
思考如何表达
think about um uh uh expressing uh things that used to cause graph breaks
思考如何表达那些过去会导致计算图中断的写法
things that used to cause graph breaks
那些过去会导致计算图中断的写法
things that used to cause graph breaks in PyTorch. Uh with torch while loop uh
那些过去会导致 PyTorch 计算图中断的写法。借助 torch.while_loop
in PyTorch. Uh with torch while loop uh
在 PyTorch 中。借助 torch.while_loop
in PyTorch. Uh with torch while loop uh also can now be captured in a CUDA
在 PyTorch 中，torch.while_loop 现在也能被 CUDA 图捕获
also can now be captured in a CUDA
现在也能被 CUDA 图捕获
also can now be captured in a CUDA graph. Um declarative dynamic shapes uh
现在也能被 CUDA Graph 捕获。声明式动态形状
graph. Um declarative dynamic shapes uh
CUDA Graph。声明式动态形状
graph. Um declarative dynamic shapes uh are also uh added. This is another sort
CUDA Graph。声明式动态形状也已加入。这是另一种
are also uh added. This is another sort
也已加入。这是另一种
are also uh added. This is another sort of language feature. There's now a
也已加入。这是另一种语言特性。现在有了
of language feature. There's now a
语言特性。现在有了
of language feature. There's now a dynamic spec uh uh decorator at dynamic
语言特性。现在有了 @dynamic_spec 装饰器
dynamic spec uh uh decorator at dynamic
@dynamic_spec 装饰器
dynamic spec uh uh decorator at dynamic spec uh which is shared across torch
@dynamic_spec 装饰器，可供 torch 系列工具共用
spec uh which is shared across torch
@dynamic_spec 可供 torch 系列工具共用
spec uh which is shared across torch compile torch export and make.fx FX
@dynamic_spec 可供 torch.compile、torch.export 和 make_fx 共用
compile torch export and make.fx FX
torch.compile、torch.export 和 make_fx
compile torch export and make.fx FX experimental torch compiler uh support
torch.compile、torch.export 和 make_fx。实验性的 torch.compile 支持
experimental torch compiler uh support
实验性的 torch.compile 支持
experimental torch compiler uh support is also available for complex value
torch.compile 也开始试验性支持复数值
is also available for complex value
也支持复数值
is also available for complex value tensors. Uh this is an opt-in thing uh
也支持复数值张量。这项功能需主动启用
tensors. Uh this is an opt-in thing uh
张量。这项功能需主动启用
tensors. Uh this is an opt-in thing uh which decomposes uh supported complex
张量。这项功能需主动启用，会将受支持的复数
which decomposes uh supported complex
会将受支持的复数
which decomposes uh supported complex operations into real and imaginary
会将受支持的复数运算分解为实部和虚部
operations into real and imaginary
运算分解为实部和虚部
operations into real and imaginary computations enabling compiler backends
运算分解为实部和虚部的计算，让编译器后端
computations enabling compiler backends
计算，让编译器后端
computations enabling compiler backends to optimize complex number workloads
计算，让编译器后端优化复数计算任务
to optimize complex number workloads
优化复数计算任务
to optimize complex number workloads which are super important for science
优化复数计算任务，这对科学研究非常重要
which are super important for science
这对科学研究非常重要
which are super important for science and I think uh have been hard to do in
这对科学研究非常重要，而且我觉得
and I think uh have been hard to do in
而且我觉得
and I think uh have been hard to do in PyTorch for a long time. Um broader
而且我觉得这在 PyTorch 里长期都很难做到。更广泛的
PyTorch for a long time. Um broader
PyTorch 里长期都很难做到。更广泛的
PyTorch for a long time. Um broader platform support uh is you know we also
PyTorch 里长期都很难做到。平台支持方面，我们也
platform support uh is you know we also
平台支持方面，我们也
platform support uh is you know we also made improvements across a bunch of
平台支持方面，我们也改进了许多
made improvements across a bunch of
改进了许多
made improvements across a bunch of different platforms including Rockcom.
改进了包括 ROCm 在内的多个平台。
different platforms including Rockcom.
包括 Rockcom 在内的不同平台。
different platforms including Rockcom. There's now 7.14 wheels uh produced um
包括 Rockcom 在内的不同平台。现在已有 7.14 版 wheel 包。
There's now 7.14 wheels uh produced um
现在已有 7.14 版 wheel 包。
There's now 7.14 wheels uh produced um from the rock pip uh SDK and Intel
现在已有来自 rock pip SDK 和英特尔的 7.14 版 wheel 包。
from the rock pip uh SDK and Intel
来自 rock pip SDK 和英特尔。
from the rock pip uh SDK and Intel adding uh native graph capture for the
来自 rock pip SDK 和英特尔，并加入原生图捕获功能。
adding uh native graph capture for the
加入原生图捕获功能。
adding uh native graph capture for the XPU and inductor uh target inductor
为 XPU 和 Inductor 目标加入原生图捕获功能。
XPU and inductor uh target inductor
XPU 和 Inductor 目标，涉及 Inductor。
XPU and inductor uh target inductor targeting uh inductor uh functionality
XPU 和 Inductor 目标，重点是 Inductor 功能。
targeting uh inductor uh functionality
重点是 Inductor 功能。
targeting uh inductor uh functionality targeting the new Ruben platform from
重点是 Inductor 功能，并面向新的 Ruben 平台。
targeting the new Ruben platform from
面向新的 Ruben 平台。
targeting the new Ruben platform from Nvidia. So that was a mouthful but
面向英伟达新的 Ruben 平台。说起来有点长，不过……
Nvidia. So that was a mouthful but
英伟达。说起来有点长，不过……
Nvidia. So that was a mouthful but that's the sort of like highlights from
英伟达。说起来有点长，不过这些就是主要亮点。
that's the sort of like highlights from
这些就是主要亮点。
that's the sort of like highlights from this particular release. Having set that
这些就是此次发布的亮点。说到这里，
this particular release. Having set that
此次发布。说到这里，
this particular release. Having set that stage let's move to questions. Um so at
此次发布。说到这里，我们来回答问题。首先，
stage let's move to questions. Um so at
我们来回答问题。首先，
stage let's move to questions. Um so at the first question I think that we might
我们来回答问题。首先，我想第一个问题可能是：
the first question I think that we might
我想第一个问题可能是：
the first question I think that we might have
我想第一个问题可能会是：
will be what CUDA version does PyTorch
PyTorch 会随附哪个 CUDA 版本？
will be what CUDA version does PyTorch 2.14 ship
PyTorch 2.14 会随附哪个 CUDA 版本？
2.14 ship
2.14 会随附哪个版本？
2.14 ship uh and which one do I get by default and
2.14 会随附哪个版本？默认又会得到哪个？
uh and which one do I get by default and
默认会得到哪个版本？还有，
uh and which one do I get by default and what packaging changes for CUDA do we
默认会得到哪个版本？CUDA 的打包方式又会有哪些变化？
what packaging changes for CUDA do we
CUDA 的打包方式会有哪些变化？
what packaging changes for CUDA do we expect for the upcoming release? Andre
下次发布时，CUDA 的打包方式会有哪些变化？Andre，
expect for the upcoming release? Andre
下次发布时会有哪些变化？Andre，
expect for the upcoming release? Andre >> [snorts]
下次发布时会有哪些变化？Andre。（哼笑）
>> [snorts]
（哼笑）
>> [snorts] >> um yes so basically for the current
（哼笑）嗯，是的，当前……
>> um yes so basically for the current
嗯，是的，当前……
>> um yes so basically for the current 21.14 release uh we support exactly same
嗯，是的，当前 21.14 版支持与之前完全相同的……
21.14 release uh we support exactly same
21.14 版支持与之前完全相同的……
21.14 release uh we support exactly same cuda matrix as previous release 21.13 so
21.14 版支持与上一版 21.13 完全相同的 CUDA 版本矩阵，
cuda matrix as previous release 21.13 so
CUDA 版本矩阵与上一版 21.13 相同，
cuda matrix as previous release 21.13 so it's cuda 12.6 kuda 13.0 and cuda 13.2
CUDA 版本矩阵与上一版 21.13 相同，即 CUDA 12.6、13.0 和 13.2。
it's cuda 12.6 kuda 13.0 and cuda 13.2
即 CUDA 12.6、13.0 和 13.2。
it's cuda 12.6 kuda 13.0 and cuda 13.2 um cuda 13.0 is being published to pipy
即 CUDA 12.6、13.0 和 13.2。CUDA 13.0 已发布到 PyPI。
um cuda 13.0 is being published to pipy
CUDA 13.0 已发布到 PyPI。
um cuda 13.0 is being published to pipy um cuda 13.2 two becomes stable. Um it
CUDA 13.0 已发布到 PyPI，CUDA 13.2 则转为稳定版。
um cuda 13.2 two becomes stable. Um it
CUDA 13.2 转为稳定版；它在……
um cuda 13.2 two becomes stable. Um it for previous release it was prototype
CUDA 13.2 转为稳定版；在上一版中，它还是原型版。
for previous release it was prototype
在上一版中，它还是原型版。
for previous release it was prototype considered as prototype right now it's
在上一版中，它被视为原型版，现在则是……
considered as prototype right now it's
目前仍被视为原型。
considered as prototype right now it's stable. Um so um for the next uh also
目前仍被视为原型，但已经稳定。接下来……
stable. Um so um for the next uh also
已经稳定。接下来……
stable. Um so um for the next uh also for this release we included rocker
已经稳定。这次发布还加入了 ROCm……
for this release we included rocker
这次发布加入了 ROCm……
for this release we included rocker modifications. So rocom 714 wheels are
这次发布加入了 ROCm 的改动，因此 ROCm 7.1.4 的 wheel 包……
modifications. So rocom 714 wheels are
这些改动使 ROCm 7.1.4 的 wheel 包……
modifications. So rocom 714 wheels are published
这些改动使 ROCm 7.1.4 的 wheel 包得以发布。
published
已发布。
published um right now build with uh the rock uh
已发布，目前使用 ROCm……构建。
um right now build with uh the rock uh
目前使用 ROCm……构建。
um right now build with uh the rock uh pip SDK.
目前使用 ROCm pip SDK 构建。
pip SDK.
使用 pip SDK。
pip SDK. Um so for the next release 2.15 it's I
使用 pip SDK。至于下一个 2.15 版本，我……
Um so for the next release 2.15 it's I
至于下一个 2.15 版本，我……
Um so for the next release 2.15 it's I think where the lot of changes are
我认为下一个 2.15 版本会有很多变化。
think where the lot of changes are
我认为会有很多变化。
think where the lot of changes are coming um first of all 2 um 14 release
我认为会有很多变化。首先，2.14 版本……
coming um first of all 2 um 14 release
首先，2.14 版本……
coming um first of all 2 um 14 release was the last release that we released
首先，2.14 版本是我们最后一个发布……的版本。
was the last release that we released
是我们最后一个发布……的版本。
was the last release that we released CUDA 12.x wheels so 12.6 six for the
是我们最后一个发布 CUDA 12.x wheel 包的版本，也就是 CUDA 12.6。
CUDA 12.x wheels so 12.6 six for the
CUDA 12.x wheel 包，也就是 CUDA 12.6；接下来……
CUDA 12.x wheels so 12.6 six for the 2.15 release. We will uh remove those
CUDA 12.x wheel 包，也就是 CUDA 12.6。到了 2.15 版本，我们会移除这些包。
2.15 release. We will uh remove those
到了 2.15 版本，我们会移除这些包。
2.15 release. We will uh remove those wheels. There will no longer be shipped
到了 2.15 版本，我们会移除这些 wheel 包，不再随 PyTorch 提供。
wheels. There will no longer be shipped
这些 wheel 包将不再提供。
wheels. There will no longer be shipped with PyTorch. However, you are able you
这些 wheel 包将不再随 PyTorch 提供。不过，你仍然可以……
with PyTorch. However, you are able you
随 PyTorch 提供。不过，你仍然可以……
with PyTorch. However, you are able you will still be able to compile
随 PyTorch 提供。不过，你仍然可以自行编译。
will still be able to compile
仍然可以自行编译。
will still be able to compile with those manually
仍然可以手动用这些版本编译。
with those manually
手动用这些版本编译。
with those manually um because and we are keeping one CUDA
手动用这些版本编译，因为我们会保留一个 CUDA……
um because and we are keeping one CUDA
因为我们会保留一个 CUDA……
um because and we are keeping one CUDA 12.6 CI built on our system. So we are
因为我们会在系统中保留一个 CUDA 12.6 的 CI 构建，以便……
12.6 CI built on our system. So we are
我们会在系统中保留一个 CUDA 12.6 的 CI 构建，以便……
12.6 CI built on our system. So we are ensuring that it's still the case. So
我们会在系统中保留一个 CUDA 12.6 的 CI 构建，确保它仍然可用。
ensuring that it's still the case. So
确保它仍然可用。
ensuring that it's still the case. So there is no regression in this case. Um
确保它仍然可用，避免出现回归。
there is no regression in this case. Um
这方面不会出现回归。
there is no regression in this case. Um with CUDA 12.6 six support um uh that
这方面不会出现回归。至于 CUDA 12.6 支持……
with CUDA 12.6 six support um uh that
至于 CUDA 12.6 支持……
with CUDA 12.6 six support um uh that we're removing we're no longer be
随着我们移除 CUDA 12.6 支持，我们将不再……
we're removing we're no longer be
我们将不再……
we're removing we're no longer be supporting pre-built wheels for Maxwell,
我们将不再为 Maxwell 提供预编译 wheel 包，
supporting pre-built wheels for Maxwell,
不再为 Maxwell 提供预编译 wheel 包，
supporting pre-built wheels for Maxwell, Pascal and VA architectures.
不再为 Maxwell、Pascal 和 Volta 架构提供预编译 wheel 包。
Pascal and VA architectures.
Pascal 和 Volta 架构。
Pascal and VA architectures. Um so the next part uh it's CUDA 13.2
Pascal 和 Volta 架构。接下来是 CUDA 13.2。
Um so the next part uh it's CUDA 13.2
嗯，接下来是 CUDA 13.2。
Um so the next part uh it's CUDA 13.2 will be published as default CUDA
接下来，CUDA 13.2 将作为默认 CUDA 版本发布。
will be published as default CUDA
将作为默认 CUDA 版本发布。
will be published as default CUDA version on PIP and we will introduce
将在 pip 上作为默认 CUDA 版本发布，我们还会推出……
version on PIP and we will introduce
pip 上的版本，我们还会推出……
version on PIP and we will introduce CUDA 13.4 four as a prototype uh CUDA
pip 上的版本；我们还会推出 CUDA 13.4 的原型版本。
CUDA 13.4 four as a prototype uh CUDA
CUDA 13.4 的原型版本。
CUDA 13.4 four as a prototype uh CUDA version with support for ver Rubin
CUDA 13.4 的原型版本，将支持 Vera Rubin 架构。
version with support for ver Rubin
支持 Vera Rubin 架构的版本。
version with support for ver Rubin architecture. Um I think this covers
支持 Vera Rubin 架构的版本。嗯，我想这涵盖了……
architecture. Um I think this covers
架构。嗯，我想这涵盖了……
architecture. Um I think this covers pretty much it in terms of cuda and a
架构。嗯，我想 CUDA 方面基本就这些了，还有……
pretty much it in terms of cuda and a
CUDA 方面基本就这些了，还有……
pretty much it in terms of cuda and a little bit of rocom. Please
CUDA 方面基本就这些了，ROCm 也讲了一点。请……
little bit of rocom. Please
ROCm 也讲了一点。请……
little bit of rocom. Please >> if I can make a small comment there's a
ROCm 也讲了一点。请……我补充一句，数字和版本很多。
>> if I can make a small comment there's a
我补充一句，数字和版本很多。
>> if I can make a small comment there's a like a lot of numbers lot of versions
我补充一句，数字和版本确实很多。
like a lot of numbers lot of versions
数字和版本确实很多。
like a lot of numbers lot of versions please track the pytor issues and dev
数字和版本确实很多，请关注 PyTorch 的议题和 dev-discuss。
please track the pytor issues and dev
请关注 PyTorch 的议题和 dev-discuss。
please track the pytor issues and dev discuss where we publish all those
请关注 PyTorch 的议题和 dev-discuss，我们会在那里公布各版本。
discuss where we publish all those
我们会在那里公布各版本。
discuss where we publish all those versions because it's they hard to
我们会在那里公布各版本，因为这些版本很难……
versions because it's they hard to
这些版本很难……
versions because it's they hard to remember and sometimes we have to pivot
这些版本很难记，而且有时我们得调整计划。
remember and sometimes we have to pivot
很难记，而且有时我们得调整计划。
remember and sometimes we have to pivot depending on some new hardware
很难记，而且有时我们得根据新硬件……
depending on some new hardware
得根据新硬件……
depending on some new hardware capabilities or whatever but that's the
得根据新硬件的能力等情况调整，但这就是……
capabilities or whatever but that's the
硬件能力等情况，不过这就是……
capabilities or whatever but that's the current plans. Thank you.
硬件能力等情况，不过这就是目前的计划。谢谢。
current plans. Thank you.
目前的计划。谢谢。
current plans. Thank you. Yeah, and just to add, there's a release
目前的计划。谢谢。对了，补充一下，有一份发布文件……
Yeah, and just to add, there's a release
对了，补充一下，有一份发布文件……
Yeah, and just to add, there's a release MD file in the PyTorch PyTorch where the
对了，补充一下，PyTorch 仓库里有一份 release.md 文件。
MD file in the PyTorch PyTorch where the
PyTorch 仓库里的 release.md 文件……
MD file in the PyTorch PyTorch where the current matrix is published and yeah,
PyTorch 仓库里的 release.md 文件公布了当前的版本矩阵。
current matrix is published and yeah,
那里公布了当前的版本矩阵。
current matrix is published and yeah, you can go ahead and take a look there
那里公布了当前的版本矩阵，大家可以去看看。
you can go ahead and take a look there
大家可以去那里看看。
you can go ahead and take a look there and ask any questions.
大家可以去那里看看，有问题也可以问。
>> Okay. Um, do we have a next question
好的。嗯，下一个问题……
>> Okay. Um, do we have a next question queued up?
好的。嗯，还有下一个问题吗？
[snorts]
[哼笑]
[snorts] Okay. Um, thank you, uh, Michael for
[哼笑] 好的，感谢 Michael 提问。
Okay. Um, thank you, uh, Michael for
好的，感谢 Michael 提问。
Okay. Um, thank you, uh, Michael for asking this question. With Agentic RL
好的，感谢 Michael 提问。随着 Agentic RL……
asking this question. With Agentic RL
感谢提问。随着 Agentic RL……
asking this question. With Agentic RL becoming a bigger part of training, um
感谢提问。随着 Agentic RL 在训练中越来越重要，嗯……
becoming a bigger part of training, um
正逐渐成为训练中更重要的一部分，嗯。
becoming a bigger part of training, um are you all seeing these workloads
正逐渐成为训练中更重要的一部分。嗯，你们是否发现这些工作负载
are you all seeing these workloads
你们是否发现这些工作负载
are you all seeing these workloads create different infrastructure
你们是否发现这些工作负载带来了不同的基础设施
create different infrastructure
带来了不同的基础设施
create different infrastructure challenges than traditional model
带来了与传统模型训练不同的基础设施挑战
challenges than traditional model
与传统模型训练不同的挑战
challenges than traditional model training? Anything PyTorch needs still
与传统模型训练不同的挑战？PyTorch 在这方面还有什么
training? Anything PyTorch needs still
训练？PyTorch 在这方面还有什么
training? Anything PyTorch needs still needs to get better at there? I'm
训练？PyTorch 在这方面还有什么需要改进的？我
needs to get better at there? I'm
需要改进的？我
needs to get better at there? I'm actually going to um direct this one to
需要改进的？我想先把这个问题抛给
actually going to um direct this one to
我想先把这个问题抛给
actually going to um direct this one to Joe first and then Andre and Nikita, you
我想先请 Joe 回答，然后 Andre 和 Nikita，你们
Joe first and then Andre and Nikita, you
先请 Joe 回答，然后 Andre 和 Nikita，你们
Joe first and then Andre and Nikita, you guys can jump in after. Um Joe, I know
Joe 先来，Andre 和 Nikita 随后补充。嗯，Joe，我知道
guys can jump in after. Um Joe, I know
你们随后补充。嗯，Joe，我知道
guys can jump in after. Um Joe, I know you care a lot about agentic RL. So
你们随后补充。Joe，我知道你很关注智能体强化学习。所以
you care a lot about agentic RL. So
你很关注智能体强化学习。所以
you care a lot about agentic RL. So >> yeah,
你很关注智能体强化学习。所以。对。
>> yeah,
对。
>> yeah, >> I mean I think um you know if you look
对。我觉得，你看
>> I mean I think um you know if you look
我觉得，你看
>> I mean I think um you know if you look at it's it's pretty interesting the the
我觉得，你看，这很有意思，现在的
at it's it's pretty interesting the the
这很有意思，现在的
at it's it's pretty interesting the the models coming out these days are coming
这很有意思，现在的模型推出得
models coming out these days are coming
现在的模型推出得
models coming out these days are coming out fast and furious and I think there
现在的模型推出得又快又多，我觉得
out fast and furious and I think there
又快又多，我觉得
out fast and furious and I think there there was at least a for a while a
又快又多，我觉得至少有一段时间
there was at least a for a while a
至少有一段时间
there was at least a for a while a perception that people are are
至少有一段时间，大家觉得人们在
perception that people are are
大家觉得人们在
perception that people are are pre-training models at an increased pace
大家觉得人们在加快模型预训练的速度
pre-training models at an increased pace
加快模型预训练的速度
pre-training models at an increased pace right but I think a lot of the gains
加快模型预训练的速度，对吧？但我觉得很多进展
right but I think a lot of the gains
对吧？但我觉得很多进展
right but I think a lot of the gains that that we've seen actually you know
对吧？但我觉得我们看到的很多进展其实
that that we've seen actually you know
我们看到的很多进展其实
that that we've seen actually you know some of the Chinese models for example
我们看到的很多进展，其实比如一些中国模型
some of the Chinese models for example
比如一些中国模型
some of the Chinese models for example that are coming out and and versioned
比如一些中国模型不断推出、快速迭代
that are coming out and and versioned
不断推出、快速迭代
that are coming out and and versioned really fast and the Quen models a lot of
这些模型迭代得很快，Qwen 模型的很多进展
really fast and the Quen models a lot of
迭代得很快，Qwen 模型的很多进展
really fast and the Quen models a lot of it is actually due to RL uh and you know
其实得益于 RL，而且
it is actually due to RL uh and you know
it is actually due to RL uh and you know I think one of the things that we've
其实得益于 RL，而且我觉得我们
I think one of the things that we've
我觉得我们
I think one of the things that we've learned over the is you know if you
我觉得我们逐渐认识到，你知道，如果你
learned over the is you know if you
学到的是，如果你……
learned over the is you know if you build a really strong pre-trained base
学到的是，如果你构建了强大的预训练基座
build a really strong pre-trained base
构建强大的预训练基座
build a really strong pre-trained base um to build on you can actually RL over
有了强大的预训练基座，就能在此基础上做强化学习
um to build on you can actually RL over
在这个基础上，你就能做强化学习
um to build on you can actually RL over it and you can actually throw more
在这个基础上，你就能做强化学习，还能投入更多
it and you can actually throw more
还能在上面投入更多
it and you can actually throw more compute on it and I think the deepseek
还能投入更多算力。我认为 DeepSeek
compute on it and I think the deepseek
投入更多算力。我认为 DeepSeek
compute on it and I think the deepseek paper actually taught us a lot of
投入更多算力。我认为 DeepSeek 的论文
paper actually taught us a lot of
这篇论文确实让我们学到了很多
paper actually taught us a lot of lessons that kind of confirms for the
这篇论文确实让我们学到了很多，也印证了
lessons that kind of confirms for the
这些经验也印证了
lessons that kind of confirms for the the bitter lesson pill people among us
这些经验也印证了我们这些信奉“苦涩教训”的人
the bitter lesson pill people among us
我们这些信奉“苦涩教训”的人
the bitter lesson pill people among us including myself that you know if you
我们这些信奉“苦涩教训”的人，包括我自己，都认为如果你
including myself that you know if you
包括我自己，都认为如果你
including myself that you know if you continue to throw more compute at stable
包括我自己，都认为如果你继续给稳定的强化学习投入更多算力
continue to throw more compute at stable
继续给稳定的强化学习投入更多算力
continue to throw more compute at stable stable RL using that word stable very
继续给稳定的强化学习投入更多算力。我说“稳定”这个词时
stable RL using that word stable very
说“稳定的强化学习”时，我对“稳定”这个词
stable RL using that word stable very very uh carefully purposefully uh then
说“稳定的强化学习”时，我非常谨慎、刻意地用了“稳定”这个词。那么
very uh carefully purposefully uh then
我是非常谨慎、刻意地这么说的。那么
very uh carefully purposefully uh then you can actually extend capabilities of
我是非常谨慎、刻意地这么说的。那么你确实能持续提升
you can actually extend capabilities of
你确实能持续提升
you can actually extend capabilities of models over time. And so I think like
你确实能不断提升模型的能力。所以我觉得
models over time. And so I think like
模型的能力能不断提升。所以我觉得
models over time. And so I think like you know uh in the earlier days I guess
模型的能力能不断提升。所以我觉得，早些时候
you know uh in the earlier days I guess
我想，在早些时候
you know uh in the earlier days I guess of RL um and and we started this project
我想，在强化学习发展的早期，我们启动了一个项目
of RL um and and we started this project
在强化学习发展的早期，我们启动了一个项目
of RL um and and we started this project called OpenM last year when I was
在强化学习发展的早期，我们启动了一个叫 OpenM 的项目。那是去年
called OpenM last year when I was
叫 OpenM 的项目。那是去年
called OpenM last year when I was actually almost one year ago exactly uh
叫 OpenM 的项目。准确说，差不多正好是一年前
actually almost one year ago exactly uh
准确说，差不多正好是一年前
actually almost one year ago exactly uh at the PyTorch conference we uh launched
准确说，差不多正好是一年前，我们在 PyTorch 大会上发布了它
at the PyTorch conference we uh launched
我们在 PyTorch 大会上发布了它
at the PyTorch conference we uh launched that project and it continues to grow
我们在 PyTorch 大会上发布了这个项目，它还在持续发展
that project and it continues to grow
这个项目还在持续发展
that project and it continues to grow and I think one the whole goal of it was
这个项目还在持续发展。我想，它的总体目标是
and I think one the whole goal of it was
我想，它的总体目标是
and I think one the whole goal of it was to democratize the use of reinforcement
我想，它的总体目标是让强化学习的使用更加普及
to democratize the use of reinforcement
让强化学习的使用更加普及
to democratize the use of reinforcement learning um because it's it's a lot
让强化学习的使用更加普及，因为现在
learning um because it's it's a lot
因为现在做这件事
learning um because it's it's a lot easier to kind of create an environment
因为现在创建一个环境容易多了
easier to kind of create an environment
创建一个环境容易多了
easier to kind of create an environment create your tasks um and then be able to
创建一个环境、设计自己的任务都容易多了，然后你就能
create your tasks um and then be able to
设计自己的任务，然后你就能
create your tasks um and then be able to to set up you know especially today with
设计自己的任务，然后就能完成配置，尤其是现在有了
to set up you know especially today with
搭建起来，尤其是如今有了
to set up you know especially today with all the tools available Nemo RL
尤其是如今有了 NeMo RL 等各种工具，搭建起来更容易
all the tools available Nemo RL
有了 NeMo RL 等各种工具
all the tools available Nemo RL TRL unsloth, you can actually uh use
有了 NeMo RL、TRL、Unsloth 等工具，你就能用
TRL unsloth, you can actually uh use
有了 TRL 和 Unsloth，你就能用
TRL unsloth, you can actually uh use reinforcement learning um you know way
有了 TRL 和 Unsloth，你就能用强化学习，方式也
reinforcement learning um you know way
强化学习也变得
reinforcement learning um you know way easier than you could probably like five
强化学习比五年前容易得多
easier than you could probably like five
比五年前容易得多
easier than you could probably like five or 10 years ago in the earlier days um
比五年或十年前的早期容易得多
or 10 years ago in the earlier days um
比十年前的早期容易得多
or 10 years ago in the earlier days um and actually add capabilities to your
比十年前的早期容易得多，还能给模型增加能力
and actually add capabilities to your
还能给模型增加能力
and actually add capabilities to your models bas basically be able to postrain
还能给模型增加能力，基本上就是给模型做后训练
models bas basically be able to postrain
基本上就是给模型做后训练
models bas basically be able to postrain using reinforcement learning for openw
基本上就是用强化学习对开放权重模型做后训练
using reinforcement learning for openw
用强化学习处理开放权重模型
using reinforcement learning for openw weight models and I think that's
用强化学习处理开放权重模型，我认为这
weight models and I think that's
开放权重模型，我认为这
weight models and I think that's something we want to continue to
开放权重模型，我认为这也是我们想继续
something we want to continue to
这也是我们想继续做的事
something we want to continue to obviously de democratize and and enable
我们显然想继续普及这项技术，让更多开发者用上
obviously de democratize and and enable
普及这项技术，让更多开发者用上
obviously de democratize and and enable with developers um and so like Daniel
让更多开发者用上。比如 Daniel
with developers um and so like Daniel
开发者也能用上。比如 Daniel
with developers um and so like Daniel from Unsloth continues to bear that that
Unsloth 的 Daniel 一直在为这件事努力
from Unsloth continues to bear that that
Unsloth 的 Daniel 一直在
from Unsloth continues to bear that that flag for many uh and obviously we
Unsloth 的 Daniel 一直在为许多人扛起这面旗帜，我们当然也
flag for many uh and obviously we
为许多人扛起这面旗帜，我们当然也
flag for many uh and obviously we contribute uh significantly to open
为许多人扛起这面旗帜，我们也为开源项目做出了重要贡献
contribute uh significantly to open
我们也为开源项目做出了重要贡献
contribute uh significantly to open project and that fits nicely into the
我们为开源项目做出了重要贡献，这也很好地融入了
project and that fits nicely into the
这些项目也很好地融入了
project and that fits nicely into the PyTorch ecosystem and extends it as
这些项目也很好地融入了 PyTorch 生态，并扩展了它
PyTorch ecosystem and extends it as
PyTorch 生态也因此得到扩展
PyTorch ecosystem and extends it as people use PyTorch and other tools to uh
随着人们使用 PyTorch 和其他工具，它也得到扩展
people use PyTorch and other tools to uh
人们用 PyTorch 和其他工具
people use PyTorch and other tools to uh to to to customize their models for
人们用 PyTorch 和其他工具，根据任务定制模型
to to to customize their models for
根据任务定制模型
to to to customize their models for their tasks.
根据各自的任务定制模型。
their tasks.
各自的任务。
their tasks. >> But fundamentally, PyTorch has a lot of
各自的任务。说到底，PyTorch 已经具备很多
>> But fundamentally, PyTorch has a lot of
说到底，PyTorch 已经具备很多
>> But fundamentally, PyTorch has a lot of the things that that folks need. Um we
说到底，PyTorch 已经具备大家需要的很多东西。我们
the things that that folks need. Um we
大家需要的很多东西。我们
the things that that folks need. Um we need these sort of layered packages like
大家需要的很多东西。我们还需要这类分层软件包，比如
need these sort of layered packages like
我们还需要这类分层软件包，比如
need these sort of layered packages like OpenM but but PyTorch itself. Are there
我们还需要 OpenM 这样的分层软件包，但 PyTorch 本身呢？
OpenM but but PyTorch itself. Are there
OpenM 这样的软件包之外，PyTorch 本身呢？
OpenM but but PyTorch itself. Are there any changes that you see uh you see
OpenM 这样的软件包之外，PyTorch 本身还有哪些变化是你预见到的？
any changes that you see uh you see
你觉得，呃，你觉得有哪些改动
any changes that you see uh you see needed now or in the future in PyTorch?
你觉得 PyTorch 现在或将来需要做哪些改动？
needed now or in the future in PyTorch?
PyTorch 现在或将来需要做哪些改动？
needed now or in the future in PyTorch? >> Well, I think
PyTorch 现在或将来需要做哪些改动？>>嗯，我觉得
>> Well, I think
>>嗯，我觉得
>> Well, I think Oh, sorry. Go for it.
>>嗯，我觉得……哦，抱歉，你先说。
Oh, sorry. Go for it.
哦，抱歉，你先说。
Oh, sorry. Go for it. >> No, no, go ahead. I want to hear your
哦，抱歉，你先说。>>不不，你先说，我想听听你的
>> No, no, go ahead. I want to hear your
>>不不，你先说，我想听听你的
>> No, no, go ahead. I want to hear your point of view. on the infrastructure
>>不不，你先说，我想听听你的看法。基础设施方面
point of view. on the infrastructure
看法。基础设施方面
point of view. on the infrastructure side like uh the nickel 2 and like the
看法。基础设施方面，比如 NCCL 2，还有
side like uh the nickel 2 and like the
基础设施方面，比如 NCCL 2，还有
side like uh the nickel 2 and like the safer nickel is one of the things that
基础设施方面，比如 NCCL 2，还有更安全的 NCCL，这是
safer nickel is one of the things that
更安全的 NCCL，这是
safer nickel is one of the things that is constantly painful for post training
更安全的 NCCL 一直是后训练中让人头疼的问题
is constantly painful for post training
一直是后训练中让人头疼的问题
is constantly painful for post training workflows when you have to restart. So
后训练流程一旦需要重启，就很麻烦。所以
workflows when you have to restart. So
流程一旦需要重启，就很麻烦。所以
workflows when you have to restart. So that would be an infrastructure part but
流程一旦需要重启，就很麻烦。所以这属于基础设施层面，但
that would be an infrastructure part but
这属于基础设施层面，但
that would be an infrastructure part but also we have as Joel Joe said a lot of
这属于基础设施层面，但正如 Joel Joe 所说，我们也有很多
also we have as Joel Joe said a lot of
正如 Joel Joe 所说，我们也有很多
also we have as Joel Joe said a lot of great partnership. I encourage people to
正如 Joel Joe 所说，我们也有很多很棒的合作。我建议大家
great partnership. I encourage people to
很棒的合作。我建议大家
great partnership. I encourage people to check out well u maybe not encourage but
很棒的合作。我建议大家看看……嗯，也不算建议吧，但
check out well u maybe not encourage but
去看看……嗯，也不算建议吧，但
check out well u maybe not encourage but there are two frameworks that exist in
去看看……嗯，也不算建议吧，但有两个框架
there are two frameworks that exist in
有两个框架
there are two frameworks that exist in the pytor side. There is a torch titan
PyTorch 这边有两个框架，其中一个是 TorchTitan
the pytor side. There is a torch titan
PyTorch 这边有 TorchTitan
the pytor side. There is a torch titan and torch forge that kind of give you
PyTorch 这边有 TorchTitan 和 TorchForge，它们提供
and torch forge that kind of give you
TorchForge 也会提供
and torch forge that kind of give you some recipes on the post training and I
TorchForge 也会提供一些后训练方案，我
some recipes on the post training and I
一些后训练方案，我
some recipes on the post training and I think you should kind of direct your
一些后训练方案，我觉得你应该把
think you should kind of direct your
我觉得你应该把
think you should kind of direct your attention more towards those
我觉得你应该多关注这些
attention more towards those
多关注这些
attention more towards those repositories when you're asking a
多关注这些代码仓库，尤其是当你问
repositories when you're asking a
这些代码仓库，尤其是当你问
repositories when you're asking a specific questions about the frameworks
这些代码仓库，尤其是当你问框架的具体问题时
specific questions about the frameworks
框架的具体问题时
specific questions about the frameworks rather about the like harness rather
框架的具体问题时，更像是在问配套工具，而
rather about the like harness rather
更像是在问配套工具，而
rather about the like harness rather than like a training framework itself
更像是在问配套工具，而非训练框架本身
than like a training framework itself
非训练框架本身
than like a training framework itself but support for MFP4 is also very
非训练框架本身，不过对 MFP4 的支持也很
but support for MFP4 is also very
不过对 MFP4 的支持也很
but support for MFP4 is also very important for post training pipelines so
不过对 MFP4 的支持对后训练流程也很重要，所以
important for post training pipelines so
这对后训练流程很重要，所以
important for post training pipelines so like all the infrastructures that is
这对后训练流程很重要，所以所需的基础设施
like all the infrastructures that is
所需的基础设施
like all the infrastructures that is needed is there but Joe to continue
所需的基础设施都已到位。不过 Joe，请接着说。
needed is there but Joe to continue
都已到位。不过 Joe，请接着说。
needed is there but Joe to continue >> no I I think you're spot on I think
都已到位。不过 Joe，请接着说。>> 不，我觉得你说得很对。我觉得
>> no I I think you're spot on I think
>> 不，我觉得你说得很对。我觉得
>> no I I think you're spot on I think there you know infra I mean we're we're
>> 不，我觉得你说得很对。我觉得，基础设施这块，我们
there you know infra I mean we're we're
基础设施这块，我们
there you know infra I mean we're we're using a pretty large large amount of
基础设施这块，我们用了相当多的
using a pretty large large amount of
用了相当多的
using a pretty large large amount of compute to do RL here in reflection. We
我们在 Reflection 用了大量算力做 RL。我们
compute to do RL here in reflection. We
用算力在 Reflection 做 RL。我们
compute to do RL here in reflection. We obviously did a lot of RL meta. Um I
用算力在 Reflection 做 RL。我们在 Meta 显然也做了大量 RL。嗯，我
obviously did a lot of RL meta. Um I
我们在 Meta 显然也做了大量 RL。嗯，我
obviously did a lot of RL meta. Um I think infrastructure is the challenge. I
我们在 Meta 显然也做了大量 RL。我觉得基础设施是个挑战。我
think infrastructure is the challenge. I
觉得基础设施是个挑战。我
think infrastructure is the challenge. I think there there's a lot of work I
觉得基础设施是个挑战。我觉得还有很多工作要做，我
think there there's a lot of work I
觉得还有很多工作要做，我
think there there's a lot of work I think to um you know to to scale it up
觉得还有很多工作要做，才能把规模扩大
think to um you know to to scale it up
才能把规模扩大
think to um you know to to scale it up to make it stable. I think I'm just
才能把规模扩大并保持稳定。我只是
to make it stable. I think I'm just
并保持稳定。我只是
to make it stable. I think I'm just looking at even like I'm I can't really
并保持稳定。我只是想，就连我现在也没法
looking at even like I'm I can't really
就连我现在也没法
looking at even like I'm I can't really use examples of what we're doing
就连我现在也没法拿我们正在做的事举例
use examples of what we're doing
拿我们正在做的事举例
use examples of what we're doing internally yet because we're still
拿我们内部正在做的事举例，因为我们还
internally yet because we're still
因为我们还
internally yet because we're still pretty salty. But like even when we were
因为我们还挺保密的。但即使当时我们
pretty salty. But like even when we were
还挺保密的。但即使当时我们
pretty salty. But like even when we were uh dealing with like fault tolerance in
还挺保密的。但即使当时我们在处理容错问题
uh dealing with like fault tolerance in
在处理容错问题
uh dealing with like fault tolerance in like the llama days, you know, most of
在 Llama 那段时期处理容错问题时，大部分
like the llama days, you know, most of
在 Llama 那段时期，大部分
like the llama days, you know, most of our uh the faults that we found even in
在 Llama 那段时期，我们发现的大部分故障，甚至
our uh the faults that we found even in
我们发现的大部分故障，甚至
our uh the faults that we found even in pre-training or even in post- training
我们发现的大部分故障，即使在预训练或后训练阶段
pre-training or even in post- training
在预训练甚至后训练阶段
pre-training or even in post- training came from obviously GPUs failing over.
在预训练甚至后训练阶段，显然都来自 GPU 故障。
came from obviously GPUs failing over.
显然都来自 GPU 故障。
came from obviously GPUs failing over. um you know we had uh yeah we I think
显然都来自 GPU 故障。嗯，我们当时……对，我想
um you know we had uh yeah we I think
嗯，我们当时……对，我想
um you know we had uh yeah we I think what something like 30% of of those
嗯，我们当时……对，我想，大约 30% 的
what something like 30% of of those
大约 30% 的
what something like 30% of of those failures or we had close to like 400 and
大约 30% 的故障，或者说，我们有 400 多块
failures or we had close to like 400 and
故障，或者说，我们有 400 多块
failures or we had close to like 400 and something GPUs out of the 16,000 GPUs we
故障，或者说，训练用的 16,000 块 GPU 中有 400 多块
something GPUs out of the 16,000 GPUs we
训练用的 16,000 块 GPU 中有 400 多块
something GPUs out of the 16,000 GPUs we were training on for the large model
用于训练大模型的 16,000 块 GPU 中有 400 多块
were training on for the large model
用于训练大模型的那些任务
were training on for the large model were failing. We wrote that into the
用于训练大模型的那些任务失败了。我们把这点写进了
were failing. We wrote that into the
失败了。我们把这点写进了
were failing. We wrote that into the paper. You can kind of look at the graph
失败了。我们把这点写进了论文。看看图就能发现
paper. You can kind of look at the graph
论文。看看图就能发现
paper. You can kind of look at the graph there. I think like infrastructure
论文。看看图就能发现。我觉得基础设施
there. I think like infrastructure
我觉得基础设施
there. I think like infrastructure stability and um and fall tolerance and
我觉得基础设施的稳定性和容错能力
stability and um and fall tolerance and
稳定性和容错能力
stability and um and fall tolerance and I think we'll get to that in some of the
稳定性和容错能力，我想后面的问题会谈到
I think we'll get to that in some of the
我想后面的问题会谈到
I think we'll get to that in some of the other questions but that's probably one
我想后面的问题会谈到，但这可能是
other questions but that's probably one
后面的问题会谈到，但这可能是
other questions but that's probably one of the biggest biggest things and I
后面的问题会谈到，但这可能是最大的难题之一。我
of the biggest biggest things and I
最大的难题之一。我
of the biggest biggest things and I think that's one of the reasons why like
最大的难题之一。我觉得这也是
think that's one of the reasons why like
我觉得这也是
think that's one of the reasons why like Tinker is actually like pretty
我觉得这也是 Tinker 挺有意思的原因之一，
Tinker is actually like pretty
Tinker 其实挺有意思，
Tinker is actually like pretty interesting from from thinking machines.
Thinking Machines 推出的 Tinker 其实挺有意思。
interesting from from thinking machines.
Thinking Machines 推出的产品挺有意思。
interesting from from thinking machines. It's like a, you know, not not to to
Thinking Machines 推出的产品挺有意思。我不是想
It's like a, you know, not not to to
我不是想
It's like a, you know, not not to to plug the his product here, but like it
我不是想在这里给他的产品打广告，但它
plug the his product here, but like it
在这里给他的产品打广告，但它
plug the his product here, but like it it actually does um it's actually a
在这里给他的产品打广告，但它确实做到了，它是个
it actually does um it's actually a
它确实做到了，它是个
it actually does um it's actually a really uh cool API that actually
它确实做到了，它是个很棒的 API，能
really uh cool API that actually
很棒的 API，能
really uh cool API that actually abstracts that away. And I think that's
很棒的 API，能把那些复杂问题封装起来。我觉得
abstracts that away. And I think that's
把那些复杂问题封装起来。我觉得
abstracts that away. And I think that's for those especially the academics I've
把那些复杂问题封装起来。我觉得，对我接触过的学者来说，
for those especially the academics I've
对我接触过的学者来说，尤其如此。
for those especially the academics I've talked to and researchers like that is
对我接触过的学者和研究人员来说，这
talked to and researchers like that is
对我接触过的研究人员来说，这
talked to and researchers like that is by far the hardest part. And obviously
对我接触过的研究人员来说，这无疑是最难的部分。当然，
by far the hardest part. And obviously
这无疑是最难的部分。当然，
by far the hardest part. And obviously it's powered by PyTorch which is really
这无疑是最难的部分。当然，它由 PyTorch 驱动，这很好。
it's powered by PyTorch which is really
它由 PyTorch 驱动，这很好。
it's powered by PyTorch which is really great. Um but that that is like the the
它由 PyTorch 驱动，这很好。但
great. Um but that that is like the the
这很好。但
great. Um but that that is like the the thing that that needs to be solved for
这很好。但这正是需要解决的
thing that that needs to be solved for
这正是需要解决的
thing that that needs to be solved for this to be something that's widespread
这正是需要解决的问题，解决了才能
this to be something that's widespread
才能让它得到广泛
this to be something that's widespread used. So
才能让它得到广泛应用。所以
used. So
得到应用。所以
used. So >> awesome. I think that's a pretty good
所以，太好了。我觉得这个回答
>> awesome. I think that's a pretty good
太好了。我觉得这个回答
>> awesome. I think that's a pretty good pretty solid answer to that question.
太好了。我觉得这个问题回答得很充分。
pretty solid answer to that question.
这个问题答得挺到位。
pretty solid answer to that question. Um, next up, um, why didn't you add LLM?
这个问题答得挺到位。接下来，为什么没有加入 LLM？
Um, next up, um, why didn't you add LLM?
接下来，为什么没有加入 LLM？
Um, next up, um, why didn't you add LLM? Why don't didn't you add LLM support
接下来，为什么没有加入 LLM？为什么没有加入 LLM 支持？
Why don't didn't you add LLM support
为什么没有加入 LLM 支持？
Why don't didn't you add LLM support into the UI so people can talk to an
为什么不在 UI 中加入 LLM 支持，让大家能和
into the UI so people can talk to an
在 UI 中，让大家能和
into the UI so people can talk to an agent instead of reading through the
在 UI 中，让大家能和智能体交谈，而不用翻阅
agent instead of reading through the
智能体交谈，而不用翻阅
agent instead of reading through the documentation?
智能体交谈，而不用翻阅文档？
documentation?
文档？
documentation? Uh, who wants to answer this? Uh,
文档？谁想回答这个问题？
Uh, who wants to answer this? Uh,
谁想回答这个问题？
Uh, who wants to answer this? Uh, [laughter]
谁想回答这个问题？[笑声]
[laughter]
[笑声]
[laughter] >> I'm not sure what UI we're talking
[笑声] 我不太确定说的是哪个 UI。
>> I'm not sure what UI we're talking
我不太确定说的是哪个 UI。
>> I'm not sure what UI we're talking about, but yes, like you can ask
我不太确定说的是哪个 UI。不过，确实可以向智能体提问。
about, but yes, like you can ask
不过，确实可以提问。
about, but yes, like you can ask questions to an agent uh on the
不过，确实可以在网站上向智能体提问。
questions to an agent uh on the
可以在网站上向智能体提问。
questions to an agent uh on the pytor.org, work but there's also kind of
可以在 pytorch.org 上向智能体提问，但也有一些
pytor.org, work but there's also kind of
pytorch.org 上可以用，但也有一些
pytor.org, work but there's also kind of a pragmatic approach that um like
pytorch.org 上可以用，但也有一些实际考量。
a pragmatic approach that um like
实际考量是，
a pragmatic approach that um like running LM for public consumption is not
实际考量是，向公众提供 LM 服务
running LM for public consumption is not
向公众提供 LM 服务
running LM for public consumption is not cheap and via foundation right so there
向公众提供 LM 服务并不便宜；我们是基金会，对吧，所以
cheap and via foundation right so there
并不便宜；我们是基金会，对吧，所以
cheap and via foundation right so there are lots of open LLMs that are very very
并不便宜；我们是基金会，对吧。市面上有很多开放的 LLM，
are lots of open LLMs that are very very
市面上有很多开放的 LLM，
are lots of open LLMs that are very very good about answering questions about
市面上有很多开放的 LLM，很擅长回答
good about answering questions about
很擅长回答
good about answering questions about PyTorch documentation and we partnered
很擅长回答关于 PyTorch 文档的问题。我们也曾合作
PyTorch documentation and we partnered
关于 PyTorch 文档的问题。我们也曾合作
PyTorch documentation and we partnered with one of the providers early on so
我们早期和其中一家服务商合作过，所以
with one of the providers early on so
with one of the providers early on so you can ask PyTorch questions that I
我们早期和其中一家服务商合作过，所以你可以问 PyTorch 相关问题。我
you can ask PyTorch questions that I
你可以问 PyTorch 相关问题。我
you can ask PyTorch questions that I don't remember job probably have more
我不记得了，Job 可能更了解
don't remember job probably have more
不记得了，Job 可能更了解
don't remember job probably have more upto-ate details about the partnership
不记得了，Job 可能更清楚合作的最新情况，
upto-ate details about the partnership
合作的最新情况，
upto-ate details about the partnership like who is the provider but yeah
合作的最新情况，比如服务商是谁。总之，
like who is the provider but yeah
比如服务商是谁。总之，
like who is the provider but yeah >> yeah go to collab and talk an agent,
比如服务商是谁。对，去 Colab 和智能体聊就行。
>> yeah go to collab and talk an agent,
对，去 Colab 和智能体聊就行。
>> yeah go to collab and talk an agent, right? And it answers your questions
对，去 Colab 和智能体聊就行，对吧？它会回答你的问题。
right? And it answers your questions
对吧？它会回答你的问题。
right? And it answers your questions about PyTorch.
对吧？它会回答你关于 PyTorch 的问题。
about PyTorch.
关于 PyTorch。
about PyTorch. >> Actually,
关于 PyTorch。>> 其实，
>> Actually,
其实，
>> Actually, >> I would like to add Go ahead.
其实，>> 我想补充一点。请说。
>> I would like to add Go ahead.
我想补充一点。请说。
>> I would like to add Go ahead. >> Go for it, Andre.
我想补充一点。请说。>> Andre，你说。
>> Go for it, Andre.
Andre，你说。
>> Go for it, Andre. >> So, basically, yes. Um, go ahead and
Andre，你说。>> 对，基本上是这样。你可以
>> So, basically, yes. Um, go ahead and
对，基本上是这样。你可以
>> So, basically, yes. Um, go ahead and create an issue for us describing
对，基本上是这样。你可以提个问题，说明
create an issue for us describing
提个问题，说明
create an issue for us describing exactly where you want to add the LLM
提个问题，说明你具体想在哪里加入 LLM
exactly where you want to add the LLM
你具体想在哪里加入 LLM
exactly where you want to add the LLM and maybe we can look into it. Yes,
你具体想在哪里加入 LLM，我们可以研究一下。对，
and maybe we can look into it. Yes,
我们可以研究一下。对，
and maybe we can look into it. Yes, because we have extensive documentation
我们可以研究一下。对，因为我们有大量文档
because we have extensive documentation
因为我们有大量文档
because we have extensive documentation and extensive um uh basically release
因为我们有大量文档，还有详尽的
and extensive um uh basically release
还有详尽的版本更新
and extensive um uh basically release notes and there there are multiple
还有详尽的版本更新说明，也有多个
notes and there there are multiple
说明，也有多个
notes and there there are multiple sources of documentation. So I think if
说明，也有多个文档来源。所以我觉得，如果
sources of documentation. So I think if
文档来源。所以我觉得，如果
sources of documentation. So I think if you're more direct about it what you
文档来源。所以我觉得，如果你能更明确地说说
you're more direct about it what you
你能更明确地说说
you're more direct about it what you want to do maybe we can come come up
你能更明确地说说想做什么，我们或许能想出
want to do maybe we can come come up
想做什么，我们或许能想出
want to do maybe we can come come up with the solutions for this.
想做什么，我们或许能想出解决办法。
with the solutions for this.
解决办法。
with the solutions for this. >> Yeah and an issue on GitHub is the right
解决办法。>> 对，在 GitHub 上提个问题是
>> Yeah and an issue on GitHub is the right
对，在 GitHub 上提个问题是
>> Yeah and an issue on GitHub is the right way to do that. Go ahead Joe.
对，在 GitHub 上提个问题是合适的。Joe，你说。
way to do that. Go ahead Joe.
合适的。Joe，你说。
way to do that. Go ahead Joe. >> Yeah. No, I was just gonna say I mean in
合适的。Joe，你说。>> 对，我只是想说，
>> Yeah. No, I was just gonna say I mean in
对，我只是想说，
>> Yeah. No, I was just gonna say I mean in the if the the the search obviously we
对，我只是想说，搜索方面，我们显然
the if the the the search obviously we
搜索方面，我们显然
the if the the the search obviously we use kind of an LM based search now I
搜索方面，我们显然已经用了某种基于 LM 的搜索。我
use kind of an LM based search now I
已经用了某种基于 LM 的搜索。我
use kind of an LM based search now I think there and I think you know you can
已经用了某种基于 LM 的搜索。我觉得你也可以
think there and I think you know you can
我觉得你也可以
think there and I think you know you can pragmatically um
我觉得你也可以务实一点，
pragmatically um
务实一点，
pragmatically um you can pragmatically use like Gemini as
务实一点，比如用 Gemini
you can pragmatically use like Gemini as
比如用 Gemini
you can pragmatically use like Gemini as well and I think all of our
比如也可以用 Gemini。我觉得我们所有的
well and I think all of our
我觉得我们所有的
well and I think all of our documentation is in distribution right
我觉得我们所有的文档都包含在发行版里，对吧？
documentation is in distribution right
文档都包含在发行版里，对吧？
documentation is in distribution right and uh it's it's well well indexed um
文档都包含在发行版里，对吧？而且索引做得很好。
and uh it's it's well well indexed um
而且索引做得很好。
and uh it's it's well well indexed um and so you know I go into Google and and
而且索引做得很好。所以我会打开 Google，
and so you know I go into Google and and
所以我会打开 Google，
and so you know I go into Google and and and actually Gemini does a really great
所以我会打开 Google。其实 Gemini 很擅长
and actually Gemini does a really great
其实 Gemini 很擅长
and actually Gemini does a really great job of like of scouring our
其实 Gemini 很擅长查找我们的
job of like of scouring our
查找我们的
job of like of scouring our documentation and and distilling things
查找我们的文档，并提炼内容，
documentation and and distilling things
文档，并提炼内容，
documentation and and distilling things down to what I need. So, um, we don't
文档，并提炼出我需要的信息。所以我们
down to what I need. So, um, we don't
提炼出我需要的信息。所以我们
down to what I need. So, um, we don't actually even need to do a lot embedded
提炼出我需要的信息。所以我们甚至不需要在网站里嵌入太多功能，
actually even need to do a lot embedded
甚至不需要嵌入太多功能，
actually even need to do a lot embedded in our site, but obviously make sure our
甚至不需要在网站里嵌入太多功能，但显然要确保我们的
in our site, but obviously make sure our
在网站里嵌入太多功能，但显然要确保我们的
in our site, but obviously make sure our docs are updated. Um, and and I mean, we
在网站里嵌入太多功能，但显然要确保文档及时更新。我是说，我们
docs are updated. Um, and and I mean, we
文档及时更新。我是说，我们
docs are updated. Um, and and I mean, we like there's obviously the last year
文档及时更新。我是说，过去一年我们显然
like there's obviously the last year
过去一年我们显然
like there's obviously the last year we've been trending towards how do you
过去一年我们显然一直在思考如何
we've been trending towards how do you
我们一直在思考如何
we've been trending towards how do you build things in a way obviously are good
我们一直在思考如何构建既方便
build things in a way obviously are good
构建既方便
build things in a way obviously are good for humans, but also like consumable by
构建既方便人类使用，也方便
for humans, but also like consumable by
人类使用，也方便
for humans, but also like consumable by LMS as well. And so, I think the team
人类使用，也方便 LMS 读取的内容。所以我觉得团队
LMS as well. And so, I think the team
LMS 也能读取。所以我觉得团队
LMS as well. And so, I think the team has done a great job kind of getting
LMS 也能读取。所以我觉得团队做得很好，已经让
has done a great job kind of getting
团队做得很好，已经让
has done a great job kind of getting things in a place where machines can
团队做得很好，已经让内容变得便于机器
things in a place where machines can
内容变得便于机器
things in a place where machines can read things um along with the humans.
内容变得既便于机器读取，也便于人阅读。
read things um along with the humans.
既便于机器读取，也便于人阅读。
read things um along with the humans. So, um, but we continue to improve.
既便于机器读取，也便于人阅读。不过我们还在继续改进。
>> Sounds great. Uh, next question. Um,
听起来很棒。下一个问题。
>> Sounds great. Uh, next question. Um, Demila B uh asks, "What is the what is
听起来很棒。下一个问题。Demila B 问：“目前
Demila B uh asks, "What is the what is
Demila B 问：“目前
Demila B uh asks, "What is the what is still the biggest unresolved limitation
Demila B 问：“目前最大的未解决局限
still the biggest unresolved limitation
最大的未解决局限
still the biggest unresolved limitation in PyTorch today for training large
如今在 PyTorch 中训练大型
in PyTorch today for training large
in PyTorch today for training large dynamic GNN's especially when the graph
如今在 PyTorch 中训练大型动态 GNN，尤其当图的
dynamic GNN's especially when the graph
动态 GNN，尤其当图的
dynamic GNN's especially when the graph topology say changes at every step?"
动态 GNN，尤其当图的拓扑结构每一步都变化时，是什么？”
topology say changes at every step?"
拓扑结构每一步都变化时，是什么？”
topology say changes at every step?" That's a great question. Um, who here
拓扑结构每一步都变化时，是什么？”好问题。这里谁
That's a great question. Um, who here
好问题。这里谁
That's a great question. Um, who here feels most confident talking about graph
好问题。这里谁最有把握谈谈图
feels most confident talking about graph
最有把握谈谈图
feels most confident talking about graph neural networks?
最有把握谈谈图神经网络？
neural networks?
神经网络？
neural networks? Joe, is that an area you've you've
神经网络？Joe，这方面你有没有……
Joe, is that an area you've you've
Joe，这方面你有没有……
Joe, is that an area you've you've looked into or not so much?
Joe，这方面你研究过吗？
looked into or not so much?
研究过吗？
looked into or not so much? I'm probably not the GNN expert here. We
研究过吗？我可能不是这里的 GNN 专家。我们……
I'm probably not the GNN expert here. We
我可能不是这里的 GNN 专家。我们……
I'm probably not the GNN expert here. We have used GNN's in the past for
我可能不是这里的 GNN 专家。我们以前用过 GNN，来处理……
have used GNN's in the past for
以前用过 GNN，来处理……
have used GNN's in the past for interesting kind of scientific
以前用过 GNN，来处理一些有意思的科学……
interesting kind of scientific
一些有意思的科学……
interesting kind of scientific use cases. Um especially in the
一些有意思的科学应用，尤其是在……
use cases. Um especially in the
应用，尤其是在……
use cases. Um especially in the chemistry work we did uh with with uh
应用，尤其是在我们与……合作开展的化学研究中。
chemistry work we did uh with with uh
我们与……合作开展的化学研究。
chemistry work we did uh with with uh with open chemistry. Um and there's
我们与 Open Chemistry 合作开展的化学研究。而且……
with open chemistry. Um and there's
与 Open Chemistry 合作。而且……
with open chemistry. Um and there's they're certainly useful um for those
与 Open Chemistry 合作。GNN 对这类应用确实很有用，
they're certainly useful um for those
GNN 对这类应用确实很有用，
they're certainly useful um for those types because you have very complex data
GNN 对这类应用确实很有用，因为数据非常复杂，
types because you have very complex data
因为数据非常复杂，
types because you have very complex data that you're you're trying to embed that
因为你要嵌入模型的数据非常复杂，
that you're you're trying to embed that
你要把这些……
that you're you're trying to embed that information into the model. So, a lot of
你要把这些信息嵌入模型。所以涉及很多……
information into the model. So, a lot of
信息嵌入模型。所以涉及很多……
information into the model. So, a lot of different modalities, but I'm I'm
信息嵌入模型。所以涉及很多不同模态，但我……
different modalities, but I'm I'm
不同模态，但我……
different modalities, but I'm I'm probably far from a GNN expert.
不同模态，但我远称不上 GNN 专家。
probably far from a GNN expert.
远称不上 GNN 专家。
probably far from a GNN expert. >> Yeah.
远称不上 GNN 专家。对。
>> Yeah.
对。
>> Yeah. >> Yeah. I think the good answer is the one
对。对，我觉得比较好的回答是……
>> Yeah. I think the good answer is the one
对，我觉得比较好的回答是……
>> Yeah. I think the good answer is the one that Andrew made to the previous
对，我觉得 Andrew 对上一个问题的回答很好。
that Andrew made to the previous
Andrew 对上一个问题的回答。
that Andrew made to the previous question like, you know, if you have a
Andrew 对上一个问题的回答是：如果你有……
question like, you know, if you have a
如果你有……
question like, you know, if you have a particular like I think you should
如果你有具体问题，我觉得你应该……
particular like I think you should
有具体问题的话，我觉得你应该……
particular like I think you should probably file an issue against PyTorch
有具体问题的话，最好向 PyTorch……
probably file an issue against PyTorch
最好向 PyTorch……提交问题反馈。
probably file an issue against PyTorch Geometric and if they say that you know
最好向 PyTorch Geometric 提交问题反馈。如果他们说……
Geometric and if they say that you know
向 PyTorch Geometric 反馈。如果他们说……
Geometric and if they say that you know that there's a fundamental issue in
如果他们说 PyTorch 存在根本性问题，
that there's a fundamental issue in
存在根本性问题，
that there's a fundamental issue in PyTorch, you should file an issue
如果 PyTorch 存在根本性问题，你应该提交问题反馈……
PyTorch, you should file an issue
你应该向 PyTorch 提交问题反馈……
PyTorch, you should file an issue against us because we don't know until
你应该向我们提交问题反馈，因为我们只有……
against us because we don't know until
向我们反馈，因为我们只有……
against us because we don't know until we like hear about it. But like I would
向我们反馈，因为你不说，我们就不知道。不过我会……
we like hear about it. But like I would
我们很想听听。不过我觉得……
we like hear about it. But like I would say GNN's is not the most hot topic in
我们很想听听。不过我觉得，GNN 不是最热门的话题，
say GNN's is not the most hot topic in
我觉得 GNN 不是最热门的话题，
say GNN's is not the most hot topic in uh artificial intelligence in the last
我觉得 GNN 不是过去一段时间人工智能领域最热门的话题，
uh artificial intelligence in the last
过去一段时间，人工智能领域……
uh artificial intelligence in the last 12 months and so we don't like have a
过去 12 个月，人工智能领域……所以我们没有
12 months and so we don't like have a
过去 12 个月，所以我们没有
12 months and so we don't like have a particular focus on those
过去 12 个月，所以我们没有特别关注这类模型。
particular focus on those
特别关注这类模型，
particular focus on those but they should work and there shouldn't
特别关注这类模型，但它们应该能运行，也不该
but they should work and there shouldn't
但它们应该能运行，也不该
but they should work and there shouldn't be any limitations other than inherent
但它们应该能运行，除了架构本身的限制，不该有其他限制。
be any limitations other than inherent
除了架构本身的限制，不该有其他限制。
be any limitations other than inherent limitations in the architecture that
除了架构本身固有的限制，不该有其他限制，比如
limitations in the architecture that
架构本身的限制，比如
limitations in the architecture that like post training is somewhat slow
架构本身的限制，比如后训练有点慢，
like post training is somewhat slow
后训练有点慢，
like post training is somewhat slow because your graph propagation like
后训练有点慢，因为图上的信息传播，
because your graph propagation like
因为图上的信息传播，
because your graph propagation like backward propagation across the graph
因为图上的信息传播，比如沿图反向传播，
backward propagation across the graph
沿图反向传播，
backward propagation across the graph like introduce lots and lots of
沿图反向传播，会产生大量
like introduce lots and lots of
会产生大量
like introduce lots and lots of gradients which are somewhat unstable
会产生大量不太稳定的梯度，
gradients which are somewhat unstable
不太稳定的梯度，
gradients which are somewhat unstable and you need to like be very careful
梯度不太稳定，所以你得格外小心，
and you need to like be very careful
所以你得格外小心，
and you need to like be very careful because the trading electron rate should
所以你得格外小心，因为训练学习率得
because the trading electron rate should
因为训练学习率得
because the trading electron rate should be very low but that's not new. [snorts]
因为训练学习率得非常低。不过这也不是什么新问题。（轻哼）
>> Okay, thank you folks for taking a swing
好的，谢谢各位尝试回答
>> Okay, thank you folks for taking a swing at a challenging question.
好的，谢谢各位尝试回答这个难题。
>> Um Adam's uh question is next. Um how
接下来是 Adam 的问题：
>> Um Adam's uh question is next. Um how does an inductor choose between kublos
接下来是 Adam 的问题：Inductor 如何在 cuBLAS、
does an inductor choose between kublos
Inductor 如何在 cuBLAS、
does an inductor choose between kublos cutless and cute DSL kernels and does
Inductor 如何在 cuBLAS、CUTLASS 和 CuTe DSL 内核之间选择？
cutless and cute DSL kernels and does
CUTLASS 和 CuTe DSL 内核之间如何选择？
cutless and cute DSL kernels and does the user have any flexibility here? Is
CUTLASS 和 CuTe DSL 内核之间如何选择？用户能否自行调整？
the user have any flexibility here? Is
用户能否自行调整？这个
the user have any flexibility here? Is this cho is this choice exposed um uh
用户能否自行调整？这个选择是否开放给用户？
this cho is this choice exposed um uh
这个选择是否开放给用户？
this cho is this choice exposed um uh for example in FX uh layer?
这个选择是否开放给用户？比如在 FX 层？
for example in FX uh layer?
比如在 FX 层？
for example in FX uh layer? >> So I can probably answer this one. Well
比如在 FX 层？我大概可以回答这个问题。
>> So I can probably answer this one. Well
我大概可以回答这个问题。嗯，
>> So I can probably answer this one. Well like inductor tries to do the best perf
我大概可以回答这个问题。Inductor 会尽量取得最佳性能，
like inductor tries to do the best perf
Inductor 会尽量取得最佳性能，
like inductor tries to do the best perf right and it like tries to select the
Inductor 会尽量取得最佳性能，并尝试选出
right and it like tries to select the
并尝试选出
right and it like tries to select the ones that it believes will be better. Uh
并尝试选出它认为性能更好的内核。
ones that it believes will be better. Uh
它认为更好的那些。嗯
ones that it believes will be better. Uh you can also do max autotune when it
它认为更好的那些。嗯，你也可以使用最大自动调优，当它……
you can also do max autotune when it
你也可以使用最大自动调优，当它……
you can also do max autotune when it should just dutifully iterate over all
你也可以使用最大自动调优，让它逐一遍历所有……
should just dutifully iterate over all
逐一遍历所有……
should just dutifully iterate over all the options and try to pick the one that
逐一遍历所有选项，并尝试选出……
the options and try to pick the one that
这些选项，并尝试选出……
the options and try to pick the one that works for you. Also there is a hardware
这些选项，并尝试选出适合你的方案。另外还有硬件……
works for you. Also there is a hardware
适合你的方案。另外还有硬件……
works for you. Also there is a hardware limitations and there should be knobs in
适合你的方案。另外还有硬件限制，应该有一些开关……
limitations and there should be knobs in
硬件限制，应该有一些开关……
limitations and there should be knobs in the inductor to say use or doesn't use
硬件限制，Inductor 里应该有开关来指定是否使用……
the inductor to say use or doesn't use
在 Inductor 里指定是否使用……
the inductor to say use or doesn't use certain backends but I don't think there
在 Inductor 里指定是否使用某些后端，但我觉得……
certain backends but I don't think there
某些后端，但我觉得……
certain backends but I don't think there is a very easy way to express it through
某些后端，但我觉得没有很简便的方法……
is a very easy way to express it through
没有很简便的方法……
is a very easy way to express it through the FX graph but you can suggest this
没有很简便的方法通过 FX 图表达，不过你可以把这点……
the FX graph but you can suggest this
通过 FX 图表达，不过你可以把这点……
the FX graph but you can suggest this one as an improvement. So once again
通过 FX 图表达，不过你可以把这点作为改进建议。所以还是那句话……
one as an improvement. So once again
作为改进建议。所以还是那句话……
one as an improvement. So once again file an issue saying that you want this
作为改进建议。所以还是那句话：提个 issue，说明你想要这个功能……
file an issue saying that you want this
提个 issue，说明你想要这个功能……
file an issue saying that you want this one but I kind of want you to think
提个 issue，说明你想要这个功能，但我希望你也想想……
one but I kind of want you to think
但我希望你也想想……
one but I kind of want you to think about it like why do you want to be
但我希望你也想想，为什么要……
about it like why do you want to be
想想为什么要……
about it like why do you want to be explicit like don't we want to converge
想想为什么要明确指定它。我们难道不希望统一到……
explicit like don't we want to converge
明确指定它。我们难道不希望统一到……
explicit like don't we want to converge to one model and I suspect that cute DSL
明确指定它。我们难道不希望统一到一种模型吗？我猜 CuTe DSL……
to one model and I suspect that cute DSL
统一到一种模型吗？我猜 CuTe DSL……
to one model and I suspect that cute DSL is probably something we kind of leaning
统一到一种模型吗？我猜 CuTe DSL 可能是我们……
is probably something we kind of leaning
可能是我们……
is probably something we kind of leaning towards on the most modern architectures
可能是我们在最新架构上倾向采用的方向……
towards on the most modern architectures
在最新架构上倾向采用的方向……
towards on the most modern architectures like blackfields and probably have
在 Blackwell 等最新架构上倾向采用的方向，而且可能……
like blackfields and probably have
比如 Blackwell，而且可能……
like blackfields and probably have common verbs but I think like kublast
比如 Blackwell，可能还有一些共通的操作，但我觉得像 cuBLAS……
common verbs but I think like kublast
有一些共通的操作，但我觉得像 cuBLAS……
common verbs but I think like kublast will probably give you a much better
有一些共通的操作，但我觉得 cuBLAS 可能会带来好得多的……
will probably give you a much better
可能会带来好得多的……
will probably give you a much better perf on and cutless on an architectures
可能在某些架构上，cuBLAS 和 CUTLASS 的性能会好得多……
perf on and cutless on an architectures
在某些架构上，cuBLAS 和 CUTLASS 的性能……
perf on and cutless on an architectures because there's kind of a cut off there.
在某些架构上，cuBLAS 和 CUTLASS 的性能会更好，因为这里有个分界点。
>> Okay, any other uh responses on this
好，关于这个问题还有其他回应吗？
>> Okay, any other uh responses on this one? Okay, let's move to the next one.
好，关于这个问题还有其他回应吗？那我们进入下一个问题。
one? Okay, let's move to the next one.
那我们进入下一个问题。
one? Okay, let's move to the next one. We have I love that there are so many
那我们进入下一个问题。观众提了这么多……
We have I love that there are so many
观众提了这么多……
We have I love that there are so many audience questions. So, thank you folks
观众提了这么多问题，我很高兴。谢谢大家。
audience questions. So, thank you folks
观众提问。谢谢大家。
audience questions. So, thank you folks for putting those in. Uh I think that's
观众提问。谢谢大家提交问题。我觉得这
for putting those in. Uh I think that's
谢谢大家提交问题。我觉得这
for putting those in. Uh I think that's great. Okay. Um we have somebody from
谢谢大家提交问题。我觉得这很好。好，有位来自
great. Okay. Um we have somebody from
很好。好，有位来自
great. Okay. Um we have somebody from LinkedIn who asked uh which PyTorch 20
很好。好，有位来自 LinkedIn 的人问，PyTorch 20
LinkedIn who asked uh which PyTorch 20
LinkedIn 上有人问，PyTorch 20
LinkedIn who asked uh which PyTorch 20 uh 21.14 uh feature gives the biggest
LinkedIn 上有人问，PyTorch 20、21.14 的哪个功能
uh 21.14 uh feature gives the biggest
21.14 的哪个功能带来的
uh 21.14 uh feature gives the biggest performance boost for production LLM
21.14 的哪个功能最能提升生产环境中的 LLM
performance boost for production LLM
最能提升生产环境中的 LLM
performance boost for production LLM inference and how easy is it uh to
最能提升生产环境中的 LLM 推理性能？采用起来又有多容易？
inference and how easy is it uh to
LLM 推理性能？采用起来又有多容易？
inference and how easy is it uh to adopt? Um
LLM 推理性能？采用起来又有多容易？嗯。
adopt? Um
采用起来？嗯。
adopt? Um I don't know that we did an ablation
采用起来？嗯。我不确定我们是否做过消融实验。
I don't know that we did an ablation
我不确定我们是否做过消融实验。
I don't know that we did an ablation study of the various different features
我不确定我们是否对各项功能做过消融实验。
study of the various different features
对各项功能做消融实验。
study of the various different features but does anybody have a um have a
对各项功能做消融实验。不过有人有什么
but does anybody have a um have a
不过有人有什么
but does anybody have a um have a thought here? I suspect cudgraphs uh
不过有人有什么想法吗？我猜可能是 CUDA Graphs。
thought here? I suspect cudgraphs uh
有什么想法吗？我猜可能是 CUDA Graphs。
thought here? I suspect cudgraphs uh ability to trace more functions, avoid
有什么想法吗？我猜可能是 CUDA Graphs 能追踪更多函数，避免
ability to trace more functions, avoid
能追踪更多函数，避免
ability to trace more functions, avoid cudograph breaks and ability to like
能追踪更多函数，避免 CUDA Graph 中断，还能
cudograph breaks and ability to like
避免 CUDA Graph 中断，还能
cudograph breaks and ability to like trace coms uh would be the one maybe
避免 CUDA Graph 中断，还能追踪通信操作。可能是这个。
trace coms uh would be the one maybe
追踪通信操作。可能是这个。
trace coms uh would be the one maybe some of the torch compiler features but
追踪通信操作。也可能是 Torch 编译器的某些功能，不过
some of the torch compiler features but
也可能是 Torch 编译器的某些功能，不过
some of the torch compiler features but that depends on the frameworks that
也可能是 Torch 编译器的某些功能，不过这取决于你使用的
that depends on the frameworks that
这取决于你使用的
that depends on the frameworks that you're using for your LLM inference,
这取决于你用什么框架做 LLM 推理，
you're using for your LLM inference,
你用什么框架做 LLM 推理，
you're using for your LLM inference, right?
你用什么框架做 LLM 推理，对吧？
right?
对吧？
right? And they should be pretty easy to adopt.
对吧？这些功能应该很容易采用。
And they should be pretty easy to adopt.
这些功能应该很容易采用。
And they should be pretty easy to adopt. So like lots of those features were
这些功能应该很容易采用。很多功能都是
So like lots of those features were
很多功能都是
So like lots of those features were driven by like asks from users such as
很多功能都是应用户需求而开发的，比如
driven by like asks from users such as
应用户需求而开发的，比如
driven by like asks from users such as like VLM or SJAN. So I hope that they
应 VLM 或 SJAN 等用户的需求而开发。所以我希望他们
like VLM or SJAN. So I hope that they
比如 VLM 或 SJAN。所以我希望他们
like VLM or SJAN. So I hope that they will be incorporating those features
比如 VLM 或 SJAN。所以我希望他们能把这些功能
will be incorporating those features
能把这些功能
will be incorporating those features into their frameworks and NVJMS is also
能把这些功能整合进他们的框架。NVJMS 也是
into their frameworks and NVJMS is also
整合进他们的框架。NVJMS 也是
into their frameworks and NVJMS is also a great one that probably important for
整合进他们的框架。NVJMS 也很棒，可能对……很重要。
a great one that probably important for
这点很好，可能对……很重要
a great one that probably important for performance.
这点很好，可能对性能很重要。
>> Okay.
好的。
>> Okay. >> Yeah, I think NVJ specifically on black
好的。我觉得 NVJ 尤其是在 Black 上……
>> Yeah, I think NVJ specifically on black
我觉得 NVJ 尤其是在 Black 上……
>> Yeah, I think NVJ specifically on black with low precision I think it's
我觉得 NVJ 尤其是在 Black 上使用低精度时……
with low precision I think it's
使用低精度时，我觉得这……
with low precision I think it's important. Yeah.
使用低精度时，我觉得这很重要。对。
>> Okay. Um the next one is from Asam. Uh,
好的。下一个问题来自 Asam。
>> Okay. Um the next one is from Asam. Uh, and I might be mispronouncing there. I
好的。下一个问题来自 Asam。我可能念错了名字，
and I might be mispronouncing there. I
我可能念错了名字，
and I might be mispronouncing there. I apologize if I did. Um, PyTorch, uh,
如果念错了，抱歉。PyTorch……
apologize if I did. Um, PyTorch, uh,
apologize if I did. Um, PyTorch, uh, 21.14 makes fault tolerance a first
如果念错了，抱歉。PyTorch 21.14 将容错提升为一等……
21.14 makes fault tolerance a first
21.14 将容错提升为一等……
21.14 makes fault tolerance a first class CTN concept. Does the new model
21.14 将容错提升为一等 CTN 概念。新模型能否……
class CTN concept. Does the new model
一等 CTN 概念。新模型能否……
class CTN concept. Does the new model allow a training job to recover from a
一等 CTN 概念。新模型能否让训练任务从……
allow a training job to recover from a
让训练任务从……恢复，
allow a training job to recover from a failed rank without reconstructing the
让训练任务从某个 rank 故障中恢复，而无须重建……
failed rank without reconstructing the
某个 rank 故障中恢复，而无须重建……
failed rank without reconstructing the entire distributed process group? And
某个 rank 故障中恢复，而无须重建整个分布式进程组？另外，
entire distributed process group? And
整个分布式进程组？另外，
entire distributed process group? And what state is expected to remain valid
整个分布式进程组？另外，恢复后哪些状态预计仍然有效？
what state is expected to remain valid
哪些状态预计仍然有效？
what state is expected to remain valid after recovery?
恢复后哪些状态预计仍然有效？
Do we have any anyone here who's expert
这里有谁熟悉……
Do we have any anyone here who's expert in the new um torchcom's model?
这里有谁熟悉新的 torchcom 模型吗？
>> [clears throat]
（清嗓子）
>> [clears throat] >> None of us are.
（清嗓子）我们都不熟悉。
>> None of us are.
我们都不熟悉。
>> None of us are. >> Okay. Not me.
我们都不熟悉。好的，我也不熟悉。
>> Okay. Not me.
好的，我也不熟悉。
>> Okay. Not me. >> I think we're I think we're going to
好的，我也不熟悉。我想我们得……
>> I think we're I think we're going to
我想我们得……
>> I think we're I think we're going to have to refer this question to um uh to
我想我们得把这个问题……
have to refer this question to um uh to
得把这个问题……
have to refer this question to um uh to the discussion. So this would be a great
得把这个问题转到讨论区。这会是个很好的……
the discussion. So this would be a great
转到讨论区。这会是个很好的……
the discussion. So this would be a great question for example for discuss
转到讨论区。比如，这个问题很适合在 discuss 上提。
question for example for discuss
比如，这个问题很适合在 discuss 上提。
question for example for discuss uh.pytorch or dev discuss. Um so I think
比如在 discuss.pytorch 或 dev discuss 上提。我想，
uh.pytorch or dev discuss. Um so I think
在 discuss.pytorch 或 dev discuss 上提。我想，
uh.pytorch or dev discuss. Um so I think uh the the specific uh details about
在 discuss.pytorch 或 dev discuss 上提。我想，具体细节……
uh the the specific uh details about
具体细节……
uh the the specific uh details about like what part of the state uh would be
具体来说，状态的哪些部分……
like what part of the state uh would be
状态的哪些部分……
like what part of the state uh would be expected to remain valid uh is the kind
状态的哪些部分预计仍然有效，这类问题……
expected to remain valid uh is the kind
预计仍然有效，这类问题……
expected to remain valid uh is the kind of thing one of the distributed uh uh
预计仍然有效，这类问题得由分布式领域的……
of thing one of the distributed uh uh
关于这件事，分布式领域的一位……
of thing one of the distributed uh uh engineers would be really strong
关于这件事，一位分布式工程师应该很在行。
engineers would be really strong
工程师应该很在行。
engineers would be really strong rice question.
工程师应该很在行。好问题。
rice question.
好问题。
rice question. >> Yeah.
好问题。>> 对。
>> Yeah.
>> 对。
>> Yeah. >> Yep. Exactly. But I want to just flag
>> 对。>> 没错。不过我想提醒一下
>> Yep. Exactly. But I want to just flag
>> 没错。不过我想提醒一下
>> Yep. Exactly. But I want to just flag that this is experimental support and we
>> 没错。不过我想提醒一下，这项支持仍属实验性，我们
that this is experimental support and we
这项支持仍属实验性，我们
that this is experimental support and we indeed like seeking your feedback. So
这项支持仍属实验性，我们也很想听到你的反馈。所以
indeed like seeking your feedback. So
也很想听到你的反馈。所以
indeed like seeking your feedback. So please try to obtain into this like
也很想听到你的反馈。所以请试着启用这些功能，
please try to obtain into this like
请试着启用这些功能，
please try to obtain into this like nickel ch and other CTN default
请试着启用这些功能，比如 NCCL 和其他 c10d
nickel ch and other CTN default
NCCL 和其他 c10d
nickel ch and other CTN default tolerance features and let us know if
NCCL 和其他 c10d 容错功能，并告诉我们
tolerance features and let us know if
容错功能，并告诉我们
tolerance features and let us know if they work for you or not.
容错功能，并告诉我们它们是否适合你的场景。
they work for you or not.
它们是否适合你的场景。
they work for you or not. But yes, like a new model allows for a
它们是否适合你的场景。不过，新模型确实能让
But yes, like a new model allows for a
不过，新模型确实能让
But yes, like a new model allows for a more graceful recovery, but it doesn't
不过，新模型确实能让恢复过程更平稳，但它不能
more graceful recovery, but it doesn't
恢复过程更平稳，但它不能
more graceful recovery, but it doesn't guarantee that it will work out of the
恢复过程更平稳，但它不能保证功能
guarantee that it will work out of the
保证功能
guarantee that it will work out of the box. You probably need to like adjust
保证功能开箱即用。你可能需要调整
box. You probably need to like adjust
开箱即用。你可能需要调整
box. You probably need to like adjust your training pipeline to uh like take
开箱即用。你可能需要调整训练流程，才能
your training pipeline to uh like take
训练流程，才能
your training pipeline to uh like take benefit of that and like recognize this
训练流程，才能利用这一点，并将这种
benefit of that and like recognize this
利用这一点，并将这种
benefit of that and like recognize this error as recoverable. But yes, sounds
利用这一点，并将这种错误识别为可恢复错误。不过，
error as recoverable. But yes, sounds
错误识别为可恢复错误。不过，
error as recoverable. But yes, sounds like a great discuss question.
错误识别为可恢复错误。不过，这确实是个值得讨论的好问题。
>> Next question.
>> 下一个问题。
>> Next question. Yes, it's the um uh Shiva Shush um uh
>> 下一个问题。是 Shiva Shush 的问题，
Yes, it's the um uh Shiva Shush um uh
是 Shiva Shush 的问题，
Yes, it's the um uh Shiva Shush um uh again pronunciation caveat on Apple
是 Shiva Shush 的问题，名字读音可能有误：关于 Apple
again pronunciation caveat on Apple
名字读音可能有误：关于 Apple
again pronunciation caveat on Apple silicon uh 21.14 adds uh native linear
名字读音可能有误：在 Apple Silicon 上，21.14 增加了原生线性
silicon uh 21.14 adds uh native linear
在 Apple Silicon 上，21.14 增加了原生线性
silicon uh 21.14 adds uh native linear algebra and more metal kernels uh for
在 Apple Silicon 上，21.14 增加了原生线性代数支持和更多用于
algebra and more metal kernels uh for
代数支持和更多用于
algebra and more metal kernels uh for LLM decode on unified memory. Which path
代数支持和更多用于统一内存上大语言模型解码的 Metal 内核。哪条路径
LLM decode on unified memory. Which path
统一内存上大语言模型解码的 Metal 内核。哪条路径
LLM decode on unified memory. Which path actually moves the needle uh versus 2.13
统一内存上大语言模型解码的 Metal 内核。与 2.13 相比，哪条路径真正带来了提升：
actually moves the needle uh versus 2.13
与 2.13 相比，哪条路径真正带来了提升：
actually moves the needle uh versus 2.13 the new metal kernels or inductor
与 2.13 相比，哪条路径真正带来了提升：新的 Metal 内核，还是 Inductor？
the new metal kernels or inductor
新的 Metal 内核或 Inductor
the new metal kernels or inductor picking up better epilogs? Any measured
新的 Metal 内核或 Inductor 用上了更好的尾部计算？有测量过
picking up better epilogs? Any measured
用上了更好的尾部计算？有测量过
picking up better epilogs? Any measured tokens per second deltas um on the M
用上了更好的尾部计算？有测量过 M 系列上每秒 token 数的变化吗？
tokens per second deltas um on the M
M 系列上每秒 token 数的变化
tokens per second deltas um on the M series or fixed to code loop? And I I
M 系列上每秒 token 数的变化，还是只针对代码循环？我，我
series or fixed to code loop? And I I
系列，还是只针对代码循环？我，我
series or fixed to code loop? And I I believe Nikita, you've been really
系列，还是只针对代码循环？我想 Nikita，你之前一直
believe Nikita, you've been really
我想 Nikita，你之前一直
believe Nikita, you've been really active in the past with some of the
我想 Nikita，你之前一直积极参与一些
active in the past with some of the
之前积极参与一些
active in the past with some of the Apple changes. So I'm gonna toss this
之前积极参与一些 Apple 方面的改动。这个问题我就交给
Apple changes. So I'm gonna toss this
Apple 方面的改动。这个问题我就交给
Apple changes. So I'm gonna toss this one to you.
Apple 方面的改动。这个问题就交给你了。
one to you.
交给你了。
one to you. >> Sure. Well, first of all, we don't
交给你了。>> 好的。首先，我们没有
>> Sure. Well, first of all, we don't
>> 好的。首先，我们没有
>> Sure. Well, first of all, we don't specifically measure and also it's very
>> 好的。首先，我们没有专门测量过，而且这也很
specifically measure and also it's very
专门测量过，而且这也很
specifically measure and also it's very subjective because like different M
专门测量过，而且这也很难一概而论，因为不同的 M
subjective because like different M
难一概而论，因为不同的 M
subjective because like different M series have a different behavior. But
难一概而论，因为不同的 M 系列表现不同。不过
series have a different behavior. But
系列表现不同。不过
series have a different behavior. But there is one feature that was introduced
系列表现不同。不过，214 中引入了一项功能
there is one feature that was introduced
214 中引入了一项功能
there is one feature that was introduced in 214. we use uh like a new apple
214 中引入了一项功能。我们用了 Apple 的一项新
in 214. we use uh like a new apple
在 214 中。我们用了 Apple 的一项新
in 214. we use uh like a new apple silicon or like metal framework feature
在 214 中。我们用了一项新的 Apple Silicon 或 Metal 框架功能
silicon or like metal framework feature
Apple Silicon 或 Metal 框架功能
silicon or like metal framework feature called metal performance primitives
Apple Silicon 或 Metal 框架功能，叫作 Metal Performance Primitives
called metal performance primitives
叫作 Metal Performance Primitives
called metal performance primitives which is similar to uh I don't know
叫作 Metal Performance Primitives，它有点类似于，嗯，我也说不准
which is similar to uh I don't know
它有点类似于，嗯，我也说不准
which is similar to uh I don't know probably to cut in a sense so it's very
它有点类似于，嗯，我也说不准，某种意义上可能类似 CUDA，所以它很
probably to cut in a sense so it's very
某种意义上可能类似 CUDA，所以它很
probably to cut in a sense so it's very different it allows one to express
某种意义上可能类似 CUDA，但它很不一样：它允许你表达
different it allows one to express
不一样：它允许你表达
different it allows one to express matrix multiplication it's done in eager
不一样：它允许你表达矩阵乘法；运算在即时模式下
matrix multiplication it's done in eager
矩阵乘法；运算在即时模式下
matrix multiplication it's done in eager mode and it can in some cases produce
矩阵乘法；运算在即时模式下进行，有时能带来
mode and it can in some cases produce
模式下进行，有时能带来
mode and it can in some cases produce just of this particular operation like
模式下进行，有时仅就这个运算而言，能带来
just of this particular operation like
仅就这个运算而言，能带来
just of this particular operation like 3x or even sometimes measured 5x but
仅就这个运算而言，能带来 3 倍提升，有时甚至测到 5 倍，但
3x or even sometimes measured 5x but
3 倍提升，有时甚至测到 5 倍，但
3x or even sometimes measured 5x but this is more like a synthetic benchmark
3 倍提升，有时甚至测到 5 倍，但这更像是合成基准测试的结果
this is more like a synthetic benchmark
这更像是合成基准测试的结果
this is more like a synthetic benchmark not an end to end one performance boost
这更像是合成基准测试的结果，不是端到端的性能提升
not an end to end one performance boost
不是端到端的性能提升
not an end to end one performance boost so you should give it tries there is no
不是端到端的性能提升，所以你可以试试；目前没有
so you should give it tries there is no
所以你应该试试，没有……
so you should give it tries there is no inductor peing better epilogues
所以你应该试试；Inductor 不一定能生成更好的尾声代码。
inductor peing better epilogues
Inductor 生成更好的尾声代码
inductor peing better epilogues necessarily for Apple silicon and yes we
Inductor 在 Apple 芯片上不一定能生成更好的尾声代码。对，我们……
necessarily for Apple silicon and yes we
对于 Apple 芯片未必如此。对，我们……
necessarily for Apple silicon and yes we we don't do measurements because again
对于 Apple 芯片未必如此。对，我们没有做测量，因为……
we don't do measurements because again
我们没有做测量，因为……
we don't do measurements because again it's kind of you cannot measure on the
我们没有做测量，因为你没法只测……
it's kind of you cannot measure on the
因为你没法只测……
it's kind of you cannot measure on the pietorch alone you need to measure on a
因为你没法只测 PyTorch，还得测某个……
pietorch alone you need to measure on a
光测 PyTorch 不够，还得测某个……
pietorch alone you need to measure on a particular framework but you can
光测 PyTorch 不够，还得测具体框架。不过你可以……
particular framework but you can
具体框架。不过你可以……
particular framework but you can probably check those numbers at hugging
具体框架。不过你或许能在 Hugging……
probably check those numbers at hugging
你或许能在 Hugging……查到那些数据
probably check those numbers at hugging face transformers on one of their um
你或许能在 Hugging Face Transformers 的某个……查到那些数据
face transformers on one of their um
Face Transformers 的某个……
face transformers on one of their um frameworks if this is what you're using
如果你用的是 Hugging Face Transformers 的某个框架……
frameworks if this is what you're using
如果你用的是这个框架……
frameworks if this is what you're using for your inference pipelines
如果你的推理流程用的是这个框架。
>> okay Um yes, let's do so. Uh Shibash had
>> 好，那就这样。Shibash 刚才……
>> okay Um yes, let's do so. Uh Shibash had three several questions in a row, so I
>> 好，那就这样。Shibash 连着问了好几个问题，所以我……
three several questions in a row, so I
连着问了好几个问题，所以我……
three several questions in a row, so I don't know if we'll get to all of them,
连着问了好几个问题，所以我不确定能否全部回答。
don't know if we'll get to all of them,
我不确定能否全部回答。
don't know if we'll get to all of them, but let's take this next one here.
我不确定能否全部回答，不过先看下一个。
but let's take this next one here.
不过先看下一个。
but let's take this next one here. [snorts] Uh the declarative uh dynamic
不过先看下一个。[轻哼] 声明式动态……
[snorts] Uh the declarative uh dynamic
[轻哼] 声明式动态……
[snorts] Uh the declarative uh dynamic spec looks useful for Asian workloads
[轻哼] 声明式动态规格似乎适合亚洲工作负载
spec looks useful for Asian workloads
这种规格似乎适合亚洲工作负载
spec looks useful for Asian workloads where context length um changes
这种规格似乎适合上下文长度会变化的亚洲工作负载
where context length um changes
这类工作负载的上下文长度会变化
where context length um changes midsession. Uh if the live shape set
上下文长度会在会话中途变化。如果实际出现的形状集合……
midsession. Uh if the live shape set
会在会话中途变化。如果实际出现的形状集合……
midsession. Uh if the live shape set expands beyond the declared spec, does
会在会话中途变化。如果实际出现的形状集合超出声明的规格，会……
expands beyond the declared spec, does
如果超出声明的规格，会……
expands beyond the declared spec, does inductor recompile quietly or can you
如果超出声明的规格，Inductor 会悄悄重新编译，还是可以……
inductor recompile quietly or can you
Inductor 会悄悄重新编译，还是可以……
inductor recompile quietly or can you make it a hard fail uh so that you can
Inductor 会悄悄重新编译，还是可以让它直接报错，以便……
make it a hard fail uh so that you can
让它直接报错，以便……
make it a hard fail uh so that you can have more predictable latency? Um does
让它直接报错，让延迟更可预测？
have more predictable latency? Um does
让延迟更可预测？那么……
have more predictable latency? Um does anybody know the answer to this one? Um
让延迟更可预测？有人知道这个问题的答案吗？
anybody know the answer to this one? Um
有人知道这个问题的答案吗？
anybody know the answer to this one? Um >> I don't know on top of my head but
有人知道这个问题的答案吗？>> 我一时想不起来，不过……
>> I don't know on top of my head but
>> 我一时想不起来，不过……
>> I don't know on top of my head but knowing the development patterns of the
>> 我一时想不起来，不过按 Inductor 的开发习惯……
knowing the development patterns of the
按它的开发习惯……
knowing the development patterns of the inductor I suspect there should be an op
按 Inductor 的开发习惯，我猜应该有个选项。
inductor I suspect there should be an op
我觉得 Inductor 应该有个操作
inductor I suspect there should be an op to make it fail
我觉得 Inductor 应该有个操作，能让它失败
to make it fail
让它失败
to make it fail >> but there also should be a knob like
让它失败。但也应该有个开关
>> but there also should be a knob like
但也应该有个开关
>> but there also should be a knob like that was a default orch compile behavior
但也应该有个开关。那曾是 torch.compile 的默认行为
that was a default orch compile behavior
那曾是 torch.compile 的默认行为
that was a default orch compile behavior for quite some time that like if it
很长一段时间里，那都是 torch.compile 的默认行为：如果它
for quite some time that like if it
很长一段时间里，如果它
for quite some time that like if it fails to do something instead of ering
没能完成某项操作，它不会报错
fails to do something instead of ering
fails to do something instead of ering out it just falls back to either or like
没能完成某项操作时，它不会报错，而是回退
out it just falls back to either or like
而是回退
out it just falls back to either or like to the previous behavior. So there are
而是回退到之前的行为。所以两种
to the previous behavior. So there are
回退到之前的行为。所以两种
to the previous behavior. So there are both nodes exist but you should ask this
回退到之前的行为。所以两种模式都存在，但你应该问问
both nodes exist but you should ask this
两种模式都存在，但你应该问问
both nodes exist but you should ask this question and de discuss. Um it's kind of
两种模式都存在，但你应该提出这个问题，讨论一下。嗯，这有点
question and de discuss. Um it's kind of
提出这个问题，讨论一下。嗯，这有点
question and de discuss. Um it's kind of yeah hard to know all the specifics.
提出这个问题，讨论一下。嗯，所有细节确实很难弄清楚。
yeah hard to know all the specifics.
对，所有细节确实很难弄清楚。
yeah hard to know all the specifics. >> Yeah I feel I I feel I feel like the if
对，所有细节确实很难弄清楚。对，我觉得，如果
>> Yeah I feel I I feel I feel like the if
对，我觉得，如果
>> Yeah I feel I I feel I feel like the if we don't already have a knob to do this
对，我觉得，如果我们还没有这样的开关
we don't already have a knob to do this
如果我们还没有这样的开关
we don't already have a knob to do this this would be a knob that that the team
如果我们还没有这样的开关，团队应该会接受
this would be a knob that that the team
团队应该会接受这个开关
this would be a knob that that the team would likely receive. Well um because
团队应该会接受这个开关。嗯，因为
would likely receive. Well um because
应该会接受。嗯，因为
would likely receive. Well um because that that latency uh predictability is
应该会接受。嗯，因为延迟的可预测性
that that latency uh predictability is
因为延迟的可预测性
that that latency uh predictability is is pretty important to a lot of use
因为延迟的可预测性对很多使用场景
is pretty important to a lot of use
对很多使用场景都很重要
is pretty important to a lot of use cases. Okay. Um let's go ahead and move
对很多使用场景都很重要。好，我们继续
cases. Okay. Um let's go ahead and move
好，我们继续
cases. Okay. Um let's go ahead and move on to the to the next uh question in the
好，我们继续看下一个问题
on to the to the next uh question in the
看列表里的下一个问题
on to the to the next uh question in the list here. Um, how will dropping a CUDA
看列表里的下一个问题。取消提供 CUDA
list here. Um, how will dropping a CUDA
列表里的问题：取消提供 CUDA
list here. Um, how will dropping a CUDA 12 wheels in 2.15 affect downstream uh
列表里的问题：在 2.15 中取消提供 CUDA 12 的 wheel 包，会怎样影响下游
12 wheels in 2.15 affect downstream uh
在 2.15 中取消提供 CUDA 12 的 wheel 包，会怎样影响下游
12 wheels in 2.15 affect downstream uh C++ libr uh libraries uh or binaries for
在 2.15 中取消提供 CUDA 12 的 wheel 包，会怎样影响下游的 C++ 库或二进制文件
C++ libr uh libraries uh or binaries for
下游的 C++ 库或二进制文件
C++ libr uh libraries uh or binaries for for projects such as to sharp, but I
下游的 C++ 库或二进制文件，比如 TorchSharp 这样的项目
for projects such as to sharp, but I
比如 TorchSharp 这样的项目，不过我
for projects such as to sharp, but I know there's there's others. Um, Andre,
比如 TorchSharp 这样的项目，不过我知道还有其他项目。嗯，Andre，
know there's there's others. Um, Andre,
我知道还有其他项目。嗯，Andre，
know there's there's others. Um, Andre, do you want to take this one?
我知道还有其他项目。嗯，Andre，这个问题你来回答吗？
do you want to take this one?
这个问题你来回答吗？
do you want to take this one? >> Yeah. Yes. Uh, so basically I think
这个问题你来回答吗？对。嗯，基本上我觉得
>> Yeah. Yes. Uh, so basically I think
对。嗯，我觉得基本上
>> Yeah. Yes. Uh, so basically I think right now it would be good time for you
对。嗯，我觉得现在是个好时机
right now it would be good time for you
现在是个好时机
right now it would be good time for you to start planning to migrating for coder
现在是时候开始规划迁移到 CUDA 13 了
to start planning to migrating for coder
开始规划迁移到 CUDA
to start planning to migrating for coder 13 and probably the best version would
开始规划迁移到 CUDA 13，最佳版本可能是
13 and probably the best version would
13，最佳版本可能是
13 and probably the best version would be 13.2 two since this is going to be
13，最佳版本可能是 13.2.2，因为它将是
be 13.2 two since this is going to be
13.2.2，因为它将是
be 13.2 two since this is going to be our um stable version for the next 2.15
13.2.2，因为它将是下一个 2.15 版本的
our um stable version for the next 2.15
我们下一个 2.15 版本的稳定版
our um stable version for the next 2.15 release. Um and yeah, I think it's and
我们下一个 2.15 版本的稳定版。嗯，我觉得
release. Um and yeah, I think it's and
版本。嗯，我觉得
release. Um and yeah, I think it's and if you still want to use CUDA2.x, you
版本。嗯，如果你还想用 CUDA 2.x，
if you still want to use CUDA2.x, you
如果你还想用 CUDA 2.x，
if you still want to use CUDA2.x, you should be able to compile yourself from
如果你还想用 CUDA 2.x，应该可以自行从源码
should be able to compile yourself from
应该可以自行从源码编译
should be able to compile yourself from the source. So this is should still be
应该可以自行从源码编译。所以这应该仍然
the source. So this is should still be
从源码编译。所以这应该仍然
the source. So this is should still be supported. So you can take a look at how
从源码编译。所以这应该仍受支持。你可以看看
supported. So you can take a look at how
仍受支持。你可以看看
supported. So you can take a look at how we compile liptor binaries and basically
仍受支持。你可以看看我们如何编译 libtorch 二进制文件，然后
we compile liptor binaries and basically
我们如何编译 libtorch 二进制文件，然后
we compile liptor binaries and basically duplicate the workflow and compile it
我们如何编译 libtorch 二进制文件，再照着流程自己编译
duplicate the workflow and compile it
照着流程自己编译
duplicate the workflow and compile it yourself on your workers. um that that
照着流程在你的工作机上自行编译。这
yourself on your workers. um that that
在你的工作机上自行编译。这
yourself on your workers. um that that could be an option for short term like
在你的工作机上自行编译。短期内这
could be an option for short term like
短期内这也是个办法，比如
could be an option for short term like if you cannot migrate uh faster um I
短期内这也是个办法，比如你暂时没法更快地迁移。
if you cannot migrate uh faster um I
如果你暂时没法更快地迁移，我
if you cannot migrate uh faster um I don't know maybe Nikita wants to chime
如果你暂时没法更快地迁移，我也不确定，也许 Nikita 想
don't know maybe Nikita wants to chime
我也不确定，也许 Nikita 想
don't know maybe Nikita wants to chime in here any additional
我也不确定，也许 Nikita 想补充几句
in here any additional
补充几句
in here any additional >> um sure I guess like uh uh two
还有什么补充吗？嗯，可以，我想说两点
>> um sure I guess like uh uh two
嗯，可以，我想说两点
>> um sure I guess like uh uh two question like two two points one is that
嗯，可以，我想说两点。第一点是
question like two two points one is that
我想说两点。第一点是
question like two two points one is that uh like if you're on an older GPU
第一点是，如果你用的是较老的 GPU，
uh like if you're on an older GPU
如果你用的是较老的 GPU，
uh like if you're on an older GPU unfortunately CUDA 13 doesn't support
如果你用的是较老的 GPU，很遗憾，CUDA 13 不支持
unfortunately CUDA 13 doesn't support
很遗憾，CUDA 13 不支持
unfortunately CUDA 13 doesn't support some of them so you have to stay on the
很遗憾，CUDA 13 不支持其中一些型号，所以你得继续用
some of them so you have to stay on the
其中一些型号，所以你得继续用
some of them so you have to stay on the older PyTorch versions but also one
其中一些型号，所以你得继续用旧版 PyTorch。另外，
older PyTorch versions but also one
旧版 PyTorch。另外，
older PyTorch versions but also one should not expect any performance
旧版 PyTorch。另外，也别指望有任何性能
should not expect any performance
别指望有任何性能提升
should not expect any performance uh gains or uh like new features for
别指望有任何性能提升或新功能
uh gains or uh like new features for
旧硬件的性能提升或新功能……
uh gains or uh like new features for this older hardware with new releases.
新版本给旧硬件带来的性能提升或新功能。
this older hardware with new releases.
新版本为旧硬件提供的功能。
this older hardware with new releases. So like there is no reason for you to
新版本为旧硬件提供的功能。所以你没有理由……
So like there is no reason for you to
所以你没有理由……
So like there is no reason for you to upgrade. You can continue using 214 uh
所以你没必要升级，旧项目可以继续用 2.14。
upgrade. You can continue using 214 uh
升级。你可以继续用 2.14……
upgrade. You can continue using 214 uh for your older like pipelines
升级。旧的流水线可以继续用 2.14。
for your older like pipelines
用于你以前的流水线。
for your older like pipelines and TPU binaries will still be there,
用于你以前的流水线，TPU 二进制包也还在。
and TPU binaries will still be there,
TPU 二进制包也还在。
and TPU binaries will still be there, right? I don't know how much to sharp is
TPU 二进制包也还在，对吧？我不太清楚 TorchSharp 的情况。
right? I don't know how much to sharp is
对吧？我不太清楚 TorchSharp 的情况。
right? I don't know how much to sharp is indeed about like I guess it's most
对吧？我不太清楚 TorchSharp 的实际情况，我猜它主要……
indeed about like I guess it's most
实际上，我猜它主要……
indeed about like I guess it's most frequently used on Windows and I don't
实际上，我猜它主要用在 Windows 上，但我不……
frequently used on Windows and I don't
常用在 Windows 上，但我不……
frequently used on Windows and I don't know how much of that is like
常用在 Windows 上，但我不知道其中有多少……
know how much of that is like
不知道其中有多少……
know how much of that is like relevant to people on Windows like using
不知道这对 Windows 用户有多大关系，比如使用……
relevant to people on Windows like using
对使用这些功能的 Windows 用户有多大关系……
relevant to people on Windows like using blackville features like like VFP4
对使用 Blackwell 特性的 Windows 用户有多大关系，比如 NVFP4。
blackville features like like VFP4
Blackwell 的特性，比如 NVFP4。
blackville features like like VFP4 because like not available. So use 214
Blackwell 的特性，比如 NVFP4，因为这些功能还用不了。所以用 2.14。
because like not available. So use 214
因为这些功能还用不了，所以用 2.14。
because like not available. So use 214 but also yeah like CUDA 12 was released
因为这些功能还用不了，所以用 2.14。不过 CUDA 12 也已经发布……
but also yeah like CUDA 12 was released
不过 CUDA 12 也已经发布……
but also yeah like CUDA 12 was released five years ago if I'm not mistaken. So
不过，如果我没记错，CUDA 12 是五年前发布的。所以……
five years ago if I'm not mistaken. So
如果我没记错，是五年前发布的。所以……
five years ago if I'm not mistaken. So it's it's a good time to upgrade like
如果我没记错，是五年前发布的。所以现在也该升级了。
it's it's a good time to upgrade like
现在也该升级了。
it's it's a good time to upgrade like ask yourself why do you need to be on
现在也该升级了。想想自己为什么还需要用……
ask yourself why do you need to be on
想想自己为什么还需要用……
ask yourself why do you need to be on CUDA 12 in 2026 or like heading towards
想想为什么到了 2026 年，你还需要用 CUDA 12，甚至快到……
CUDA 12 in 2026 or like heading towards
到了 2026 年，甚至快到 2027 年，还在用 CUDA 12。
CUDA 12 in 2026 or like heading towards 2027
2027 年。
2027 [snorts]
2027 年。（哼笑）
[snorts]
（哼笑）
[snorts] >> though I' though I've known people who
（哼笑）不过，我也认识一些人……
>> though I' though I've known people who
不过，我也认识一些人……
>> though I' though I've known people who have stayed on old CUDA versions for a
不过，我也认识一些人，一直沿用旧版 CUDA……
have stayed on old CUDA versions for a
一直沿用旧版 CUDA……
have stayed on old CUDA versions for a long time but but yes
一直沿用旧版 CUDA 很多年。不过，确实。
long time but but yes
很多年。不过，确实。
long time but but yes okay
很多年。不过，确实。好。
okay
好。
okay next question
好，下一个问题。
next question
下一个问题。
next question um okay so this one is a simple one and
下一个问题。嗯，好，这个问题很简单……
um okay so this one is a simple one and
嗯，好，这个问题很简单，
um okay so this one is a simple one and this uh came from the the community uh
嗯，好，这个问题很简单，来自社区。
this uh came from the the community uh
这个问题来自社区。
this uh came from the the community uh questions ahead of time uh if you're on
这是社区提前提交的问题。如果你用的是……
questions ahead of time uh if you're on
提前提交的问题：如果你用的是……
questions ahead of time uh if you're on AMD what change for uh rockcomm in 2.14.
提前提交的问题：如果你用 AMD，ROCm 在 PyTorch 2.14 中有什么变化？
AMD what change for uh rockcomm in 2.14.
如果用 AMD，ROCm 在 PyTorch 2.14 中有什么变化？
AMD what change for uh rockcomm in 2.14. Andre, do you want to talk to this one?
如果用 AMD，ROCm 在 PyTorch 2.14 中有什么变化？Andre，你来回答好吗？
Andre, do you want to talk to this one?
Andre，你来回答好吗？
Andre, do you want to talk to this one? >> Yes. Yes. So, basically for romcom
Andre，你来回答好吗？好的。关于 ROCm，
>> Yes. Yes. So, basically for romcom
好的。关于 ROCm，
>> Yes. Yes. So, basically for romcom specifically, uh we removed the rocom
好的。具体来说，我们移除了 ROCm……
specifically, uh we removed the rocom
具体来说，我们移除了 ROCm……
specifically, uh we removed the rocom 7.1 support. Uh no wheels are no longer
具体来说，我们移除了对 ROCm 7.1 的支持，不再提供相应的安装包。
7.1 support. Uh no wheels are no longer
不再支持 ROCm 7.1，也不再提供相应的安装包。
7.1 support. Uh no wheels are no longer shipped with 214 PyTorch. So, um uh if
PyTorch 2.14 不再提供相应的安装包。所以，如果……
shipped with 214 PyTorch. So, um uh if
shipped with 214 PyTorch. So, um uh if you're on roam 7.1, I think you need to
PyTorch 2.14 不再提供相应的安装包。如果你用的是 ROCm 7.1，我想你需要……
you're on roam 7.1, I think you need to
如果你用的是 ROCm 7.1，我想你需要……
you're on roam 7.1, I think you need to migrate to either Rocomm 7.2 or 714. Uh
如果你用的是 ROCm 7.1，需要迁移到 ROCm 7.2 或 714。
migrate to either Rocomm 7.2 or 714. Uh
迁移到 ROCm 7.2 或 714。
migrate to either Rocomm 7.2 or 714. Uh those are two versions that are
迁移到 ROCm 7.2 或 714。这两个版本……
those are two versions that are
这两个版本……
those are two versions that are supported currently by 214 PyTorch. Um
这两个版本目前都受 PyTorch 2.14 支持。
supported currently by 214 PyTorch. Um
目前都受 PyTorch 2.14 支持。
supported currently by 214 PyTorch. Um 714 is the latest one and it is using uh
目前都受 PyTorch 2.14 支持。714 是最新版本，它使用……
714 is the latest one and it is using uh
714 是最新版本，它使用……
714 is the latest one and it is using uh the rock pdk 7.2 it's the same version
714 是最新版本，使用 ROCm PDK 7.2；它与……版本相同。
the rock pdk 7.2 it's the same version
ROCm PDK 7.2，与……版本相同。
the rock pdk 7.2 it's the same version that we also shipped with previous
ROCm PDK 7.2，与我们上一版……所用的版本相同。
that we also shipped with previous
与我们上一版……所用的版本相同。
that we also shipped with previous release of torch. So it's uh more
与上一版 PyTorch 所用的版本相同，所以它更……
release of torch. So it's uh more
release of torch. So it's uh more similar to what rocom 7.1 was. So I
与上一版 PyTorch 所用的版本相同，所以更接近 ROCm 7.1。
similar to what rocom 7.1 was. So I
更接近 ROCm 7.1。所以我……
similar to what rocom 7.1 was. So I think you so you have a choice
更接近 ROCm 7.1。所以我觉得你可以选择。
think you so you have a choice
我觉得你可以选择。
think you so you have a choice basically. I think the best way is to
总之，你可以选择。我觉得最好……
basically. I think the best way is to
总之，我觉得最好……
basically. I think the best way is to migrate straight to 714. Um but yeah, I
总之，我觉得最好直接迁移到 714。不过……
migrate straight to 714. Um but yeah, I
直接迁移到 714。不过……
migrate straight to 714. Um but yeah, I think that's about it. Yes.
直接迁移到 714。嗯，我想就这些。
think that's about it. Yes.
我想就这些。对。
think that's about it. Yes. [snorts]
我想就这些。对。［轻哼］
>> Okay.
好的。
>> Okay. >> And there are some advanced features
好的。另外还有一些高级功能……
>> And there are some advanced features
另外还有一些高级功能……
>> And there are some advanced features which are available in 714 like he file
另外，714 还提供一些高级功能，比如 HIP 文件……
which are available in 714 like he file
714 提供的功能，比如 HIP 文件……
which are available in 714 like he file which is similar to coup file like
714 提供的功能，比如 HIP 文件，类似于 CUDA 文件……
which is similar to coup file like
这类似于 cuFile，比如
which is similar to coup file like direct storage access from GPUs and you
这类似于 cuFile，比如 GPU 直接访问存储，你还
direct storage access from GPUs and you
GPU 直接访问存储，你还
direct storage access from GPUs and you can use more hip solver functions for
GPU 直接访问存储，你还可以使用更多 hipSOLVER 函数，比如
can use more hip solver functions for
可以使用更多 hipSOLVER 函数，比如
can use more hip solver functions for example torch and alf uses that one.
可以使用更多 hipSOLVER 函数，比如 Torch 和 ALF 就用到了它。
example torch and alf uses that one.
比如 Torch 和 ALF 就用到了它。
example torch and alf uses that one. >> Yes. And the packaging is actually a lot
比如 Torch 和 ALF 就用到了它。>> 对，而且打包方式也改进了很多
>> Yes. And the packaging is actually a lot
>> 对，而且打包方式也改进了很多
>> Yes. And the packaging is actually a lot better and a lot more modern for 714.
>> 对，714 的打包方式改进了很多，也更现代化了。
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
>> Okay. Um I think our next question is going to
>> 好的。我想下一个问题会
Um I think our next question is going to
我想下一个问题会
Um I think our next question is going to be kind of a little bit of a broader
我想下一个问题会稍微宽泛一些
be kind of a little bit of a broader
稍微宽泛一些
be kind of a little bit of a broader question. Um uh so it seems like the
是个稍微宽泛一些的问题。看起来
question. Um uh so it seems like the
是个问题。看起来
question. Um uh so it seems like the diversity in the Okay, here we are. Uh
是个问题。看起来多样性……好，找到了。
diversity in the Okay, here we are. Uh
多样性……好，找到了。
diversity in the Okay, here we are. Uh it seems like the diversity in hardware
多样性……好，找到了。最近硬件种类似乎
it seems like the diversity in hardware
最近硬件种类似乎
it seems like the diversity in hardware in the AI world is exploding lately. At
最近 AI 领域的硬件种类似乎在迅速增加。至少
in the AI world is exploding lately. At
AI 领域的硬件种类似乎在迅速增加。至少
in the AI world is exploding lately. At least that's what I see on on on uh uh
AI 领域的硬件种类似乎在迅速增加。至少我看到的是这样，
least that's what I see on on on uh uh
至少我看到的是这样，
least that's what I see on on on uh uh in my news passing by. uh my uh screen
至少我每天刷到的新闻给我这种感觉，屏幕上
in my news passing by. uh my uh screen
我刷到的新闻，屏幕上
in my news passing by. uh my uh screen every day. Uh how do we think about
每天都能看到。我们该如何看待
every day. Uh how do we think about
every day. Uh how do we think about platform support um within the PyTorch
每天都能看到。我们该如何看待 PyTorch 社区的
platform support um within the PyTorch
PyTorch 社区的平台支持
platform support um within the PyTorch community? I'd love to hear from from
PyTorch 社区的平台支持？我想先听听
community? I'd love to hear from from
社区的平台支持？我想先听听
community? I'd love to hear from from Joe on this and then I'm sure Andrea and
社区的平台支持？我想先听听 Joe 的看法，然后 Andrea 和
Joe on this and then I'm sure Andrea and
Joe 的看法，然后 Andrea 和
Joe on this and then I'm sure Andrea and Nikita may also want to chime in with
Joe 的看法，然后 Andrea 和 Nikita 可能也想补充
Nikita may also want to chime in with
Nikita 可能也想补充
Nikita may also want to chime in with details.
Nikita 可能也想补充一些细节。
details.
一些细节。
details. >> Yeah,
一些细节。>> 对，
>> Yeah,
>> 对，
>> Yeah, >> I mean we know we've been I'm coming at
>> 对，>> 我是说，我们知道我们一直……我从
>> I mean we know we've been I'm coming at
>> 我是说，我们知道我们一直……我从
>> I mean we know we've been I'm coming at Harbor 180 for a long time with PyTorch.
>> 我是说，我们知道我们一直……我从 Harbor 180 的角度关注 PyTorch 已经很久了。
Harbor 180 for a long time with PyTorch.
从 Harbor 180 的角度关注 PyTorch 已经很久了。
Harbor 180 for a long time with PyTorch. I think we've been trying uh to support
从 Harbor 180 的角度关注 PyTorch 已经很久了。我想我们一直在努力支持
I think we've been trying uh to support
我想我们一直在努力支持
I think we've been trying uh to support a lot of different backends. We there's
我想我们一直在努力支持许多不同的后端。基金会里还有
a lot of different backends. We there's
许多不同的后端。基金会里还有
a lot of different backends. We there's working groups in the in the foundation.
许多不同的后端。基金会里还有相关工作组。
working groups in the in the foundation.
基金会里的工作组。
working groups in the in the foundation. I think you know in some ways like you
基金会里的工作组。我觉得，从某些方面来说，你……
I think you know in some ways like you
我觉得，从某些方面来说，你……
I think you know in some ways like you know there's a couple different angles.
我觉得这件事可以从几个不同角度来看。
know there's a couple different angles.
这件事可以从几个不同角度来看。
know there's a couple different angles. One obviously we wanted to have a
这件事可以从几个不同角度来看。首先，我们显然希望有……
One obviously we wanted to have a
首先，我们显然希望有……
One obviously we wanted to have a diverse set of of hardware vendors and
多元的硬件厂商，以及……
diverse set of of hardware vendors and
diverse set of of hardware vendors and and a hardware ecosystem to give choice
多元的硬件厂商和硬件生态，让开发者有更多选择。
and a hardware ecosystem to give choice
还有一个硬件生态，让开发者有更多选择。
and a hardware ecosystem to give choice to developers because not just at the
还有一个硬件生态，让开发者有更多选择，因为这不只是云端的事。
to developers because not just at the
让开发者有更多选择，因为这不只是云端的事。
to developers because not just at the cloud. I think everyone sort of thinks
让开发者有更多选择，因为这不只是云端的事。我觉得大家往往认为……
cloud. I think everyone sort of thinks
云端。我觉得大家往往认为……
cloud. I think everyone sort of thinks of like the cloud side is like the
云端。我觉得大家往往认为，云端才是……
of like the cloud side is like the
云端才是……
of like the cloud side is like the default but like running on device
云端才是默认选择，但模型也可以在设备上运行。
default but like running on device
默认选择，但模型也可以在设备上运行。
default but like running on device running you know um within wearables
默认选择，但模型也可以在设备上、在可穿戴设备中运行。
running you know um within wearables
也可以在可穿戴设备中运行。
running you know um within wearables like there's there's like a lot going on
也可以在可穿戴设备中运行。这里面有很多变化。
like there's there's like a lot going on
这里面有很多变化。
like there's there's like a lot going on in different hardware architectures and
不同的硬件架构都有很多发展。
in different hardware architectures and
不同的硬件架构，以及……
in different hardware architectures and that's why this like compiler and kernel
不同的硬件架构，这也让编译器和内核……
that's why this like compiler and kernel
这也让编译器和内核……
that's why this like compiler and kernel ecosystems is so diverse. I think that's
这也让编译器和内核生态如此多样。我觉得……
ecosystems is so diverse. I think that's
生态如此多样。我觉得……
ecosystems is so diverse. I think that's like one piece. I think pragmatically
生态如此多样。我觉得这是一个原因。实际来看……
like one piece. I think pragmatically
这是一个原因。实际来看……
like one piece. I think pragmatically though like like compute is scarce these
这是一个原因。不过现实是，如今算力紧缺。
though like like compute is scarce these
不过现实是，如今算力紧缺。
though like like compute is scarce these days and you know being able to run on
不过现实是，如今算力紧缺，能够在不同平台上运行……
days and you know being able to run on
如今算力紧缺，能够在不同平台上运行……
days and you know being able to run on Nvidia, being able to run on AMD, being
如今算力紧缺，能用 Nvidia，也能用 AMD，还能……
Nvidia, being able to run on AMD, being
能用 Nvidia，也能用 AMD，还能……
Nvidia, being able to run on AMD, being able to run on TPUs. I think it's
能用 Nvidia，也能用 AMD，还能用 TPU。我觉得……
able to run on TPUs. I think it's
还能用 TPU。我觉得……
able to run on TPUs. I think it's actually um you know things have like
还能用 TPU。我觉得，其实情况是……
actually um you know things have like
其实情况是……
actually um you know things have like you know big labs or folks that that
其实，大型实验室或者其他……
you know big labs or folks that that
大型实验室或者其他……
you know big labs or folks that that need a lot of compute have have had to
大型实验室，或者需要大量算力的人，都不得不……
need a lot of compute have have had to
需要大量算力的人，都不得不……
need a lot of compute have have had to learn how to run on on you know a lot of
需要大量算力的人，都不得不学会在多种平台上运行。
learn how to run on on you know a lot of
学会在多种平台上运行。
learn how to run on on you know a lot of different architectures. I think like if
学会在多种不同架构上运行。我觉得，如果……
different architectures. I think like if
不同的架构。我觉得，如果……
different architectures. I think like if I look at anthropic they run on Nvidia,
不同的架构。比如 Anthropic，他们会用 Nvidia，
I look at anthropic they run on Nvidia,
我看 Anthropic，他们用 NVIDIA。
I look at anthropic they run on Nvidia, they run on Tranium, they run on TPUs.
我看 Anthropic，他们用 NVIDIA，也用 Trainium 和 TPU。
they run on Tranium, they run on TPUs.
他们用 Trainium，也用 TPU。
they run on Tranium, they run on TPUs. Um even in like different workflows like
他们用 Trainium，也用 TPU。嗯，甚至在不同的工作流程里，比如……
Um even in like different workflows like
嗯，甚至在不同的工作流程里，比如……
Um even in like different workflows like I know we're talking a lot about
嗯，甚至在不同的工作流程里，比如……我知道我们一直在谈……
I know we're talking a lot about
我知道我们一直在谈……
I know we're talking a lot about training typically but you know training
我知道我们通常主要在谈训练，但你看，训练……
training typically but you know training
通常主要在谈训练，但你看，训练……
training typically but you know training RL like we're talking about running on
通常主要在谈训练，但做强化学习时，我们说的是运行在……
RL like we're talking about running on
比如强化学习，我们说的是运行在……
RL like we're talking about running on GPUs. We run environments in CPUs. So
比如强化学习，模型跑在 GPU 上，环境跑在 CPU 上。所以……
GPUs. We run environments in CPUs. So
模型跑在 GPU 上，环境跑在 CPU 上。所以……
GPUs. We run environments in CPUs. So all of a sudden you see the Intel stock
模型跑在 GPU 上，环境跑在 CPU 上。所以最近你突然看到英特尔股价……
all of a sudden you see the Intel stock
你突然看到英特尔股价……
all of a sudden you see the Intel stock up these days because they're selling a
你突然看到英特尔股价最近上涨，因为他们卖出了……
up these days because they're selling a
最近上涨，因为他们卖出了……
up these days because they're selling a lot more CPUs for RL which is good. Um
最近上涨，因为他们为强化学习卖出了更多 CPU，这是好事。嗯……
lot more CPUs for RL which is good. Um
为强化学习卖出了更多 CPU，这是好事。嗯……
lot more CPUs for RL which is good. Um you know when you you run reinforcement
为强化学习卖出了更多 CPU，这是好事。嗯，你知道，运行强化……
you know when you you run reinforcement
你知道，运行强化……
you know when you you run reinforcement learning you're running a lot of
你知道，运行强化学习时，会进行大量……
learning you're running a lot of
学习时，会进行大量……
learning you're running a lot of inference. um at inference time you're
学习时，会进行大量推理。嗯，在推理阶段，你会……
inference. um at inference time you're
推理。嗯，在推理阶段，你会……
inference. um at inference time you're running a ton of inference obviously
推理。嗯，在推理阶段，你显然要进行海量推理。
running a ton of inference obviously
显然要进行海量推理。
running a ton of inference obviously like you're doing a lot of compute time
显然要进行海量推理，也就是要投入大量计算资源……
like you're doing a lot of compute time
也就是要投入大量计算资源……
like you're doing a lot of compute time inference time compute um scaling that
比如推理阶段的计算资源，要在……
inference time compute um scaling that
推理阶段的计算资源，要在……
inference time compute um scaling that up in different axes um and so I think
推理阶段的计算资源，要从不同维度扩大规模。所以我觉得……
up in different axes um and so I think
从不同维度扩大规模。所以我觉得……
up in different axes um and so I think like you know you might run that on on
从不同维度扩大规模。所以我觉得，你可能会把它跑在……
like you know you might run that on on
你可能会把它跑在……
like you know you might run that on on different architecture you might run AMD
你可能会把它跑在不同的架构上，比如 AMD……
different architecture you might run AMD
不同的架构，比如 AMD……
different architecture you might run AMD you might run on on on different things
不同的架构，比如 AMD，也可能跑在其他硬件上……
you might run on on on different things
也可能跑在其他硬件上……
you might run on on on different things so I think the hardware diversity is
也可能跑在其他硬件上。所以我认为，硬件多样性……
so I think the hardware diversity is
所以我认为，硬件多样性……
so I think the hardware diversity is like is great for developers and I think
所以我认为，硬件多样性对开发者很有利，而且我觉得……
like is great for developers and I think
对开发者很有利，而且我觉得……
like is great for developers and I think that even going back like a year or
对开发者很有利，而且我觉得，即使回到大约一年前……
that even going back like a year or
即使回到大约一年前……
that even going back like a year or longer we've been talking about this and
即使回到一年前甚至更早，我们就在谈这个……
longer we've been talking about this and
甚至更早，我们就在谈这个……
longer we've been talking about this and um for PyTorch even back in we've been
甚至更早，我们就在谈这个。嗯，PyTorch 方面，我们早在……
um for PyTorch even back in we've been
嗯，PyTorch 方面，我们早在……
um for PyTorch even back in we've been working with AMD since what 2018 um I'm
嗯，PyTorch 方面，我们从 2018 年左右就开始和 AMD 合作了，我……
working with AMD since what 2018 um I'm
大概从2018年起就和AMD合作，嗯，我……
working with AMD since what 2018 um I'm so you remember those days right So, I I
大概从2018年起就和AMD合作。嗯，你还记得那时候吧？所以我……
so you remember those days right So, I I
你还记得那时候吧？所以我……
so you remember those days right So, I I think it's it's I I wouldn't even say
你还记得那时候吧？所以我觉得，甚至不能说……
think it's it's I I wouldn't even say
我觉得，甚至不能说……
think it's it's I I wouldn't even say it's exploding lately. I actually think
我甚至不能说它是最近才爆发的。其实我觉得……
it's exploding lately. I actually think
它是最近才爆发的。其实我觉得……
it's exploding lately. I actually think it's been exploding for a long time and
它早就蓬勃发展了，而且……
it's been exploding for a long time and
it's been exploding for a long time and I think um we just continue to grow and
它早就蓬勃发展了，而且我觉得我们还在持续增长……
I think um we just continue to grow and
我觉得我们还在持续增长，而且……
I think um we just continue to grow and obviously Nvidia gets a lot of the
我觉得我们还在持续增长。当然，Nvidia吸引了很多……
obviously Nvidia gets a lot of the
当然，Nvidia吸引了很多……
obviously Nvidia gets a lot of the headlines as they as they well deserve.
当然，Nvidia占据了很多头条，这也是实至名归。
headlines as they as they well deserve.
占据头条也是他们实至名归。
headlines as they as they well deserve. Um but there's definitely a lot of
占据头条也是他们实至名归。不过，确实还有很多……
Um but there's definitely a lot of
不过，确实还有很多……
Um but there's definitely a lot of architectures out there that are are
不过，确实还需要很多其他架构……
architectures out there that are are
还有很多其他架构……
architectures out there that are are needed and um and it's just going to
这些架构都有其用武之地，而且还会……
needed and um and it's just going to
needed and um and it's just going to continue to kind of grow in different
这些架构都有其用武之地，而且会继续向不同方向发展。
continue to kind of grow in different
继续向不同方向发展。
continue to kind of grow in different directions. Um, and I think we're going
继续向不同方向发展。我想我们会……
directions. Um, and I think we're going
向不同方向发展。我想我们会……
directions. Um, and I think we're going to get inference is obviously much more
向不同方向发展。我想，推理显然越来越……
to get inference is obviously much more
推理显然越来越……
to get inference is obviously much more important these days for many. Um, and
如今对很多人来说，推理显然重要得多。而且……
important these days for many. Um, and
如今对很多人来说，这重要得多。而且……
important these days for many. Um, and it has to be much more efficient to be
如今对很多人来说，这重要得多，而且它必须更高效，才能……
it has to be much more efficient to be
它必须更高效，才能……
it has to be much more efficient to be able to scale and that's just going to
它必须更高效，才能实现规模化，而这又会……
able to scale and that's just going to
实现规模化，而这又会……
able to scale and that's just going to necessitate different types of
实现规模化，而这又需要不同类型的……
necessitate different types of
需要不同类型的……
necessitate different types of architectures. Disagregated inference
需要不同类型的架构。比如分离式推理……
architectures. Disagregated inference
架构。比如分离式推理……
architectures. Disagregated inference for example where you separate pre-fill
比如分离式推理，就是把预填充……
for example where you separate pre-fill
比如把预填充……
for example where you separate pre-fill and decode um is a major trend right now
比如把预填充和解码分开，这是目前的一大趋势。
and decode um is a major trend right now
把解码分开，是目前的一大趋势。
and decode um is a major trend right now and has been for the last several
把解码分开，是目前的一大趋势，而且过去几个月一直如此。
and has been for the last several
过去几个月一直如此。
and has been for the last several months. Um, so I think that's it's going
过去几个月一直如此。所以我觉得，这方面还会……
months. Um, so I think that's it's going
所以我觉得，这方面还会……
months. Um, so I think that's it's going to continue to innovate obviously where
所以我觉得，显然还会继续创新……
to continue to innovate obviously where
显然还会继续创新……
to continue to innovate obviously where the workloads are going to be. So would
显然会随着工作负载的发展继续创新。所以我也想……
the workloads are going to be. So would
随着工作负载的发展继续创新。所以我也想……
the workloads are going to be. So would love others to to chime in though.
不过，我也很想听听其他人的看法。
love others to to chime in though.
不过也想听听其他人的看法。
love others to to chime in though. >> Yeah. Um, Nikita and Andre, do you want
不过也想听听其他人的看法。对，Nikita 和 Andre，你们想……
>> Yeah. Um, Nikita and Andre, do you want
对，Nikita 和 Andre，你们想……
>> Yeah. Um, Nikita and Andre, do you want to say anything about distributed or
对，Nikita 和 Andre，你们想谈谈分布式，或者……
to say anything about distributed or
谈谈分布式，或者……
to say anything about distributed or sorry about uh heterogeneous hardware?
谈谈分布式，抱歉，是异构硬件？
sorry about uh heterogeneous hardware?
抱歉，是异构硬件？
sorry about uh heterogeneous hardware? >> Uh, sure. Um, yes. Uh, basically on
抱歉，是异构硬件？可以。基本上……
>> Uh, sure. Um, yes. Uh, basically on
可以。基本上……
>> Uh, sure. Um, yes. Uh, basically on PyTorch, PyTorch specifically, we've
可以。具体到 PyTorch，我们……
PyTorch, PyTorch specifically, we've
具体到 PyTorch，我们……
PyTorch, PyTorch specifically, we've been working on the project called CRCR,
具体到 PyTorch，我们一直在做一个叫 CRCR 的项目。
been working on the project called CRCR,
一直在做一个叫 CRCR 的项目。
been working on the project called CRCR, it's a cross repository CI relay. So, it
一直在做一个叫 CRCR 的项目，它是一个跨仓库 CI 中继。
it's a cross repository CI relay. So, it
它是一个跨仓库 CI 中继，可以让……
it's a cross repository CI relay. So, it lets partner back ends to run their own
它是一个跨仓库 CI 中继，可以让合作伙伴的后端自行运行……
lets partner back ends to run their own
让合作伙伴的后端自行运行……
lets partner back ends to run their own CI against PyTorch changes. So on the
让合作伙伴的后端针对 PyTorch 的改动运行自己的 CI。
CI against PyTorch changes. So on the
针对 PyTorch 的改动运行 CI，然后……
CI against PyTorch changes. So on the PyTorch PRS and report result back to us
针对 PyTorch 的 PR 运行 CI，并把结果反馈给我们。
PyTorch PRS and report result back to us
针对 PyTorch 的 PR，并把结果反馈给我们。
PyTorch PRS and report result back to us um on the PyTorch HUD page. Uh so we
针对 PyTorch 的 PR，并把结果反馈到 PyTorch HUD 页面。
um on the PyTorch HUD page. Uh so we
在 PyTorch HUD 页面上。所以我们……
um on the PyTorch HUD page. Uh so we developed this with the partners um in
在 PyTorch HUD 页面上。过去几个月，我们与合作伙伴……
developed this with the partners um in
过去几个月，我们与合作伙伴……
developed this with the partners um in the past few months and basically it's
过去几个月，我们与合作伙伴一起开发了它，基本上……
the past few months and basically it's
过去几个月开发了它，基本上……
the past few months and basically it's pretty much released right now for this
过去几个月开发了它，现在基本已经发布，用于这次……
pretty much released right now for this
现在基本已经发布，用于这次……
pretty much released right now for this um 2015 um 2014 release and this is a
现在基本已经发布，用于这次 2015、2014 版本发布。
um 2015 um 2014 release and this is a
用于 2015、2014 版本发布。这也是……
um 2015 um 2014 release and this is a new feature in the Hut. So if you go to
用于 2015、2014 版本发布，也是 HUD 的一项新功能。如果你……
new feature in the Hut. So if you go to
这是 HUD 的一项新功能。如果你……
new feature in the Hut. So if you go to our hot page, there's the CRCR
这是 HUD 的一项新功能。如果你打开我们的 HUD 页面，会看到 CRCR……
our hot page, there's the CRCR
打开我们的 HUD 页面，会看到 CRCR……
our hot page, there's the CRCR button. You can go and access this to
打开我们的 HUD 页面，会看到 CRCR 按钮。你可以点击它……
button. You can go and access this to
点击这个按钮，你就可以……
button. You can go and access this to have a like a preview. Uh so basically
点击这个按钮，就可以预览一下。基本上……
have a like a preview. Uh so basically
可以预览一下。基本上……
have a like a preview. Uh so basically it's the way it's um configured. It's um
可以预览一下。它的配置方式是……
it's the way it's um configured. It's um
它的配置方式是……
it's the way it's um configured. It's um the four levels of access. So level one
它的配置方式分为四个接入级别。第一级……
the four levels of access. So level one
分为四个接入级别。第一级……
the four levels of access. So level one is on boarding. So events are forwarded
分为四个接入级别。第一级是接入阶段，事件会转发……
is on boarding. So events are forwarded
第一级是接入阶段，事件会转发……
is on boarding. So events are forwarded to downstream uh repositories and um
第一级是接入阶段，事件会转发到下游仓库。
to downstream uh repositories and um
转发到下游仓库，而……
to downstream uh repositories and um upstream receive no feedback. So PyTorch
转发到下游仓库，上游不会收到反馈。所以 PyTorch……
upstream receive no feedback. So PyTorch
上游不会收到反馈。所以 PyTorch……
upstream receive no feedback. So PyTorch we don't know what our
上游不会收到反馈。所以在 PyTorch 这边，我们不知道我们的……
we don't know what our
我们不知道我们的……
we don't know what our tests are running on the downstream
我们不知道我们的测试在下游仓库中的运行情况。
tests are running on the downstream
测试正在下游仓库运行。
tests are running on the downstream repos but tests are happening. So L2 is
测试正在下游仓库运行，但我们知道测试确实在进行。所以 L2 是……
repos but tests are happening. So L2 is
仓库，但测试确实在进行。所以 L2 是……
repos but tests are happening. So L2 is observation. It's when we actually uh
仓库，但测试确实在进行。所以 L2 是观察阶段，也就是我们真正……
observation. It's when we actually uh
观察阶段，也就是我们真正……
observation. It's when we actually uh PyTorch receives the results
观察阶段，也就是 PyTorch 真正收到结果的时候。
PyTorch receives the results
PyTorch 收到结果。
PyTorch receives the results uh of the downstream um tests and able
PyTorch 收到下游测试的结果，并且能够……
uh of the downstream um tests and able
下游测试的结果，并且能够……
uh of the downstream um tests and able to visualize and see what are the
下游测试的结果，并且能够直观看到有哪些……
to visualize and see what are the
直观看到有哪些……
to visualize and see what are the failures and this helps like um uh
直观看到有哪些失败，这有助于……
failures and this helps like um uh
失败，这有助于……
failures and this helps like um uh observation uh and uh um L3 it's stable
失败，这有助于观察。L3 是稳定阶段。
observation uh and uh um L3 it's stable
观察，而 L3 是稳定阶段。
observation uh and uh um L3 it's stable um it's where we are currently at um
观察，而 L3 是稳定阶段。我们目前就处于这个阶段。
um it's where we are currently at um
我们目前就处于这个阶段。
um it's where we are currently at um it's non-blocking run check on PR so
我们目前就处于这个阶段。PR 上的检查不会阻断流程，所以……
it's non-blocking run check on PR so
PR 上的检查不会阻断流程，所以……
it's non-blocking run check on PR so it's basically you apply um flow out of
PR 上的检查不会阻断流程，所以基本上就是将……
it's basically you apply um flow out of
基本上就是将……
it's basically you apply um flow out of tree lab out CR flow CRCR label to the
基本上就是把 flow out of tree lab out CR flow CRCR 标签加到……
tree lab out CR flow CRCR label to the
把 tree lab out CR flow CRCR 标签加到……
tree lab out CR flow CRCR label to the PR and the results from the uh
给 PR 加上 tree lab out CR flow CRCR 标签，以及来自……的结果
PR and the results from the uh
PR 和来自……的结果
PR and the results from the uh downstream repositories appear on your
PR 和下游仓库的结果会显示在你的……
downstream repositories appear on your
下游仓库会显示在你的……
downstream repositories appear on your PyTorch PR and um
下游仓库会显示在你的 PyTorch PR 上，嗯
PyTorch PR and um
PyTorch PR 上，嗯
PyTorch PR and um currently we're working with Nindia
PyTorch PR 上；目前我们正与 Nindia 合作
currently we're working with Nindia
目前我们正与 Nindia 合作
currently we're working with Nindia Windowsci Red Hat IBM Spire Ascent NPU
目前我们正与 Nindia、Windowsci、Red Hat、IBM、Spire 和 Ascent NPU 合作
Windowsci Red Hat IBM Spire Ascent NPU
包括 Windowsci、Red Hat、IBM、Spire 和 Ascent NPU
Windowsci Red Hat IBM Spire Ascent NPU Google TPU and VLM repos for that. So
包括 Windowsci、Red Hat、IBM、Spire、Ascent NPU、Google TPU 和 VLM 仓库。所以
Google TPU and VLM repos for that. So
还有 Google TPU 和 VLM 仓库。所以
Google TPU and VLM repos for that. So [clears throat] this will help with um
为此有 Google TPU 和 VLM 的代码仓库。所以，[清嗓]这将有助于……
[clears throat] this will help with um
[清嗓]这将有助于……
[clears throat] this will help with um onboarding different um vendors,
[清嗓]这将有助于接入不同的供应商，
onboarding different um vendors,
接入不同的供应商，
onboarding different um vendors, different architectures and different
接入不同的供应商、不同的架构，以及不同的
different architectures and different
不同的架构，以及不同的
different architectures and different repositories uh and uh maintainers of
不同的架构、不同的代码仓库，以及这些仓库的维护者
repositories uh and uh maintainers of
代码仓库，以及这些仓库的维护者
repositories uh and uh maintainers of those repositories should be able to
代码仓库，而这些仓库的维护者应该能够
those repositories should be able to
这些仓库的维护者应该能够
those repositories should be able to onboard very quickly and get results
这些仓库的维护者应该能够快速接入，并很快得到结果
onboard very quickly and get results
快速接入，并很快得到结果
onboard very quickly and get results testing for PyTorch pretty quickly and
快速接入，开展 PyTorch 测试并很快得到结果，而且
testing for PyTorch pretty quickly and
很快就能为 PyTorch 开展测试，并且……
testing for PyTorch pretty quickly and supported on PR testing and on nightly
很快就能为 PyTorch 开展测试，支持 PR 测试和夜间测试
supported on PR testing and on nightly
支持 PR 测试和夜间测试
supported on PR testing and on nightly testing. So there are kind of two modes
支持 PR 测试和夜间测试。所以有两种测试模式
testing. So there are kind of two modes
测试。所以有两种模式
testing. So there are kind of two modes for this and yeah I think this is a very
测试。所以这里有两种模式，我觉得这非常……
for this and yeah I think this is a very
对于这件事，我觉得这非常……
for this and yeah I think this is a very uh interesting uh part of the PyTorch
对于这件事，我觉得这是 PyTorch 项目中很有意思的……
uh interesting uh part of the PyTorch
PyTorch 项目中很有意思的一部分
uh interesting uh part of the PyTorch project that we're currently developing
PyTorch 项目中很有意思的一部分，我们正在开发
project that we're currently developing
我们正在开发的项目
project that we're currently developing and going to develop for
我们正在开发的项目，今后也会继续开发
and going to develop for
今后也会继续开发
and going to develop for um
今后也会继续开发，嗯……
um
嗯……
um I don't know maybe Nikita
嗯，我不确定，也许 Nikita……
I don't know maybe Nikita
我不确定，也许 Nikita……
I don't know maybe Nikita >> yeah and maybe uh like one more yeah one
我不确定，也许 Nikita……对，也许还有一点
>> yeah and maybe uh like one more yeah one
对，也许还有一点
>> yeah and maybe uh like one more yeah one more thing that like on the API side
对，还有一点是关于 API 的
more thing that like on the API side
还有一点是关于 API 的
more thing that like on the API side there's a torch accelerate API which
API 方面有个 torch accelerate API，它……
there's a torch accelerate API which
有个 torch accelerate API，它……
there's a torch accelerate API which tries to abstract away different devices
有个 torch accelerate API，旨在屏蔽不同设备的差异
tries to abstract away different devices
旨在屏蔽不同设备的差异
tries to abstract away different devices different names different capabilities
旨在屏蔽不同设备在名称和能力上的差异
different names different capabilities
不同的名称和能力
different names different capabilities so you can write once for accelerated
不同的名称和能力，这样加速计算的代码只需写一次
so you can write once for accelerated
这样加速计算的代码只需写一次
so you can write once for accelerated compute and it should on not I don't
这样加速计算的代码只需写一次，应该就能在……
compute and it should on not I don't
计算代码应该能在……不，我……
compute and it should on not I don't know I don't want to repeat the Java
计算代码应该能在……算了，我不想照搬 Java 的那句口号
know I don't want to repeat the Java
我不想照搬 Java 的那句口号
know I don't want to repeat the Java everywhere but it will run on multiple
我不想照搬 Java 那句“到处运行”的口号，但它能在多种……
everywhere but it will run on multiple
到处运行，不过它能在多种……
everywhere but it will run on multiple compute and we try to like align all our
它能在多种计算设备上运行，我们也在努力统一所有……
compute and we try to like align all our
计算设备上运行，我们也在努力统一所有……
compute and we try to like align all our operator implementation this is why CRCR
我们也在努力统一所有算子的实现，所以才有 CRCR
operator implementation this is why CRCR
算子的实现，所以才有 CRCR
operator implementation this is why CRCR is there is that uh like vendors can
算子的实现。设立 CRCR 是为了让厂商……
is there is that uh like vendors can
是为了让厂商……
is there is that uh like vendors can make sure that like their hardware
是为了让厂商确保自己的硬件……
make sure that like their hardware
确保自己的硬件……
make sure that like their hardware report the same results as we expect it
确保自己的硬件给出符合预期的结果
report the same results as we expect it
给出符合预期的结果
report the same results as we expect it would and developers will have fewer
给出符合预期的结果，开发者也会少遇到……
would and developers will have fewer
开发者也会少遇到……
would and developers will have fewer surprises when they use this like
开发者使用这种机制时，也会少遇到意外
surprises when they use this like
使用这种机制时少遇到意外
surprises when they use this like abstraction to dispatch their job to
用这种抽象层分发任务时，也会少遇到意外
abstraction to dispatch their job to
用于将任务分派给……的抽象层
abstraction to dispatch their job to accelerator available but yes it is very
用于将任务分派给可用加速器的抽象层。不过没错，这非常……
accelerator available but yes it is very
有可用的加速器，不过没错，这非常……
accelerator available but yes it is very important because you need to be on more
有可用的加速器，不过没错，这很重要，因为你需要支持更多……
important because you need to be on more
这很重要，因为你需要支持更多……
important because you need to be on more platforms.
这很重要，因为你需要支持更多平台。
>> Yeah, I think I think I mean I I think
>> 对，我觉得，我的意思是……
>> Yeah, I think I think I mean I I think this whole area is really fascinating
>> 对，我觉得，PyTorch 的这一块工作真的很有意思。
this whole area is really fascinating
这一块工作真的很有意思。
this whole area is really fascinating within PyTorch because like uh like how
PyTorch 的这一块工作真的很有意思，因为，呃，该怎么说……
within PyTorch because like uh like how
在 PyTorch 中，因为，呃，该怎么……
within PyTorch because like uh like how do you how do you have like a consistent
在 PyTorch 中，你该如何提供一致的……
do you how do you have like a consistent
你该如何提供一致的……
do you how do you have like a consistent experience across the such different
你该如何在如此不同的……之间提供一致体验？
experience across the such different
在如此不同的……之间提供一致体验。
experience across the such different hardware and then how do we do QA? How
如何在各种不同硬件上提供一致体验？然后我们怎么做 QA？又该怎么……
hardware and then how do we do QA? How
面对各种硬件，我们怎么做 QA？又该怎么……
hardware and then how do we do QA? How do we deal with like new hardware
面对各种硬件，我们怎么做 QA？又该如何应对新硬件……
do we deal with like new hardware
我们该如何应对新硬件……
do we deal with like new hardware emerging which may or may not be in the
我们该如何应对不断出现的新硬件？它们可能……
emerging which may or may not be in the
不断出现的新硬件，可能……
emerging which may or may not be in the cloud for us to test? and how do we do
不断出现的新硬件，可能在云端供我们测试，也可能不在。我们又该怎么……
cloud for us to test? and how do we do
云端能否供我们测试？我们又该怎么……
cloud for us to test? and how do we do like the the the the
云端能否供我们测试？还有，那个……该怎么做？
like the the the the
比如，那个……
like the the the the um the the the continuous integration
比如，那个持续集成……
um the the the continuous integration
嗯，持续集成……
um the the the continuous integration testing in a distributed fashion. Um so
嗯，如何以分布式方式进行持续集成测试。所以……
testing in a distributed fashion. Um so
以分布式方式进行测试。所以……
testing in a distributed fashion. Um so so this is an area where like just a lot
以分布式方式进行测试。所以，这方面投入了大量……
so this is an area where like just a lot
所以，这方面投入了大量……
so this is an area where like just a lot of effort has gone and I think we've
所以，这方面投入了大量精力，我觉得我们已经……
of effort has gone and I think we've
投入了大量精力，我觉得我们已经……
of effort has gone and I think we've just gotten like this part of PyTorch
投入了大量精力，我觉得 PyTorch 的这部分……
just gotten like this part of PyTorch
PyTorch 的这部分现在……
just gotten like this part of PyTorch has gotten a lot more mature. So I
PyTorch 的这部分成熟了很多。所以我……
has gotten a lot more mature. So I
成熟了很多。所以我……
has gotten a lot more mature. So I imagine for hardware vendors it's way
成熟了很多。所以我想，对硬件厂商来说……
imagine for hardware vendors it's way
我想，对硬件厂商来说……
imagine for hardware vendors it's way easier to sort of contemplate getting
我想，对硬件厂商来说，如今考虑让平台获得支持容易多了。
easier to sort of contemplate getting
考虑让平台获得支持容易多了。
easier to sort of contemplate getting their their platform properly supported
如今要让他们的平台得到妥善支持，容易多了。
their their platform properly supported
让他们的平台得到妥善支持。
their their platform properly supported in PyTorch now than it was you know two
如今要让他们的平台在 PyTorch 中得到妥善支持，比……
in PyTorch now than it was you know two
如今在 PyTorch 中实现支持，比两……
in PyTorch now than it was you know two years ago three years ago. So okay I
如今在 PyTorch 中实现支持，比两三年前容易多了。好，我……
years ago three years ago. So okay I
两三年前。好，我……
years ago three years ago. So okay I think
两三年前。好，我觉得……
think
我觉得……
think >> want to add sorry last last point to
我觉得……>> 抱歉，我想再补充最后一点……
>> want to add sorry last last point to
>> 抱歉，我想再补充最后一点……
>> want to add sorry last last point to this and it's the way it's developed
欠，我想再补充最后一点：这与它的开发方式有关。
this and it's the way it's developed
这与它的开发方式有关。
this and it's the way it's developed right now it's a lot more secure than it
按现在的开发方式，它比以前安全得多。
right now it's a lot more secure than it
现在它比以前安全得多。
right now it's a lot more secure than it used to be. So there's no um sharing of
现在它比以前安全得多，所以不用共享……
used to be. So there's no um sharing of
以前没这么安全。所以现在不用共享……
used to be. So there's no um sharing of the keys nothing like that. So on
不用共享密钥，也不需要类似操作。所以在……
the keys nothing like that. So on
密钥之类的都不用共享。所以在……
the keys nothing like that. So on boarding and from infrastructure point
密钥之类的都不用共享。从接入和基础设施角度看……
boarding and from infrastructure point
从接入和基础设施角度看……
boarding and from infrastructure point of view it's very fast and secure and uh
从接入和基础设施角度看，整个过程快速、安全，而且……
of view it's very fast and secure and uh
从这个角度看，整个过程快速、安全，而且……
of view it's very fast and secure and uh uh very straightforward. We set up
整个过程快速、安全，也很简单。我们设置了……
uh very straightforward. We set up
也很简单。我们设置了……
uh very straightforward. We set up specific repository CRC test when
我们设置了针对特定仓库的 CRC 测试，届时……
specific repository CRC test when
针对特定仓库的 CRC 测试，届时……
specific repository CRC test when [clears throat] you can go and look at
针对特定仓库的 CRC 测试。你可以去看看……
[clears throat] you can go and look at
[清嗓] 你可以去看看……
[clears throat] you can go and look at the on boarding guide and can start on
[清嗓] 你可以查看接入指南，然后开始……
the on boarding guide and can start on
查看接入指南，然后就可以开始……
the on boarding guide and can start on boarding.
查看接入指南，然后就可以开始接入。
boarding.
接入。
boarding. >> Yeah. Awesome. Okay. I think we have a
接入。>> 对，太好了。好，我想我们还有……
>> Yeah. Awesome. Okay. I think we have a
>> 对，太好了。好，我想我们还有……
>> Yeah. Awesome. Okay. I think we have a next question lined up.
>> 对，太好了。好，下一个问题已经准备好了。
next question lined up.
下一个问题已经准备好了。
next question lined up. Okay. And this again thank you
下一个问题已经准备好了。好，也再次感谢……
Okay. And this again thank you
好，也再次感谢……
Okay. And this again thank you Shivashish uh for asking uh three
好，也再次感谢 Shivashish 提出了三个……
Shivashish uh for asking uh three
Shivashish 提出了三个……
Shivashish uh for asking uh three interesting and challenging questions uh
Shivashish 提出了三个有趣又有挑战性的问题……
interesting and challenging questions uh
有趣又有挑战性的问题……
interesting and challenging questions uh uh for us to answer here. Uh so for
这些问题很有趣，也很有挑战性，我们来回答一下。那么……
uh for us to answer here. Uh so for
我们来回答一下。那么，对于……
uh for us to answer here. Uh so for draft then verify loops uh which would
那么，对于先生成再验证的循环，它可能……
draft then verify loops uh which would
先生成再验证的循环，可能……
draft then verify loops uh which would be sort of speculative decoding style
先生成再验证的循环，有点像推测解码……
be sort of speculative decoding style
有点像推测解码……
be sort of speculative decoding style style is could a graph capture um in the
有点像推测解码。那么，图捕获能否……
style is could a graph capture um in the
那么，图捕获能否……
style is could a graph capture um in the uh torch while loop u uh mode usable on
图捕获能否在 torch while loop 模式下用于……
uh torch while loop u uh mode usable on
torch while loop 模式能否用于……
uh torch while loop u uh mode usable on the verify step in 214 or does that
torch while loop 模式能否用于 214 中的验证步骤，还是……
the verify step in 214 or does that
214 中的验证步骤，还是……
the verify step in 214 or does that control uh flow still force a graph
214 中的验证步骤，还是这种控制流仍会导致计算图……
control uh flow still force a graph
这种控制流仍会导致计算图……
control uh flow still force a graph break um do we do we know the answer to
这种控制流仍会导致计算图中断吗？我们知道……
break um do we do we know the answer to
计算图中断吗？我们知道……
break um do we do we know the answer to that among the
计算图中断吗？我们当中有人知道答案吗？
that among the
其中……
that among the >> I think generically you cannot answer
其中……我觉得笼统地说，没法回答。
>> I think generically you cannot answer
我觉得笼统地说，没法回答。
>> I think generically you cannot answer this question because it depends on the
我觉得笼统地说，没法回答这个问题，因为这取决于……
this question because it depends on the
这个问题，因为这取决于……
this question because it depends on the workflow it should be usable and that's
这个问题，因为这取决于工作流程；它应该能用，而这正是……
workflow it should be usable and that's
工作流程；它应该能用，而这正是……
workflow it should be usable and that's uh what the new um like abstractions
工作流程；它应该能用，而这正是新的抽象机制……
uh what the new um like abstractions
新的抽象机制……
uh what the new um like abstractions that we talked about in the highlights
我们在亮点部分提到的新抽象机制……
that we talked about in the highlights
我们在亮点部分提到的……
that we talked about in the highlights are for but there could be some cases
我们在亮点部分提到的就是为此设计的，但也可能有些情况……
are for but there could be some cases
就是为此设计的，但也可能有些情况……
are for but there could be some cases when it's not but we you already have uh
就是为此设计的，但也可能有些情况无法使用。不过你已经有……
when it's not but we you already have uh
有些情况无法使用。不过你已经有……
when it's not but we you already have uh toggles to test that you can just wrap
有些情况无法使用。不过你已经有开关可以测试，只需用它包住……
toggles to test that you can just wrap
有开关可以测试，只需用它包住……
toggles to test that you can just wrap your code with like aborton graph break
有开关可以测试，只需用类似 abort on graph break 的功能包住代码。
your code with like aborton graph break
用类似 abort on graph break 的功能包住代码。
your code with like aborton graph break and then you know that you produced a
用类似 abort on graph break 的功能包住代码，就能知道是否产生了……
and then you know that you produced a
就能知道是否产生了……
and then you know that you produced a graph break or not but it's kind of I I
就能知道是否产生了图中断。不过我觉得……
graph break or not but it's kind of I I
是否发生图中断。不过我觉得……
graph break or not but it's kind of I I don't think there's one one answer that
是否发生图中断。不过我觉得没有一个……
don't think there's one one answer that
我觉得没有一个……
don't think there's one one answer that fits them all like we try to make those
我觉得没有一个适用于所有情况的答案。我们会尽量让这些功能……
fits them all like we try to make those
适用于所有情况。我们会尽量让这些功能……
fits them all like we try to make those not cause graph breaks but depending on
适用于所有情况。我们会尽量避免这些功能造成图中断，但这取决于……
not cause graph breaks but depending on
避免造成图中断，但这取决于……
not cause graph breaks but depending on the CUDA version you're on the hardware
避免造成图中断，但这取决于你使用的 CUDA 版本、硬件……
the CUDA version you're on the hardware
你使用的 CUDA 版本、硬件……
the CUDA version you're on the hardware capabilities is a Python version and so
你使用的 CUDA 版本、硬件能力、Python 版本等……
capabilities is a Python version and so
硬件能力、Python 版本等……
capabilities is a Python version and so on and so forth. It can cause graph
硬件能力、Python 版本等因素。它可能造成图中断。
on and so forth. It can cause graph
等等。它可能造成图中断。
on and so forth. It can cause graph break. So please check if it doesn't
等等。它可能造成图中断。所以请检查是否发生了……
break. So please check if it doesn't
图中断。所以请检查是否发生了……
break. So please check if it doesn't create great if it does file an issue
图中断。如果没有发生，那很好；如果发生了，请提交 issue。
create great if it does file an issue
没有发生就好；如果发生了，请提交 issue。
create great if it does file an issue but we try to eliminate as graph breaks
没有发生就好；如果发生了，请提交 issue。我们会尽量消除图中断。
but we try to eliminate as graph breaks
我们会尽量消除图中断。
but we try to eliminate as graph breaks as much as possible because it slows
我们会尽量消除图中断，因为它会拖慢……
as much as possible because it slows
因为它会拖慢……
as much as possible because it slows down
因为它会拖慢运行速度。
down
拖慢运行速度。
down your pipelines.
拖慢你的处理流程。
your pipelines.
你的处理流程。
your pipelines. >> Okay, awesome. Um, can we jump next to
你的处理流程。好的，太棒了。接下来可以看……
>> Okay, awesome. Um, can we jump next to
好的，太棒了。接下来可以看……
>> Okay, awesome. Um, can we jump next to the question about Envy Gym uh Q5? Uh,
好的，太棒了。接下来可以看关于 Envy Gym 的 Q5 问题吗？
the question about Envy Gym uh Q5? Uh,
关于 NVGEMM 的 Q5 问题？呃，
the question about Envy Gym uh Q5? Uh, Basil,
关于 NVGEMM 的 Q5 问题？呃，Basil，
>> sorry to do that verbally rather than in
抱歉，我直接口头说，没在……
>> sorry to do that verbally rather than in the chat.
抱歉，我直接口头说，没在聊天里发。
So, this is one of the key things that
这是我们强调的一个重点。
So, this is one of the key things that we highlighted at the be at the
这是我们一开始强调的一个重点。
we highlighted at the be at the
我们一开始就强调过。
we highlighted at the be at the beginning and I wanted to make sure we
我们一开始就强调过，我想确保大家……
beginning and I wanted to make sure we
一开始我就想确保大家……
beginning and I wanted to make sure we we took a moment to talk about it among
一开始我就想确保我们在答疑中花点时间聊聊。
we took a moment to talk about it among
我们在答疑中花点时间聊聊。
we took a moment to talk about it among the questions. Uh so what is NVGEM? Um
我们在答疑中花点时间聊聊：NVGEMM 是什么？
the questions. Uh so what is NVGEM? Um
问题是：NVGEMM 是什么？
the questions. Uh so what is NVGEM? Um kind of a generic question and how do I
问题是：NVGEMM 是什么？这个问题有点宽泛，还有怎么……
kind of a generic question and how do I
这个问题有点宽泛，还有怎么……
kind of a generic question and how do I turn it on? Um uh so uh Nikita do you
这个问题有点宽泛，还有怎么启用它？Nikita，你……
turn it on? Um uh so uh Nikita do you
怎么启用它？Nikita，你……
turn it on? Um uh so uh Nikita do you want to jump on this or Andre?
怎么启用它？Nikita 或 Andre，谁来回答？
want to jump on this or Andre?
Nikita 或 Andre，谁来回答？
want to jump on this or Andre? >> Sure. But we already somewhat covered it
Nikita 或 Andre，谁来回答？当然，不过我们刚才已经讲过一些了。
>> Sure. But we already somewhat covered it
当然，不过我们刚才已经讲过一些了。
>> Sure. But we already somewhat covered it when the other user asked a question
当然，不过刚才另一位用户提问时，我们已经讲过一些了。
when the other user asked a question
刚才另一位用户提问时……
when the other user asked a question about different uh good gen backends and
刚才另一位用户问到了不同的代码生成后端。
about different uh good gen backends and
关于不同的代码生成后端。
about different uh good gen backends and I said that there is a like you can't do
关于不同的代码生成后端，我说过，这个没法……
I said that there is a like you can't do
我说过，这个没法……
I said that there is a like you can't do it over FX graph but there is a toggles
我说过，没法通过 FX 图来做，但有相应的开关。
it over FX graph but there is a toggles
没法通过 FX 图来做，但有相应的开关。
it over FX graph but there is a toggles and specifically for NVJ there's max to
没法通过 FX 图来做，但有相应的开关。具体到 NVGEMM，还有……
and specifically for NVJ there's max to
具体到 NVGEMM，还有……
and specifically for NVJ there's max to tune gem backends
具体到 NVGEMM，有 max_autotune_gemm_backends 配置。
tune gem backends
GEMM 自动调优后端列表。
tune gem backends >> list and if you add NVJM here so it's
这个列表里加入 NVGEMM 就行。
>> list and if you add NVJM here so it's
把 NVGEMM 加进列表后，它……
>> list and if you add NVJM here so it's not enabled by default but then it will
把 NVGEMM 加进列表后，虽然它默认未启用，但这样就会……
not enabled by default but then it will
它默认未启用，但这样就会……
not enabled by default but then it will be enabled and it will allow some more
它默认未启用；加进去后就会启用，还能支持更多……
be enabled and it will allow some more
启用后还能支持更多……
be enabled and it will allow some more advanced epilog fusion and yeah NVJM is
启用后还能支持更高级的尾部融合。NVGEMM 是……
advanced epilog fusion and yeah NVJM is
更高级的尾部融合。NVGEMM 是……
advanced epilog fusion and yeah NVJM is um QGSL gem back end that based on
更高级的尾部融合。NVGEMM 是基于 CuTeDSL 的 GEMM 后端。
um QGSL gem back end that based on
它是基于 CuTeDSL 的 GEMM 后端，又基于……
um QGSL gem back end that based on cutless
它是基于 CUTLASS 的 CuTeDSL GEMM 后端。
cutless
基于 CUTLASS。
cutless and it allows you to like yeah fuse
基于 CUTLASS，还能让你融合……
and it allows you to like yeah fuse
还能让你融合……
and it allows you to like yeah fuse mules and fusions and get generate even
还能融合乘法等操作，生成更快的……
mules and fusions and get generate even
融合乘法等操作，生成更快的……
mules and fusions and get generate even faster uh yeah uh kernels specifically
融合乘法等操作，生成更快的内核。
faster uh yeah uh kernels specifically
更快，嗯，对，特别是内核。
faster uh yeah uh kernels specifically if you do low precision data types like
内核会更快，嗯，对，尤其是用低精度数据类型时，比如……
if you do low precision data types like
如果用低精度数据类型，比如……
if you do low precision data types like in VFP4 but it requires you to have an
比如 VFP4，但这要求你安装……
in VFP4 but it requires you to have an
用 VFP4 的话，你还需要安装……
in VFP4 but it requires you to have an Nvidia cutless DSL installed on your
用 VFP4 的话，你的系统必须装有 NVIDIA CUTLASS DSL……
Nvidia cutless DSL installed on your
你的系统得装有 NVIDIA CUTLASS DSL……
Nvidia cutless DSL installed on your system and blackwell as well so like you
你的系统得装有 NVIDIA CUTLASS DSL，还得有 Blackwell，所以……
system and blackwell as well so like you
系统还得有 Blackwell，所以……
system and blackwell as well so like you unfortunately cannot use 44 [laughter]
系统还得有 Blackwell，所以很遗憾，你用不了 44（笑声）。
unfortunately cannot use 44 [laughter]
很遗憾，用不了 44（笑声）。
unfortunately cannot use 44 [laughter] on your ampers or hoppers
很遗憾，Ampere 或 Hopper 上用不了 44（笑声）。
Okay, I see a question from Jose Silva
好，我看到 Jose Silva 的一个问题。
Okay, I see a question from Jose Silva on the on the chat. Um,
好，我看到 Jose Silva 在聊天区提了个问题。
on the on the chat. Um,
在聊天区。嗯。
on the on the chat. Um, okay, awesome. Thank you, Basil. Um, if
在聊天区。好，太好了。谢谢你，Basil。如果……
okay, awesome. Thank you, Basil. Um, if
好，太好了。谢谢你，Basil。如果……
okay, awesome. Thank you, Basil. Um, if I train a vision model on CUDA and
好，太好了。谢谢你，Basil。如果我在 CUDA 上训练视觉模型，然后……
I train a vision model on CUDA and
我在 CUDA 上训练视觉模型，然后……
I train a vision model on CUDA and export it using AOT inductor to C++
我在 CUDA 上训练视觉模型，再用 AOT Inductor 把它导出为 C++……
export it using AOT inductor to C++
用 AOT Inductor 把它导出为 C++……
export it using AOT inductor to C++ binaries for a machine running an Intel
用 AOT Inductor 把它导出为 C++ 二进制文件，供搭载 Intel……
binaries for a machine running an Intel
二进制文件，供搭载 Intel……
binaries for a machine running an Intel Iris iGPU. Um, is dynamic shape and
二进制文件，供搭载 Intel Iris iGPU 的机器运行。那么动态形状和……
Iris iGPU. Um, is dynamic shape and
Intel Iris iGPU。那么动态形状和……
Iris iGPU. Um, is dynamic shape and anti-quantization supported out of the
Intel Iris iGPU。那么动态形状和反量化能否直接……
anti-quantization supported out of the
反量化能否直接……
anti-quantization supported out of the box on those targets? On those XPU
反量化在这些目标平台上能否开箱即用？在这些 XPU……
box on those targets? On those XPU
在这些目标平台上能否开箱即用？这些 XPU……
box on those targets? On those XPU targets?
在这些目标平台上能否开箱即用？这些 XPU 目标平台呢？
targets?
目标平台呢？
targets? [laughter]
目标平台呢？（笑声）
[laughter]
（笑声）
[laughter] >> That's quite a specific question.
（笑声）>> 这个问题很具体。
>> That's quite a specific question.
>> 这个问题很具体。
>> That's quite a specific question. >> I was just going to say I don't know
>> 这个问题很具体。>> 我正想说，我不知道……
>> I was just going to say I don't know
>> 我正想说，我不知道……
>> I was just going to say I don't know that case is covered in rci. Uh,
>> 我正想说，我不知道 RCI 有没有覆盖这种情况。呃……
that case is covered in rci. Uh,
RCI 有没有覆盖这种情况。呃……
that case is covered in rci. Uh, [laughter]
RCI 有没有覆盖这种情况。呃，（笑声）
[laughter]
（笑声）
[laughter] >> it might be covered in rci, but maybe
（笑声）>> RCI 可能覆盖了，但也许……
>> it might be covered in rci, but maybe
>> RCI 可能覆盖了，但也许……
>> it might be covered in rci, but maybe not intel Iris iGPU in particular. Like
>> RCI 可能覆盖了，但未必专门覆盖 Intel Iris iGPU。我觉得……
not intel Iris iGPU in particular. Like
未必专门覆盖 Intel Iris iGPU。我觉得……
not intel Iris iGPU in particular. Like I think they're trying to cover a more
未必专门覆盖 Intel Iris iGPU。我觉得他们想覆盖更……
I think they're trying to cover a more
我觉得他们想覆盖更……
I think they're trying to cover a more >> modern GPUs. Uh
我觉得他们想覆盖更……>> 新一些的 GPU。呃……
>> modern GPUs. Uh
>> 新一些的 GPU。呃……
>> modern GPUs. Uh but I guess you never know until you try
>> 新一些的 GPU。不过不试试也说不准。
but I guess you never know until you try
不过，不试试怎么知道呢。
but I guess you never know until you try and then you can probably file an issue
不过，不试试怎么知道呢，然后你大概可以提个 issue。
and then you can probably file an issue
然后你大概可以提个 issue。
and then you can probably file an issue if it doesn't work.
然后你大概可以提个 issue，如果行不通的话。
if it doesn't work.
如果行不通的话。
if it doesn't work. >> Yeah, file is
如果行不通的话。>> 对，提个 issue。
>> Yeah, file is
>> 对，提个 issue。
>> Yeah, file is >> exactly [laughter]
>> 对，提个 issue。>> 没错（笑）
>> help us out.
>> 帮我们一把。
>> help us out. >> And we do have Yeah, we do have support
>> 帮我们一把。>> 而且我们确实有，对，确实支持……
>> And we do have Yeah, we do have support
>> 而且我们确实有，对，确实支持……
>> And we do have Yeah, we do have support for XPU devices. So on both PyTorch and
>> 而且我们确实有，对，确实支持 XPU 设备。所以在 PyTorch 和……
for XPU devices. So on both PyTorch and
适用于 XPU 设备。所以在 PyTorch 和
for XPU devices. So on both PyTorch and torch vision. So uh if you have a PR in
适用于 XPU 设备。所以在 PyTorch 和 torchvision 上。如果你有个 PR 的
torch vision. So uh if you have a PR in
torchvision。所以，如果你有个 PR 的
torch vision. So uh if you have a PR in mind, you can go and open a PR against
torchvision。所以，如果你有提交 PR 的想法，可以向
mind, you can go and open a PR against
想法，就可以向
mind, you can go and open a PR against PyTorch Vision CI.
想法，就可以向 PyTorch Vision CI 提交 PR。
PyTorch Vision CI.
PyTorch Vision 持续集成（CI）。
PyTorch Vision CI. But like I guess if I read the question
PyTorch Vision 持续集成（CI）。不过我想，如果我没理解错问题，
But like I guess if I read the question
不过我想，如果我没理解错问题，
But like I guess if I read the question correctly, if you train model on CUDA,
不过我想，如果我没理解错问题，如果你在 CUDA 上训练模型，
correctly, if you train model on CUDA,
如果我没理解错问题，如果你在 CUDA 上训练模型，
correctly, if you train model on CUDA, can you export it for XPU? You need to
如果我没理解错问题，如果你在 CUDA 上训练模型，能导出给 XPU 用吗？你需要……
can you export it for XPU? You need to
能导出给 XPU 用吗？你需要……
can you export it for XPU? You need to make some changes to your model first,
能导出到 XPU 吗？你得先修改一下模型，
make some changes to your model first,
先修改一下模型，
make some changes to your model first, right? You need to like transfer your
先修改一下模型，对吧？你得把你的……
right? You need to like transfer your
对吧？你得把你的……
right? You need to like transfer your model to XPU, make sure that it works
对吧？你得把模型转到 XPU 上，确保它能运行，
model to XPU, make sure that it works
把模型转到 XPU 上，确保它能运行，
model to XPU, make sure that it works and then AOT inductor should work on XPU
把模型转到 XPU 上，确保它能运行，然后 AOT Inductor 应该就能在 XPU 上工作了，
and then AOT inductor should work on XPU
然后 AOT Inductor 应该就能在 XPU 上工作了，
and then AOT inductor should work on XPU same as it works on any other back ends.
然后 AOT Inductor 应该就能在 XPU 上工作了，和在其他后端上一样。
same as it works on any other back ends.
和在其他后端上一样。
same as it works on any other back ends. But I'm not even sure if int 8
和在其他后端上一样。但我甚至不确定 int8……
But I'm not even sure if int 8
但我甚至不确定 int8……
But I'm not even sure if int 8 contisation is supported through
但我甚至不确定 Inductor 是否支持 int8 量化，
contisation is supported through
是否支持量化，
contisation is supported through inductor even for CUDA. like I think
即使在 CUDA 上，Inductor 是否支持量化，我也不确定。
inductor even for CUDA. like I think
inductor even for CUDA. like I think that there are lots of like layers to
即使在 CUDA 上，Inductor 是否支持量化，我也不确定。这里面还有很多层问题，
that there are lots of like layers to
这里面还有很多层问题，
that there are lots of like layers to unload here. So please file an issue but
这里面还有很多层问题要弄清楚。所以请提个 issue，不过……
unload here. So please file an issue but
要弄清楚。所以请提个 issue，不过……
unload here. So please file an issue but I also kind of think why do you want an
要弄清楚。所以请提个 issue。不过我也在想，你为什么想要……
I also kind of think why do you want an
我也在想，你为什么想要……
I also kind of think why do you want an int 8 rather than like well int 8 and
我也在想，你为什么想用 int8，而不是……嗯，int8，还有……
int 8 rather than like well int 8 and
用 int8，而不是……嗯，int8，还有……
int 8 rather than like well int 8 and and check the spec if iGPU even support
用 int8，而不是……嗯，int8。另外，查查规格，看看 iGPU 到底支不支持。
and check the spec if iGPU even support
再查查规格，看 iGPU 是否支持。
and check the spec if iGPU even support an int8ate uh fast smart n I know that
再查查规格，看 iGPU 是否支持 INT8 快速运算。我知道……
an int8ate uh fast smart n I know that
INT8 快速运算。我知道……
an int8ate uh fast smart n I know that CPUs do but I'm not sure about GPUs in
INT8 快速运算。我知道 CPU 支持，但不确定 GPU 是否……
CPUs do but I'm not sure about GPUs in
CPU 支持，但我不确定 GPU 是否……
CPUs do but I'm not sure about GPUs in particular.
CPU 支持，但我不确定 GPU 是否支持。
Um
嗯。
Um I think Basil's pulling the one that we
我想 Basil 正在找我们……
I think Basil's pulling the one that we
I think Basil's pulling the one that we mentioned to him here.
我想 Basil 正在找我们刚才跟他提到的那个。
Maybe in the meantime we can do a small
趁这会儿，我们可以简单……
Maybe in the meantime we can do a small uh note about PyTorch release matrix. So
趁这会儿，我们可以简单说说 PyTorch 的版本对应关系。
uh note about PyTorch release matrix. So
说说 PyTorch 的版本对应关系。那么……
uh note about PyTorch release matrix. So one of the changes that is in 214 is
说说 PyTorch 的版本对应关系。214 中有一项改动是……
one of the changes that is in 214 is
214 中有一项改动是……
one of the changes that is in 214 is that we mandate that all of your
214 中有一项改动是，我们要求你的所有……
that we mandate that all of your
我们要求你的所有……
that we mandate that all of your extensions will be compiled with oh here
我们要求你的所有扩展都用……哦，找到了。
extensions will be compiled with oh here
扩展都用……哦，找到了。
extensions will be compiled with oh here you go C++ 20 by default. So if you're
扩展默认用 C++ 20 编译。所以如果你……
you go C++ 20 by default. So if you're
找到了，是默认用 C++ 20。所以如果你……
you go C++ 20 by default. So if you're using an older compiler, you really need
是默认用 C++ 20。所以如果你用的是旧编译器，就得……
using an older compiler, you really need
如果你用的是旧编译器，就得……
using an older compiler, you really need to update. It is 2026 and majority of
如果你用的是旧编译器，就得升级。现在是 2026 年，大多数……
to update. It is 2026 and majority of
就得升级。现在是 2026 年，大多数……
to update. It is 2026 and majority of the compiler should be able to support
就得升级。现在是 2026 年，大多数编译器都应该支持……
the compiler should be able to support
大多数编译器都应该支持……
the compiler should be able to support C++ 20. Uh but that's
大多数编译器都应该支持 C++ 20。不过这……
C++ 20. Uh but that's
C++ 20。不过这……
C++ 20. Uh but that's backward compatibility breaking change.
C++ 20。不过这是一项破坏向后兼容性的改动。
backward compatibility breaking change.
这是一项破坏向后兼容性的改动。
backward compatibility breaking change. And with that, I don't know, Andrew, do
这是一项破坏向后兼容性的改动。说到这儿，Andrew，你要不要……
And with that, I don't know, Andrew, do
说到这儿，Andrew，你要不要……
And with that, I don't know, Andrew, do you want to Oh, Chris, do you want to
说到这儿，Andrew，你要不要……哦，Chris，你要不要……
you want to Oh, Chris, do you want to
你要不要……哦，Chris，你要不要……
you want to Oh, Chris, do you want to read the question first?
你要不要……哦，Chris，你要先读一下问题吗？
read the question first?
先读一下问题吗？
read the question first? >> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, so this this
先读一下问题吗？对，对。那么这个……
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, so this this
对，对。那么这个……
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, so this this question which I think was going in the
对，对。我觉得这个问题和……
question which I think was going in the
我觉得这个问题和……
question which I think was going in the same direction that that Nikita was was
我觉得这个问题和 Nikita 想的方向一样……
same direction that that Nikita was was
和 Nikita 想的方向一样……
same direction that that Nikita was was thinking is do I still have to upgrade
和 Nikita 想的方向一样：我还需要每次都升级……
thinking is do I still have to upgrade
问题是，我还需要每次都升级……
thinking is do I still have to upgrade um torch vision every time I upgrade
问题是，每次升级 PyTorch，我还得升级 torchvision 吗？
um torch vision every time I upgrade
每次升级 PyTorch，我还得升级 torchvision 吗？
um torch vision every time I upgrade grade pietorch which I know was a
每次升级 PyTorch，我还得升级 torchvision 吗？我知道这以前……
grade pietorch which I know was a
升级 PyTorch 时，我知道这以前……
grade pietorch which I know was a headache that people uh had to deal with
升级 PyTorch 时，我知道这以前一直让大家很头疼。
headache that people uh had to deal with
大家不得不面对的麻烦
headache that people uh had to deal with for a very long time that um Andre do
大家长期以来不得不面对的麻烦。Andre，你……
for a very long time that um Andre do
长期以来的麻烦。Andre，你……
for a very long time that um Andre do you want to respond to this?
大家长期以来都要面对这个麻烦。Andre，你想回应一下吗？
you want to respond to this?
你想回应一下吗？
you want to respond to this? >> Yes. Yes. Um so torch vision uh 0.29 is
是的。torchvision 0.29 与……
>> Yes. Yes. Um so torch vision uh 0.29 is
>> Yes. Yes. Um so torch vision uh 0.29 is a stable uh with respect to 21.14. So it
是的。torchvision 0.29 与 21.14 兼容，所以它……
a stable uh with respect to 21.14. So it
与 21.14 兼容，所以它……
a stable uh with respect to 21.14. So it will keep working with later version
与 21.14 兼容，也能继续支持后续版本。
will keep working with later version
也能继续支持后续版本。
will keep working with later version 2.15 2.16 and later. Uh the only catch
也能继续支持 2.15、2.16 及更高版本。唯一要注意的是……
2.15 2.16 and later. Uh the only catch
2.15、2.16 及更高版本。唯一要注意的是……
2.15 2.16 and later. Uh the only catch here if you need to um introduce new
2.15、2.16 及更高版本。唯一要注意的是，如果要引入新的……
here if you need to um introduce new
如果要引入新的……
here if you need to um introduce new CUDA version you may need to download
如果要引入新的 CUDA 版本，可能需要下载……
CUDA version you may need to download
如果要用新的 CUDA 版本，可能需要下载……
CUDA version you may need to download um version of torch vision compiled with
如果要用新的 CUDA 版本，可能需要下载对应版本编译的 torchvision。
um version of torch vision compiled with
用对应版本编译的 torchvision。
um version of torch vision compiled with this CUDA version. Um but yes um like as
用这个 CUDA 版本编译的 torchvision。不过，是的……
this CUDA version. Um but yes um like as
这个 CUDA 版本。不过，是的……
this CUDA version. Um but yes um like as um
这个 CUDA 版本。不过，基本上……
um
嗯。
um as a basic you no longer need matching
基本上，你不再需要匹配版本的……
as a basic you no longer need matching
as a basic you no longer need matching torch vision to install every torch
基本上，每次安装新版 torch，都不再需要匹配版本的 torchvision。
torch vision to install every torch
每次安装新版 torch，都不再需要匹配版本的 torchvision。
torch vision to install every torch upgrade and uh in the future we may not
每次升级 torch，都不再需要安装匹配版本的 torchvision。以后我们可能也不会……
upgrade and uh in the future we may not
升级之后，以后我们可能也不会……
upgrade and uh in the future we may not do torch vision at the same time as
升级之后，以后我们可能不会再同时发布 torchvision 和……
do torch vision at the same time as
不会再同时发布 torchvision 和……
do torch vision at the same time as torch. So the releases could be um a
不会再同时发布 torchvision 和 torch，所以两个版本的发布可能会……
torch. So the releases could be um a
和 torch。所以两个版本的发布可能会……
torch. So the releases could be um a little bit decoupled because of this. So
和 torch。所以两个版本的发布可以稍微错开。
little bit decoupled because of this. So
因此，两个版本的发布可以稍微错开。
little bit decoupled because of this. So I think it's something good for us. It's
因此，两个版本的发布可以稍微错开。我觉得这对我们是件好事。
I think it's something good for us. It's
我觉得这对我们是件好事。
I think it's something good for us. It's a good news.
我觉得这对我们是件好事，是个好消息。
>> Just next next question, please.
请看下一个问题。
>> Just next next question, please. >> Next question.
请看下一个问题。下一个问题。
>> Next question.
下一个问题。
>> Next question. >> Okay. So, what is new for writing
下一个问题。好的，编写……有什么新进展？
>> Okay. So, what is new for writing
好的，编写……有什么新进展？
>> Okay. So, what is new for writing dynamic models that still compile? Well,
好的，编写仍能编译的动态模型有什么新进展？
dynamic models that still compile? Well,
仍能编译的动态模型有什么新进展？
dynamic models that still compile? Well, um Andre, do you want to take this one
仍能编译的动态模型有什么新进展？Andre，你要回答这个问题吗？
um Andre, do you want to take this one
Andre，你要回答这个问题吗？
um Andre, do you want to take this one as as as well?
Andre，这个问题也请你回答一下？
as as as well?
也请你回答一下？
as as as well? >> I think we answered this question kind
也请你回答一下？我觉得这个问题我们算是回答过了……
>> I think we answered this question kind
我想这个问题我们算是回答过了
>> I think we answered this question kind of twice already. There was a question
我想这个问题我们已经回答过两次了。还有个问题
of twice already. There was a question
已经回答过两次了。还有个问题
of twice already. There was a question separate. Like if we want to highlight
已经回答过两次了。还有个单独的问题。比如，如果要重点介绍
separate. Like if we want to highlight
单独的问题。比如，如果要重点介绍
separate. Like if we want to highlight the features there is a torch switch uh
单独的问题。比如，如果要重点介绍这些功能，有 torch switch
the features there is a torch switch uh
这些功能有 torch switch
the features there is a torch switch uh torch while loop that is captured across
这些功能有 torch switch，还有 torch while loop，它能跨
torch while loop that is captured across
torch while loop，它能跨
torch while loop that is captured across codraph and dynamic spec and people
torch while loop，它能跨 CUDA Graph 和动态规格捕获。大家
codraph and dynamic spec and people
CUDA Graph 和动态规格。大家
codraph and dynamic spec and people already asked about dynamic spec and
CUDA Graph 和动态规格。大家已经问过动态规格
already asked about dynamic spec and
已经问过动态规格
already asked about dynamic spec and whether it will cause inductor to fail
已经问过动态规格，以及它是否会导致 Inductor 失败
whether it will cause inductor to fail
它是否会导致 Inductor 失败
whether it will cause inductor to fail when it goes above like an upper
它是否会在超过某个上限时导致 Inductor 失败
when it goes above like an upper
在超过某个上限时
when it goes above like an upper boundary. People talked about uh asked
在超过某个上限时。大家还问过
boundary. People talked about uh asked
上限。大家还问过
boundary. People talked about uh asked about specialization but yes those are
上限。大家还问过特化的问题。对，这些就是
about specialization but yes those are
特化的问题。对，这些就是
about specialization but yes those are the features that you should try and
特化的问题。对，这些就是你应该尝试的功能
the features that you should try and
你应该尝试的功能
the features that you should try and like uh they will improve your VSC to
你应该尝试这些功能，它们会提升你的 VSC
like uh they will improve your VSC to
它们会提升你的 VSC
like uh they will improve your VSC to compile model with dynamically shaped
它们会提升你的 VSC，让它能编译输入形状动态变化的模型
compile model with dynamically shaped
编译输入形状动态变化的模型
compile model with dynamically shaped inputs like you will have fun um
编译输入形状动态变化的模型，你会得到
inputs like you will have fun um
输入形状动态变化的模型，你会得到
inputs like you will have fun um compiled artifacts that works for
对于形状动态变化的输入，你会得到适用的编译产物
compiled artifacts that works for
适用的编译产物
compiled artifacts that works for multiple shapes. So once again it's in
适用于多种形状的编译产物。所以再说一遍，就是
multiple shapes. So once again it's in
适用于多种形状。所以再说一遍，就是
multiple shapes. So once again it's in the torch switch [laughter] torch loop
适用于多种形状。所以再说一遍，就是 torch switch（笑）、torch loop
the torch switch [laughter] torch loop
就是 torch switch（笑）、torch loop
the torch switch [laughter] torch loop and dynamics back.
就是 torch switch（笑）、torch loop 和动态规格。
and dynamics back.
还有动态规格。
and dynamics back. >> Uh can we jump to question 14 in our
还有动态规格。>> 呃，我们能跳到准备好的第 14 个问题吗
>> Uh can we jump to question 14 in our
>> 呃，我们能跳到准备好的第 14 个问题吗
>> Uh can we jump to question 14 in our prepared ones? Um
>> 呃，我们能跳到准备好的第 14 个问题吗？
prepared ones? Um
准备好的问题吗？
prepared ones? Um this is the everpresent Torch script uh
准备好的问题吗？这是那个总会出现的 TorchScript 话题
this is the everpresent Torch script uh
这是那个总会出现的 TorchScript 话题
this is the everpresent Torch script uh topic [snorts]
这是那个总会出现的 TorchScript 话题（笑）
topic [snorts]
这个话题（笑）
topic [snorts] trying to touch on things that we
这个话题（笑），尽量谈谈我们
trying to touch on things that we
尽量谈谈我们
trying to touch on things that we haven't already discussed. Okay. So I
尽量谈谈我们还没讨论过的内容。好，我
haven't already discussed. Okay. So I
还没讨论过的内容。好，我
haven't already discussed. Okay. So I still use Torch script. Should I be
还没讨论过的内容。好，我还在用 TorchScript。我是不是该
still use Torch script. Should I be
还在用 TorchScript，我该……
still use Torch script. Should I be worried? Um Nikita, do you want to
我还在用 TorchScript，需要担心吗？呃，Nikita，你想……
worried? Um Nikita, do you want to
担心吗？呃，Nikita，你想……
worried? Um Nikita, do you want to answer this one?
担心吗？呃，Nikita，你想回答这个问题吗？
answer this one?
回答这个问题吗？
answer this one? Yes, we've been saying that to script
回答这个问题吗？是的，我们一直说 TorchScript……
Yes, we've been saying that to script
是的，我们一直说 TorchScript……
Yes, we've been saying that to script has been deprecated since I think 211 or
是的，我们一直说 TorchScript 大概从 211 或……起就已弃用。
has been deprecated since I think 211 or
我记得是从 211 或……起就已弃用。
has been deprecated since I think 211 or 212 and it has not been really working
我记得是从 211 或 212 起就已弃用，而且一直不太能用。
212 and it has not been really working
212，而且一直不太能用。
212 and it has not been really working even like you cannot use script on you
212，而且一直不太能用，甚至你都没法用 Script……
even like you cannot use script on you
甚至你都没法用 Script……
even like you cannot use script on you cannot trace the store script on Python
甚至你没法在 Python 上做追踪或用 Script……
cannot trace the store script on Python
没法在 Python 上做追踪或用 Script……
cannot trace the store script on Python 314 and I'm not sure what is the status
在 Python 3.14 上没法做追踪或用 Script，我也不清楚……
314 and I'm not sure what is the status
Python 3.14，我也不清楚……
314 and I'm not sure what is the status of 312 or 313 like it's just being
Python 3.14；至于 3.12 或 3.13，我也不清楚是什么情况。它已经……
of 312 or 313 like it's just being
至于 3.12 或 3.13，它已经……
of 312 or 313 like it's just being deprecated there are bugs there are
至于 3.12 或 3.13，它已经弃用，还有各种问题……
deprecated there are bugs there are
已经弃用，还有各种问题……
deprecated there are bugs there are security problems it supports less and
已经弃用，有漏洞和安全问题，支持的功能也越来越少……
security problems it supports less and
有安全问题，支持的功能也越来越少……
security problems it supports less and less operators I don't think you can
有安全问题，支持的算子越来越少，我觉得你已经没法……
less operators I don't think you can
支持的算子越来越少，我觉得你没法……
less operators I don't think you can capture anything that support
支持的算子越来越少，我觉得你没法捕获任何支持……
capture anything that support
捕获任何支持……
capture anything that support flotate or whatever. So don't use to
捕获任何支持 float8 之类功能的东西。所以别再用……
flotate or whatever. So don't use to
float8 之类的功能。所以别再用……
flotate or whatever. So don't use to script anymore. So AOTI expert is a
float8 之类的功能。所以别再用 TorchScript 了。AOTI 导出已经是个……
script anymore. So AOTI expert is a
别再用 TorchScript 了。AOTI 导出已经是个……
script anymore. So AOTI expert is a pretty uh like mature framework at this
别再用 TorchScript 了。AOTI 导出现在已经相当成熟……
pretty uh like mature framework at this
现在已经相当成熟……
pretty uh like mature framework at this point. Use this one. If you need to use
现在已经相当成熟了。用它吧。如果你需要用……
point. Use this one. If you need to use
成熟了。用它吧。如果你需要用……
point. Use this one. If you need to use script, you can use an older PyTorch but
用它吧。如果你必须用 Script，可以用旧版 PyTorch，但……
script, you can use an older PyTorch but
如果必须用 Script，可以用旧版 PyTorch，但……
script, you can use an older PyTorch but like be aware of the limitation. Be like
如果必须用 Script，可以用旧版 PyTorch，但要了解它的限制。
like be aware of the limitation. Be like
要了解它的限制。另外……
like be aware of the limitation. Be like we will be happy if there is a community
要了解它的限制。如果有社区维护者愿意……
we will be happy if there is a community
如果有社区维护者愿意……
we will be happy if there is a community maintainer who want to like look into
如果有社区维护者愿意接手维护……
maintainer who want to like look into
愿意接手维护……
maintainer who want to like look into the torch script but we are not actively
愿意接手维护 TorchScript，我们会很高兴，但我们目前没有积极……
the torch script but we are not actively
TorchScript，但我们目前没有积极……
the torch script but we are not actively working on new features or have anyone
TorchScript，但我们目前没有开发新功能，也没有人……
working on new features or have anyone
开发新功能，也没有人……
working on new features or have anyone who actively like triages in common
开发新功能，也没有人定期处理常见……
who actively like triages in common
定期处理常见……
who actively like triages in common issues. So unless they are security
定期处理常见问题。所以，除非涉及安全问题……
issues. So unless they are security
问题。所以，除非是安全
issues. So unless they are security related they will probably stay as is
问题。所以，除非涉及安全，否则大概会保持原样。
related they will probably stay as is
相关，否则大概会保持原样。
related they will probably stay as is and craft and script is not a security
相关，否则大概会保持原样；craft 和 script 不属于安全
and craft and script is not a security
而 craft 和 script 不属于安全
and craft and script is not a security issue unfortunately.
而 craft 和 script 很遗憾不属于安全问题。
>> Okay we have I think we have one left
好，我想我们还剩一个
>> Okay we have I think we have one left one more remaining um prepared question.
好，我想我们还剩最后一个事先准备的问题。
one more remaining um prepared question.
还剩最后一个事先准备的问题。
one more remaining um prepared question. Um
还剩最后一个事先准备的问题。嗯，
Um
嗯。
Um >> we switch to community ones or whatever.
嗯。我们要转到社区提问之类的吗？
>> we switch to community ones or whatever.
我们要转到社区提问之类的吗？
>> we switch to community ones or whatever. >> No I
我们要转到社区提问之类的吗？不，我……
>> No I
不，我……
>> No I okay I think we have one more prepared
不，我想我们还有一个事先准备的
okay I think we have one more prepared
好，我想我们还有一个事先准备的
okay I think we have one more prepared one. If there are community ones let's
好，我想我们还有一个事先准备的问题。如果有社区提问，我们
one. If there are community ones let's
问题。如果有社区提问，我们
one. If there are community ones let's go back and make sure we catch them
问题。如果有社区提问，我们回头确认一下，
go back and make sure we catch them
回头确认一下，别漏掉。
go back and make sure we catch them before we end. Um, so I hear that uh
回头确认一下，结束前别漏掉。嗯，我听说
before we end. Um, so I hear that uh
结束前别漏掉。嗯，我听说
before we end. Um, so I hear that uh 21.14 supports Python 315. Can I just
结束前别漏掉。嗯，我听说 2.14 支持 Python 3.15。我能直接
21.14 supports Python 315. Can I just
2.14 支持 Python 3.15。我能直接
21.14 supports Python 315. Can I just pip install Torch on it? Um, Andre, do
2.14 支持 Python 3.15。我能直接用 pip install torch 安装吗？Andre，
pip install Torch on it? Um, Andre, do
用 pip install torch 安装吗？Andre，你
pip install Torch on it? Um, Andre, do you want to take this one?
用 pip install torch 安装吗？Andre，你来回答这个问题好吗？
you want to take this one?
你来回答这个问题好吗？
you want to take this one? >> Um, yes. Uh, so basically the short
你来回答这个问题好吗？嗯，可以。简单
>> Um, yes. Uh, so basically the short
嗯，可以。简单来说，
>> Um, yes. Uh, so basically the short answer, we do support 315. Uh, but it's
嗯，可以。简单来说，我们确实支持 Python 3.15，但目前
answer, we do support 315. Uh, but it's
来说，我们确实支持 Python 3.15，但目前
answer, we do support 315. Uh, but it's only available via download pytorch.org.
来说，我们确实支持 Python 3.15，但目前只能从 download.pytorch.org 下载。
only available via download pytorch.org.
只能从 download.pytorch.org 下载。
only available via download pytorch.org. So pip install torch will not work with
只能从 download.pytorch.org 下载。所以直接运行 pip install torch
So pip install torch will not work with
所以直接运行 pip install torch 无法安装
So pip install torch will not work with 315 for this release 2014. Um
所以在 2.14 版本中，无法通过 pip install torch 安装 Python 3.15 对应的版本。
315 for this release 2014. Um
在 2.14 版本中，Python 3.15 对应的版本还不行。嗯，
315 for this release 2014. Um having said that in the future uh we are
在 2.14 版本中，Python 3.15 对应的版本还不行。不过将来我们
having said that in the future uh we are
不过将来我们
having said that in the future uh we are planning on um uh publishing for the
不过将来我们计划发布
planning on um uh publishing for the
计划发布
planning on um uh publishing for the next release 2.15 we're publishing uh
计划在下一个 2.15 版本发布
next release 2.15 we're publishing uh
下一个 2.15 版本会发布
next release 2.15 we're publishing uh 315 Python to the pipy as a default one.
下一个 2.15 版本会默认将 Python 3.15 对应的包发布到 PyPI。
315 Python to the pipy as a default one.
默认将 Python 3.15 对应的包发布到 PyPI。
315 Python to the pipy as a default one. We also be duplicating Python 3.10 for
默认将 Python 3.15 对应的包发布到 PyPI。我们还会为 Python 3.10 同时构建一份，
We also be duplicating Python 3.10 for
我们还会为 Python 3.10 同时构建一份，
We also be duplicating Python 3.10 for the next release. I think it's very
下一个版本也会为 Python 3.10 同时构建一份。我觉得这很
the next release. I think it's very
下个版本。我觉得这很……
the next release. I think it's very important if you're still running 3.10
下个版本。如果你还在用 3.10，这一点很重要。
important if you're still running 3.10
如果你还在用 3.10，这一点很重要。
important if you're still running 3.10 for next release it will not be
如果你还在用 3.10，下个版本将不再……
for next release it will not be
下个版本将不再……
for next release it will not be supported. no wheels published and um
下个版本将不再支持，也不会发布 wheel 包，嗯……
supported. no wheels published and um
不再支持，也不会发布 wheel 包，嗯……
supported. no wheels published and um compiling from source will not be
不再支持，也不会发布 wheel 包，而且也无法从源码编译……
compiling from source will not be
也无法从源码编译……
compiling from source will not be possible. So we'll be migrating or
也无法从源码编译。所以我们会迁移，或者……
possible. So we'll be migrating or
所以我们会迁移，或者……
possible. So we'll be migrating or supporting minimum 311.
所以我们会迁移，或者将最低支持版本设为 3.11。
supporting minimum 311.
最低支持版本是 3.11。
supporting minimum 311. Um but yes for the current version 310
最低支持版本是 3.11。不过当前版本仍支持 3.10……
Um but yes for the current version 310
不过当前版本仍支持 3.10……
Um but yes for the current version 310 3.15 including uh free threaded 3.15T is
不过当前版本支持 3.10 到 3.15，包括自由线程版 3.15T。
3.15 including uh free threaded 3.15T is
3.15，包括自由线程版 3.15T，都……
3.15 including uh free threaded 3.15T is are supported. However, one more call
3.15，包括自由线程版 3.15T，都受支持。不过还要说明一点……
are supported. However, one more call
都受支持。不过还要说明一点……
are supported. However, one more call out is that torch compile is still not
都受支持。不过还要说明一点：torch.compile 仍未……
out is that torch compile is still not
还要说明一点：torch.compile 仍未……
out is that torch compile is still not enabled for 315 and 315T.
还要说明一点：torch.compile 尚未对 3.15 和 3.15T 启用。
enabled for 315 and 315T.
尚未对 3.15 和 3.15T 启用。
enabled for 315 and 315T. Um yes I think that's that's about uh
尚未对 3.15 和 3.15T 启用。嗯，我想差不多就是这些。
Um yes I think that's that's about uh
嗯，我想差不多就是这些。
Um yes I think that's that's about uh covers it. I don't know if anybody else
嗯，我想这差不多说全了。不知道其他人是否……
covers it. I don't know if anybody else
差不多说全了。不知道其他人是否……
covers it. I don't know if anybody else have any additional thoughts.
差不多说全了。不知道其他人还有没有补充。
have any additional thoughts.
还有没有补充？
have any additional thoughts. Oh, maybe like kind of a reason why we
还有没有补充？哦，也许该说说我们为什么……
Oh, maybe like kind of a reason why we
哦，也许该说说我们为什么……
Oh, maybe like kind of a reason why we don't support 310 anymore because uh it
哦，也许该解释一下为什么不再支持 3.10，因为它……
don't support 310 anymore because uh it
不再支持 3.10，是因为它……
don't support 310 anymore because uh it reached its end of life per um like uh
不再支持 3.10，是因为它已经到了生命周期终点……
reached its end of life per um like uh
它已经到了生命周期终点……
reached its end of life per um like uh Python end of life policy for the
按照 Python 的版本生命周期政策，它已经到了生命周期终点……
Python end of life policy for the
按照 Python 的版本生命周期政策……
Python end of life policy for the releases and we also will be like so we
按照 Python 的版本生命周期政策，我们也会……
releases and we also will be like so we
我们也会……
releases and we also will be like so we constantly reviewing the supported
我们会持续审查受支持的……
constantly reviewing the supported
持续审查受支持的……
constantly reviewing the supported platforms and unfortunately retires the
我们持续审查受支持的平台，遗憾的是会淘汰……
platforms and unfortunately retires the
平台，遗憾的是会淘汰……
platforms and unfortunately retires the ones that like go out of support so we
遗憾的是，不再受支持的平台会被淘汰，所以我们……
ones that like go out of support so we
不再受支持的平台会被淘汰，所以我们……
ones that like go out of support so we probably also be stopping supporting
不再受支持的平台会被淘汰，所以我们可能也会停止支持……
probably also be stopping supporting
可能也会停止支持……
probably also be stopping supporting like Mac OS I forget what was released
可能也会停止支持某个 macOS 版本，我忘了三年前发布的是哪一版……
like Mac OS I forget what was released
比如三年前发布的 macOS 版本，我忘了具体是哪一版……
like Mac OS I forget what was released from three years ago but the typical and
比如三年前发布的 macOS 版本，我忘了具体是哪一版，但通常……
from three years ago but the typical and
三年前的，但通常……
from three years ago but the typical and life cycle for those releases are also
三年前的，但这些版本的正常生命周期也是……
life cycle for those releases are also
这些版本的生命周期也是……
life cycle for those releases are also three So we will be returning that one
这些版本的生命周期也是三年，所以我们也会停止支持那个版本。
three So we will be returning that one
三年，所以我们也会停止支持那个版本。
three So we will be returning that one as well. And again CUDA 12 that was
三年，所以我们也会停止支持那个版本。另外，刚才提到的 CUDA 12……
as well. And again CUDA 12 that was
另外，刚才提到的 CUDA 12……
as well. And again CUDA 12 that was mentioned before. Let's repeat it again
另外，刚才提到的 CUDA 12，我们再说一遍……
mentioned before. Let's repeat it again
刚才提到过，我们再说一遍……
mentioned before. Let's repeat it again that CUDA 12 support is going away. So
刚才提到过，我们再说一遍：CUDA 12 的支持即将结束。
that CUDA 12 support is going away. So
CUDA 12 的支持即将结束。所以……
that CUDA 12 support is going away. So you should still be able to build from
CUDA 12 的支持即将结束。不过你应该仍能从源码……
you should still be able to build from
你应该仍能从源码……
you should still be able to build from source. We try not to break that thing.
你应该仍能从源码构建。我们会尽量保证这条路可行。
source. We try not to break that thing.
从源码构建。我们会尽量保证这条路可行。
source. We try not to break that thing. And I don't think we will actively kind
从源码构建。我们会尽量保证这条路可行。我想我们也不会主动……
And I don't think we will actively kind
我想我们也不会主动……
And I don't think we will actively kind of break 310 but we will not be done
我想我们不会主动让 3.10 无法使用，但我们不会再……
of break 310 but we will not be done
让 3.10 无法使用，但我们不会再……
of break 310 but we will not be done like testing it. So it will get broken
让 3.10 无法使用，但我们不会再测试它，所以它迟早会出问题。
like testing it. So it will get broken
测试它，所以它迟早会出问题。
like testing it. So it will get broken eventually.
eventually.
迟早会出问题。
eventually. Cool.
迟早会出问题。好。
Cool.
好。
Cool. >> Okay. I think we have a couple more
好。>> 好的，我想我们还有几个……
>> Okay. I think we have a couple more
>> 好的，我想我们还有几个……
>> Okay. I think we have a couple more questions lined up. Um, so, uh, Brian
>> 好的，我想我们还有几个问题。Brian……
questions lined up. Um, so, uh, Brian
还有几个问题。Brian……
questions lined up. Um, so, uh, Brian asks, "How can I use PyTorch to create
还有几个问题。Brian 问：“怎样用 PyTorch 创建……
asks, "How can I use PyTorch to create
问：“怎样用 PyTorch 创建……
asks, "How can I use PyTorch to create my own LLMs?"
问：“怎样用 PyTorch 创建自己的大语言模型？”
my own LLMs?"
自己的大语言模型？”
my own LLMs?" Anyone [laughter] want to?
自己的大语言模型？”有人想答吗？［笑声］
Anyone [laughter] want to?
有人想答吗？［笑声］
Anyone [laughter] want to? >> There are lots of great tutorials. I
有人想答吗？［笑声］>> 有很多很棒的教程。我……
>> There are lots of great tutorials. I
>> 有很多很棒的教程。我……
>> There are lots of great tutorials. I want to say that like that tell how you
>> 有很多很棒的教程。我想说，它们会教你怎么……
want to say that like that tell how you
我想说，它们会教你怎么……
want to say that like that tell how you can write
我想说，它们会教你怎么编写……
can write
编写……
can write >> like LLM training and inference like
编写……>> 比如大语言模型的训练和推理……
>> like LLM training and inference like
>> 比如大语言模型的训练和推理……
>> like LLM training and inference like Andrew Corp's uh like tiny story will be
>> 比如大语言模型的训练和推理，Andrew Corp 的 TinyStory……
Andrew Corp's uh like tiny story will be
Andrew Corp 的 TinyStory……
Andrew Corp's uh like tiny story will be like a good one if you want to get
Andrew Corp 的 TinyStory 就很适合想要……
like a good one if you want to get
很适合想要……
like a good one if you want to get familiar with LLMs. But if you want to
很适合想要了解大语言模型的人。但如果你想……
familiar with LLMs. But if you want to
了解大语言模型。但如果你想……
familiar with LLMs. But if you want to train your own [laughter] like I don't
了解大语言模型。但如果你想训练自己的模型，［笑声］我就不……
train your own [laughter] like I don't
自己训练一个（笑），比如我也不……
train your own [laughter] like I don't know uh
自己训练一个（笑），比如我也不知道，呃……
know uh
知道，呃……
know uh leading model using just PyTorch you
知道，呃，只用 PyTorch 训练顶尖模型，你……
leading model using just PyTorch you
只用 PyTorch 训练顶尖模型，你……
leading model using just PyTorch you need a pretty substantial hardware
只用 PyTorch 训练顶尖模型，你需要投入相当多的硬件。
need a pretty substantial hardware
你需要投入相当多的硬件。
need a pretty substantial hardware investments uh which might be a bigger
需要投入相当多的硬件，呃，这可能是更大的……
investments uh which might be a bigger
硬件投入，呃，这可能是更大的……
investments uh which might be a bigger blocker
硬件投入，呃，这可能是更大的障碍。
blocker
障碍。
blocker >> and also you need a lot of data right so
障碍。>> 而且还需要大量数据，对吧？所以……
>> and also you need a lot of data right so
>> 而且还需要大量数据，对吧？所以……
>> and also you need a lot of data right so like I think the bottleneck is not your
>> 而且还需要大量数据，对吧？所以我觉得瓶颈不在于你的……
like I think the bottleneck is not your
我觉得瓶颈不在于你的……
like I think the bottleneck is not your framework but your infrastructure and
我觉得瓶颈不在于你的框架，而在于基础设施和……
framework but your infrastructure and
框架，而在于基础设施和……
framework but your infrastructure and your data
框架，而在于基础设施和数据。
your data
你的数据。
your data >> yeah I was going to say
你的数据。>> 对，我正想说。
>> yeah I was going to say
>> 对，我正想说。
>> yeah I was going to say >> there there are some folks out there
>> 对，我正想说。>> 确实有人在……
>> there there are some folks out there
>> 确实有人在……
>> there there are some folks out there creating opensource models models that
>> 确实有人在开发开源模型，这些模型……
creating opensource models models that
开发开源模型，这些模型……
creating opensource models models that you could then maybe [laughter]
开发开源模型，之后你或许可以（笑）……
you could then maybe [laughter]
之后你或许可以（笑）……
you could then maybe [laughter] refine. I don't know, Joe.
之后你或许可以（笑）微调一下。我也说不准，Joe。
refine. I don't know, Joe.
微调一下。我也说不准，Joe。
refine. I don't know, Joe. >> Hopefully soon. Yeah, hopefully. Uh when
微调一下。我也说不准，Joe。>> 希望很快吧。对，希望如此。呃，等……
>> Hopefully soon. Yeah, hopefully. Uh when
>> 希望很快吧。对，希望如此。呃，等……
>> Hopefully soon. Yeah, hopefully. Uh when those models models are hard to build, I
>> 希望很快吧。对，希望如此。呃，那些模型很难做，我……
those models models are hard to build, I
那些模型很难做，我……
those models models are hard to build, I have to say. Um no, I I I think like
那些模型很难做，我得承认。嗯，不，我觉得……
have to say. Um no, I I I think like
得承认。嗯，不，我觉得……
have to say. Um no, I I I think like building models from scratch, like
得承认。嗯，不，我觉得从零开始构建模型，比如……
building models from scratch, like
从零开始构建模型，比如……
building models from scratch, like really good ones obviously is expensive.
从零开始构建模型，尤其是好模型，显然很烧钱。
really good ones obviously is expensive.
尤其是好模型，显然很烧钱。
really good ones obviously is expensive. I think, you know, to Nikita's point,
尤其是好模型，显然很烧钱。我觉得，正如 Nikita 所说，
I think, you know, to Nikita's point,
我觉得，正如 Nikita 所说，
I think, you know, to Nikita's point, there's a definitely hardware is is a
我觉得，正如 Nikita 所说，硬件确实是个……
there's a definitely hardware is is a
硬件确实是个……
there's a definitely hardware is is a big challenge. I think there there's
硬件确实是个大挑战。我觉得还有……
big challenge. I think there there's
大挑战。我觉得还有……
big challenge. I think there there's some really cool like I I'll I'll plug
大挑战。我觉得有些很棒的东西，我想推荐……
some really cool like I I'll I'll plug
有些很棒的东西，我想推荐……
some really cool like I I'll I'll plug Unslo because like Daniel and Michael
有些很棒的东西，我想推荐 Unslo，因为 Daniel 和 Michael……
Unslo because like Daniel and Michael
Unslo，因为 Daniel 和 Michael……
Unslo because like Daniel and Michael are really great and they have a great
Unslo，因为 Daniel 和 Michael 很出色，他们还有一个很棒的……
are really great and they have a great
真的很棒，而且他们有很好的……
are really great and they have a great ecosystem. They have great tools. Uh you
真的很棒，生态和工具都很出色。你……
ecosystem. They have great tools. Uh you
生态和工具都很出色。你……
ecosystem. They have great tools. Uh you could basically pick out, you know, open
生态和工具都很出色。你基本上可以挑选开源……
could basically pick out, you know, open
你基本上可以挑选开源……
could basically pick out, you know, open source models and you can use unsloth
你基本上可以挑选开源模型，再用 Unsloth
source models and you can use unsloth
开源模型，再用 Unsloth
source models and you can use unsloth and and and kind of like do RL and and
开源模型，再用 Unsloth 做 RL 等训练
and and and kind of like do RL and and
做 RL 等训练
and and and kind of like do RL and and SFT and and be able to do it really
做 RL 和 SFT，而且可以做得很快
SFT and and be able to do it really
做 SFT，而且可以做得很快
SFT and and be able to do it really quick like quickly and cheaply. Uh even
做 SFT，速度快，成本也低，甚至……
quick like quickly and cheaply. Uh even
速度快，成本也低，甚至……
quick like quickly and cheaply. Uh even in notebooks um like there's actually a
速度快，成本也低。甚至在 Notebook 里就能做，那里有……
in notebooks um like there's actually a
在 Notebook 里就能做，那里有……
in notebooks um like there's actually a ton of examples there. So uh but like
在 Notebook 里就能做，那里还有大量示例。不过……
ton of examples there. So uh but like
那里有大量示例。不过……
ton of examples there. So uh but like creating it from scratch is like quite
那里有大量示例。不过从零开始做就相当……
creating it from scratch is like quite
从零开始做就相当……
creating it from scratch is like quite expensive u quite involved. Uh we've
从零开始做成本很高，也很费工夫。我们……
expensive u quite involved. Uh we've
成本很高，也很费工夫。我们……
expensive u quite involved. Uh we've kind of um we're we're at the point now
成本很高，也很费工夫。我们现在已经到了……
kind of um we're we're at the point now
我们现在已经到了……
kind of um we're we're at the point now as a community where it's just it's like
我们这个社区现在已经到了这样一个阶段……
as a community where it's just it's like
我们这个社区现在的情况是……
as a community where it's just it's like prohibitively expensive to to do that as
我们这个社区现在的情况是，自己做的成本高得难以承受
prohibitively expensive to to do that as
自己做的成本高得难以承受
prohibitively expensive to to do that as an individual. Um, but that said,
个人根本负担不起这个成本。不过话说回来，
an individual. Um, but that said,
个人负担不起。不过话说回来，
an individual. Um, but that said, there's a ton of great open models out
个人负担不起。不过话说回来，优秀的开放模型有很多
there's a ton of great open models out
优秀的开放模型有很多
there's a ton of great open models out there. Um, and you can play with them
优秀的开放模型有很多，你可以拿来试试
there. Um, and you can play with them
你可以拿来试试
there. Um, and you can play with them and you can customize them and you can
你可以拿来试试，也可以定制
and you can customize them and you can
你可以定制它们，还可以
and you can customize them and you can run them locally now with Olana and
你可以定制它们，现在还能用 Ollama 在本地运行
run them locally now with Olana and
现在还能用 Ollama 在本地运行
run them locally now with Olana and other platforms. Um, so I think that's
现在还能用 Ollama 等平台在本地运行。所以我觉得……
other platforms. Um, so I think that's
还有其他平台。所以我觉得……
other platforms. Um, so I think that's like um, yeah, obviously Karpath's uh,
还有其他平台。所以我觉得，当然，Karpathy 的……
like um, yeah, obviously Karpath's uh,
当然，Karpathy 的……
like um, yeah, obviously Karpath's uh, project is is super cool as well. U,
当然，Karpathy 的项目也特别酷。
project is is super cool as well. U,
那个项目也特别酷。
project is is super cool as well. U, there's a lot going on there. Um, but I
那个项目也特别酷，相关进展很多。不过我……
there's a lot going on there. Um, but I
相关进展很多。不过我……
there's a lot going on there. Um, but I wouldn't worry about training from
相关进展很多。不过我不会担心从零开始训练
wouldn't worry about training from
我不会担心从零开始训练
wouldn't worry about training from scratch because there's just a ton to
我不会担心从零开始训练，因为现在有大量现成的东西
scratch because there's just a ton to
从零开始训练没必要，因为现在有大量现成的东西
scratch because there's just a ton to build on right now. It's just readily
因为现在有大量现成的东西可以作为基础，而且很容易获取
build on right now. It's just readily
现在就能用它来开发，现成的。
build on right now. It's just readily available.
现在就能用它来开发，随时可用。
available.
随时可用。
available. >> Yeah. Awesome. Uh, I think we had one or
随时可用。对，太好了。我想我们还有一两个……
>> Yeah. Awesome. Uh, I think we had one or
对，太好了。我想我们还有一两个……
>> Yeah. Awesome. Uh, I think we had one or two more questions. Um so uh this one is
对，太好了。我想我们还有一两个问题。这个问题来自……
two more questions. Um so uh this one is
还有两个问题。这个问题来自……
two more questions. Um so uh this one is from Manukumar.
还有两个问题。这个问题来自 Manukumar。
from Manukumar.
来自 Manukumar。
from Manukumar. Uh
来自 Manukumar。呃……
Uh
呃……
Uh are there any uh Google Summer of Code
呃，有没有 Google Summer of Code……
are there any uh Google Summer of Code
有没有 Google Summer of Code……
are there any uh Google Summer of Code uh projects uh focused around PyTorch? I
有没有聚焦 PyTorch 的 Google Summer of Code 项目？我……
uh projects uh focused around PyTorch? I
有没有聚焦 PyTorch 的项目？我……
uh projects uh focused around PyTorch? I don't know if there are. Does anybody
有没有聚焦 PyTorch 的项目？我不知道有没有。有人……
don't know if there are. Does anybody
我不知道有没有。有人……
don't know if there are. Does anybody know among this group?
我不知道有没有。在座有谁知道吗？
know among this group?
在座有谁知道吗？
know among this group? >> I don't know. But that's a good idea.
在座有谁知道吗？我不知道，但这主意不错。
>> I don't know. But that's a good idea.
我不知道，但这主意不错。
>> I don't know. But that's a good idea. Like I think
我不知道，但这主意不错。我觉得……
maybe pitch a few few ideas to Google.
或许可以向 Google 提几个想法。
maybe pitch a few few ideas to Google. But like as name suggest, it's a Google
或许可以向 Google 提几个想法。不过顾名思义，这是 Google……
But like as name suggest, it's a Google
不过顾名思义，这是 Google……
But like as name suggest, it's a Google summer of code. We don't run it. So if
不过顾名思义，这是 Google Summer of Code，不是我们主办的。所以如果……
summer of code. We don't run it. So if
Google Summer of Code 不是我们主办的。所以如果……
summer of code. We don't run it. So if somebody wants to organize it, that
Google Summer of Code 不是我们主办的。如果有人愿意组织，那……
somebody wants to organize it, that
如果有人愿意组织，那……
somebody wants to organize it, that sounds great. And like
如果有人愿意组织，那就太好了。而且……
sounds great. And like
那就太好了。而且……
sounds great. And like >> yeah,
那就太好了。而且……对。
>> yeah,
对。
>> yeah, >> if somebody
对。如果有人……
>> if somebody
如果有人……
>> if somebody >> Yeah, we'll be happy to support.
如果有人……对，我们很乐意支持。
>> Yeah, we'll be happy to support.
对，我们很乐意支持。
>> Yeah, we'll be happy to support. >> Yep.
对，我们很乐意支持。没错。
>> Yep.
没错。
>> Yep. >> We should we should reach out to our uh
没错。我们应该联系一下……
>> We should we should reach out to our uh
我们应该联系一下……
>> We should we should reach out to our uh our our Google um PyTorch Foundation. Uh
我们应该联系一下 Google 和 PyTorch Foundation 那边，呃……
our our Google um PyTorch Foundation. Uh
Google 和 PyTorch Foundation 那边，呃……
our our Google um PyTorch Foundation. Uh uh
uh
呃……
uh >> there you go.
呃……对，就是这样。
>> there you go.
对，就是这样。
>> there you go. >> And see what we can help.
对，就是这样。看看我们能帮上什么忙。
>> And see what we can help.
看看我们能帮上什么忙。
>> And see what we can help. >> Exactly. Okay. Awesome. Um, Basil, were
看看我们能帮上什么忙。没错。好，太棒了。呃，Basil，你是不是……
>> Exactly. Okay. Awesome. Um, Basil, were
没错。好，太棒了。Basil，还有……
>> Exactly. Okay. Awesome. Um, Basil, were there any more questions in the in the
没错。好，太棒了。Basil，评论区还有其他问题吗？
there any more questions in the in the
还有其他问题吗？
there any more questions in the in the comments? Oh, okay. Uh, no, I think
评论区还有其他问题吗？哦，好。我想没有了。
comments? Oh, okay. Uh, no, I think
评论区吗？哦，好。我想没有了。
comments? Oh, okay. Uh, no, I think Okay. Well, yeah, this is a slightly
评论区吗？哦，好。我想没有了。好，这个问题稍有不同。
Okay. Well, yeah, this is a slightly
好，这个问题稍有不同。
Okay. Well, yeah, this is a slightly different question. With the silicon
好，这个问题稍有不同。随着芯片市场……
different question. With the silicon
这个问题稍有不同。随着芯片……
different question. With the silicon market exploding, how is PyTorch
这个问题稍有不同。随着芯片市场蓬勃发展，PyTorch 如何……
market exploding, how is PyTorch
市场蓬勃发展，PyTorch 如何……
market exploding, how is PyTorch ensuring that the XPU, you know,
市场蓬勃发展，PyTorch 如何确保 XPU……
ensuring that the XPU, you know,
如何确保 XPU……
ensuring that the XPU, you know, torch.xpu can compile and run um models
如何确保 XPU，也就是 torch.xpu，能编译和运行模型……
torch.xpu can compile and run um models
torch.xpu 能编译和运行模型……
torch.xpu can compile and run um models across Nvidia, AMD, and Intel chips with
torch.xpu 能在 Nvidia、AMD 和 Intel 芯片上编译和运行模型，且……
across Nvidia, AMD, and Intel chips with
在 Nvidia、AMD 和 Intel 芯片上，且……
across Nvidia, AMD, and Intel chips with um zero performance loss.
在 Nvidia、AMD 和 Intel 芯片上运行，且性能零损失。
um zero performance loss.
性能零损失。
um zero performance loss. Um
性能零损失。嗯。
>> I think it's a loaded question but also
我觉得这个问题有点预设前提，而且……
>> I think it's a loaded question but also like uh it's very hard to define what
我觉得这个问题有点预设前提，而且很难界定什么是……
like uh it's very hard to define what
很难界定什么是……
like uh it's very hard to define what zero component
很难界定什么是“零组件”。
zero component
零组件。
zero component >> right
零组件。对。
>> right
对。
>> right >> don't think there is any like hardware
对。我觉得没有哪种硬件……
>> don't think there is any like hardware
我觉得没有哪种硬件……
>> don't think there is any like hardware spec that you can say well this this
我觉得没有哪项硬件规格能让你说，这个……
spec that you can say well this this
规格能让你说，这个……
spec that you can say well this this piece of silicon is exactly the same as
规格能让你说，这块芯片和……
piece of silicon is exactly the same as
这块芯片和……
piece of silicon is exactly the same as another piece of silicon and also like a
这块芯片和另一块完全一样，而且……
another piece of silicon and also like a
另一块芯片，而且……
another piece of silicon and also like a pure
另一块芯片，还有纯粹的……
pure
纯粹的……
pure >> uh like a feature parity but as Andrew
纯粹的……嗯，比如功能对等。但正如 Andrew……
>> uh like a feature parity but as Andrew
嗯，比如功能对等。但正如 Andrew……
>> uh like a feature parity but as Andrew say there is CRC and there is in general
嗯，比如功能对等。但正如 Andrew 所说，有 CRC，整体上也有……
say there is CRC and there is in general
所说，有 CRC，整体上也有……
say there is CRC and there is in general and you should direct
所说，有 CRC，整体上也有……你应该直接……
and you should direct
你应该直接……
and you should direct like project experience development
你应该直接关注，比如项目体验方面的开发……
like project experience development
比如项目体验方面的开发……
like project experience development partnership with Intel which is part of
比如项目体验方面的开发，以及与 Intel 的合作。Intel 是……
partnership with Intel which is part of
与 Intel 的合作。Intel 是……
partnership with Intel which is part of the PyTorch Foundation and they doing
与 Intel 的合作。Intel 是 PyTorch 基金会的成员，他们正在……
the PyTorch Foundation and they doing
PyTorch 基金会的成员，他们正在……
the PyTorch Foundation and they doing their best and community doing their
PyTorch 基金会的成员。他们和社区都在尽全力……
their best and community doing their
他们在尽力，社区也在尽力……
their best and community doing their best and what you can do to make sure
他们和社区都在尽力；你也可以采取措施确保……
best and what you can do to make sure
你也可以采取措施确保……
best and what you can do to make sure that it is the case if you notice that
你也可以采取措施确保这一点。如果你发现……
that it is the case if you notice that
确保这一点。如果你发现……
that it is the case if you notice that something was working on your black fill
某些功能在你的 Blackwell 上能运行……
something was working on your black fill
something was working on your black fill and doesn't work on XPU please file an
某些功能在你的 Blackwell 上能运行，却无法在 XPU 上运行，请提交……
and doesn't work on XPU please file an
却无法在 XPU 上运行，请提交……
and doesn't work on XPU please file an issue and I guess there will be people
却无法在 XPU 上运行，请提交问题反馈。我想会有人……
issue and I guess there will be people
提交问题反馈。我想会有人……
issue and I guess there will be people who happy to answer if this can be
提交问题反馈。我想会有人愿意回答，看看能否……
who happy to answer if this can be
会有人愿意回答，看看能否……
who happy to answer if this can be addressed in some way but yeah like
会有人愿意回答，看看能否解决。不过，嗯……
addressed in some way but yeah like
能否解决。不过，嗯……
addressed in some way but yeah like we we want heterogeneity we want uh like
能否解决。不过，我们希望支持异构硬件，也希望……
we we want heterogeneity we want uh like
我们希望支持异构硬件，也希望……
we we want heterogeneity we want uh like models to work. We talked about torch
我们希望支持异构硬件，也希望模型能运行。我们谈到了 torch……
models to work. We talked about torch
模型能运行。我们谈到了 torch……
models to work. We talked about torch accelerate. We talked about CRCR. We
模型能运行。我们谈到了 torch accelerate，也谈到了 CRCR。我们还……
accelerate. We talked about CRCR. We
我们谈到了 torch accelerate，也谈到了 CRCR。我们还……
accelerate. We talked about CRCR. We talked a lot about like a newer romcom.
我们谈到了 torch accelerate，也谈到了 CRCR，还谈了很多新版 ROCm 的话题。
talked a lot about like a newer romcom.
还谈了很多新版 ROCm 的话题。
talked a lot about like a newer romcom. So there are lots of initiative but I
还谈了很多新版 ROCm 的话题。所以有不少举措，但我……
So there are lots of initiative but I
所以有不少举措，但我……
So there are lots of initiative but I guess zero performance loss is just
所以有不少举措，但我觉得零性能损失实在……
guess zero performance loss is just
我觉得零性能损失实在……
guess zero performance loss is just unattainable and it's also I'm not sure
我觉得零性能损失无法实现，而且我也不确定……
unattainable and it's also I'm not sure
无法实现，而且我也不确定……
unattainable and it's also I'm not sure what it means by
无法实现，而且我也不确定这是什么意思。
what it means by
这是什么意思？
what it means by >> not well defined. It's not well defined
——没有明确定义，确实没有。
>> not well defined. It's not well defined
>> not well defined. It's not well defined because different hardware performs you
——没有明确定义，因为不同硬件的表现……
because different hardware performs you
因为不同硬件的表现……
because different hardware performs you know just just behaves differently. Um
因为不同硬件的表现本来就不一样。嗯……
know just just behaves differently. Um
表现本来就不一样。嗯……
know just just behaves differently. Um and we try and give you lots of knobs
表现本来就不一样。我们也尽量提供很多调节选项……
and we try and give you lots of knobs
我们也尽量提供很多调节选项……
and we try and give you lots of knobs and lots of capabilities but uh
我们也尽量提供很多调节选项和功能，但……
and lots of capabilities but uh
还有很多功能，但……
and lots of capabilities but uh >> we try to reduce overhead with every
还有很多功能，但……——我们每次发布都努力降低开销……
>> we try to reduce overhead with every
——我们每次发布都努力降低开销……
>> we try to reduce overhead with every release like the majority of the
——我们每次发布都努力降低开销。多数版本里……
release like the majority of the
多数版本里……
release like the majority of the releases the features the kind of
多数版本里的功能，那些……
releases the features the kind of
版本里的功能，那些……
releases the features the kind of unspoken features that we don't talk
版本里的功能，那些我们没怎么提的改进……
unspoken features that we don't talk
那些我们没怎么提的改进……
unspoken features that we don't talk about is we always try to bring a little
那些我们没怎么提的改进，就是我们一直努力一点点带来的……
about is we always try to bring a little
我们总想带来一点
about is we always try to bring a little bit of performance here and there.
我们总想在各处提升一点性能。
bit of performance here and there.
在各处提升一点性能。
bit of performance here and there. >> Yeah, just to add to it I think one of
在各处提升一点性能。对，我补充一下，我觉得有个
>> Yeah, just to add to it I think one of
对，我补充一下，我觉得有个
>> Yeah, just to add to it I think one of the interesting project maybe for you to
对，我补充一下，我觉得有个项目可能值得你
the interesting project maybe for you to
有个项目可能值得你
the interesting project maybe for you to look into is VLM. This is like they run
有个项目可能值得你看看，就是 VLM。它会运行
look into is VLM. This is like they run
看看 VLM。它会运行
look into is VLM. This is like they run multiple different models on different
看看 VLM。它会在不同硬件上运行多种
multiple different models on different
在不同硬件上运行多种
multiple different models on different hardware and like as an example so you
在不同硬件上运行多种模型。举个例子，你
hardware and like as an example so you
硬件。举个例子，你
hardware and like as an example so you can explore it a little bit and I think
硬件。举个例子，你可以稍微研究一下，我觉得
can explore it a little bit and I think
可以稍微研究一下，我觉得
can explore it a little bit and I think it's open source and the CI is open
可以稍微研究一下，我觉得它是开源的，CI 也是开放的
it's open source and the CI is open
它是开源的，CI 也是开放的
it's open source and the CI is open source so um just as an example to look
它是开源的，CI 也开源。所以，这只是一个值得
source so um just as an example to look
开源。所以，这只是一个值得
source so um just as an example to look into could be interesting.
开源。所以，这只是一个值得研究的例子。
into could be interesting.
研究一下可能挺有意思。
into could be interesting. >> Um I feel like we have answered this but
研究一下可能挺有意思。嗯，我觉得我们已经回答过这个问题，不过
>> Um I feel like we have answered this but
嗯，我觉得我们已经回答过这个问题，不过
>> Um I feel like we have answered this but I'll just quickly uh just just uh shout
嗯，我觉得我们已经回答过这个问题，不过我再简单提一下
I'll just quickly uh just just uh shout
我再简单提一下
I'll just quickly uh just just uh shout it out here. So somebody asked on the on
我再简单提一下。有人在
it out here. So somebody asked on the on
这个问题。有人在
it out here. So somebody asked on the on the comment thread um is it uh is
这个问题。有人在评论区问，
the comment thread um is it uh is
评论区问，
the comment thread um is it uh is PyTorch supporting the newest CUDA? I
评论区问，PyTorch 支持最新的 CUDA 吗？我
PyTorch supporting the newest CUDA? I
PyTorch 支持最新的 CUDA 吗？我
PyTorch supporting the newest CUDA? I think we're we're either on the newest
PyTorch 支持最新的 CUDA 吗？我想我们用的要么是最新版
think we're we're either on the newest
我想我们用的要么是最新版
think we're we're either on the newest CUDA or pretty close. And usually if you
我想我们用的要么是最新版 CUDA，要么非常接近。通常，如果你
CUDA or pretty close. And usually if you
CUDA，要么非常接近。通常，如果你
CUDA or pretty close. And usually if you jump on nightlys, you can get the latest
CUDA，要么非常接近。通常，如果你用每日构建版，就能用上最新的
jump on nightlys, you can get the latest
用每日构建版，就能用上最新的
jump on nightlys, you can get the latest and greatest.
用每日构建版，就能用上最新的功能。
and greatest.
最新的功能。
and greatest. >> Um, so Andre, you should your head when
最新的功能。嗯，Andre，我刚才说的时候，你摇了摇头
>> Um, so Andre, you should your head when
嗯，Andre，我刚才说的时候，你摇了摇头
>> Um, so Andre, you should your head when I said that. So I must have said
嗯，Andre，我刚才说的时候，你摇了摇头。所以我一定是说错了
I said that. So I must have said
所以我一定是说错了
I said that. So I must have said something slightly wrong. So jump in
所以我一定是说错了点什么。你来
something slightly wrong. So jump in
说错了点什么。你来
something slightly wrong. So jump in here and correct me.
说错了点什么。你来纠正我吧。
here and correct me.
来纠正我吧。
here and correct me. >> So for 214, we're supporting up to CUDA
来纠正我吧。关于 214，我们最高支持到 CUDA
>> So for 214, we're supporting up to CUDA
关于 214，我们最高支持到 CUDA
>> So for 214, we're supporting up to CUDA 13.2. This is not the latest. The latest
关于 214，我们最高支持到 CUDA 13.2。这不是最新版本。最新的是
13.2. This is not the latest. The latest
13.2。这个不是最新版。最新版是……
13.2. This is not the latest. The latest was um is 13.4 and it was released just
13.2。这个不是最新版。最新版是 13.4，刚发布不久……
was um is 13.4 and it was released just
是 13.4，刚发布不久……
was um is 13.4 and it was released just like a week after we released PyTorch.
是 13.4，在我们发布 PyTorch 大约一周后发布的。
like a week after we released PyTorch.
大约在我们发布 PyTorch 一周后。
like a week after we released PyTorch. So it's like we did not include it yet
大约在我们发布 PyTorch 一周后。所以我们还没把它加进去。
So it's like we did not include it yet
所以我们还没把它加进去。
So it's like we did not include it yet but it will be included in the next
所以我们还没把它加进去，但下一个版本会包含它。
but it will be included in the next
但下一个版本会包含它。
but it will be included in the next release of PyTorch and it is already in
但下一个 PyTorch 版本会包含它，而且它已经在……
release of PyTorch and it is already in
下一个 PyTorch 版本，而且它已经在……
release of PyTorch and it is already in nightly and it has been in nightly for
下一个 PyTorch 版本，而且它已经进入 nightly 版，已经有……
nightly and it has been in nightly for
nightly 版，而且已经在里面有……
nightly and it has been in nightly for quite some time. So if you really want
nightly 版，而且已经有一段时间了。所以如果你真想……
quite some time. So if you really want
已经有一段时间了。所以如果你真想……
quite some time. So if you really want to have the latest CUDA download nightly
已经有一段时间了。所以如果你想用最新的 CUDA，就下载 nightly 版。
to have the latest CUDA download nightly
想用最新的 CUDA，就下载 nightly 版。
to have the latest CUDA download nightly and it should work uh for Linux only for
想用最新的 CUDA，就下载 nightly 版。它应该能用，目前只支持 Linux；至于……
and it should work uh for Linux only for
它应该能用，目前只支持 Linux；至于……
and it should work uh for Linux only for Windows I think it's going to be enabled
它应该能用，目前只支持 Linux；Windows 我想很快也会支持。
Windows I think it's going to be enabled
Windows 我想很快也会支持。
Windows I think it's going to be enabled pretty soon maybe within one or two
Windows 我想很快也会支持，可能再过一两……
pretty soon maybe within one or two
可能再过一两……
pretty soon maybe within one or two weeks.
可能再过一两周。
>> Awesome. Well I think that was a good
>> 太好了。我觉得这很适合……
>> Awesome. Well I think that was a good note to end on. Um, I think we had uh
太好了。我觉得用这句话收尾挺好。嗯，我觉得我们……
note to end on. Um, I think we had uh
用这句话收尾挺好。嗯，我觉得我们……
note to end on. Um, I think we had uh some fun conver fun conversation.
用这句话收尾挺好。嗯，我觉得我们聊得很愉快。
some fun conver fun conversation.
聊得很愉快。
some fun conver fun conversation. [snorts]
聊得很愉快。［哼笑］
[snorts]
［哼笑］
[snorts] Um, a little a little repetition in the
［哼笑］嗯，问题有一点……
Um, a little a little repetition in the
嗯，问题有一点……
Um, a little a little repetition in the questions, but I think that's sort of
嗯，问题有一点重复，但我觉得这算是……
questions, but I think that's sort of
问题有一点重复，但我觉得这算是……
questions, but I think that's sort of built into the way we do things. So,
问题有一点重复，但这和我们的做法有关。所以，
built into the way we do things. So,
这和我们的做法有关。所以，
built into the way we do things. So, thank you uh to my experts for uh for
这和我们的做法有关。所以，感谢几位专家……
thank you uh to my experts for uh for
感谢几位专家……
thank you uh to my experts for uh for for putting up with that. Um, uh, so
感谢几位专家包容这些重复。嗯，那么……
for putting up with that. Um, uh, so
感谢你们包容这些重复。嗯，那么……
for putting up with that. Um, uh, so let's uh just in terms of closing
感谢你们包容这些重复。嗯，那么最后……
let's uh just in terms of closing
那么最后……
let's uh just in terms of closing remarks, um, thanks as always have to
那么最后说几句。和往常一样，先要感谢……
remarks, um, thanks as always have to
说几句。和往常一样，先要感谢……
remarks, um, thanks as always have to start with the contributors across the
说几句。和往常一样，先要感谢社区里的贡献者……
start with the contributors across the
先要感谢社区里的贡献者……
start with the contributors across the community who put in the steady effort
先要感谢社区里持续付出的贡献者……
community who put in the steady effort
社区里持续付出的贡献者……
community who put in the steady effort that makes PyTorch what it is. So 500
社区里持续付出的贡献者，是他们成就了今天的 PyTorch。所以，500……
that makes PyTorch what it is. So 500
正是这些成就了今天的 PyTorch。所以，500……
that makes PyTorch what it is. So 500 odd people uh contributed to this uh
正是这些成就了今天的 PyTorch。这次版本有 500 多人参与贡献。
odd people uh contributed to this uh
多人参与了这次版本的开发。
odd people uh contributed to this uh particular release and it's been a
多人参与了这次版本的开发，而这个数字……
particular release and it's been a
这次版本的开发，而这个数字……
particular release and it's been a number near that for the last several
这次版本的开发，过去几次也差不多是这个人数。
number near that for the last several
过去几次也差不多是这个人数。
number near that for the last several releases. Uh so it's just huge community
过去几次发布也是这个人数。这是庞大的社区共同努力的结果。
releases. Uh so it's just huge community
过去几次发布也是如此。这是庞大的社区共同努力的结果。
releases. Uh so it's just huge community effort. Uh and you know what we're
每次发布都凝聚了庞大社区的努力。我们……
effort. Uh and you know what we're
共同的努力。我们……
effort. Uh and you know what we're talking about here is that effort. Uh so
共同的努力。我们今天谈的正是这些努力。所以……
talking about here is that effort. Uh so
我们今天谈的正是这些努力。所以……
talking about here is that effort. Uh so uh so thanks to all those folks. Uh
我们今天谈的正是这些努力。感谢所有参与的人。
uh so thanks to all those folks. Uh
感谢所有参与的人。
uh so thanks to all those folks. Uh thanks also to the three of you uh here
感谢所有参与的人，也谢谢在场的三位。
thanks also to the three of you uh here
也谢谢在场的三位。
thanks also to the three of you uh here on on on on stage answering these
也谢谢台上的三位回答这些……
on on on on stage answering these
在台上回答这些……
on on on on stage answering these questions. Uh many of which you were
在台上回答这些问题，其中很多问题你们……
questions. Uh many of which you were
这些问题，其中很多问题你们……
questions. Uh many of which you were answering un completely unprepared
这些问题，其中很多是你们毫无准备就回答的。
answering un completely unprepared
你们毫无准备就作了回答。
answering un completely unprepared because they they were audience
你们毫无准备就作了回答，因为那都是观众……
because they they were audience
因为那都是观众……
because they they were audience questions [laughter] in. So, thank you
因为那都是观众提的问题（笑）。所以，谢谢……
questions [laughter] in. So, thank you
观众提的问题（笑）。所以，谢谢……
questions [laughter] in. So, thank you for being brave uh and wise. Um so, uh
观众提的问题（笑）。谢谢你们的勇气和智慧。
for being brave uh and wise. Um so, uh
谢谢你们的勇气和智慧。
for being brave uh and wise. Um so, uh and being generous with your time and
谢谢你们的勇气和智慧，也谢谢你们慷慨地分享时间和……
and being generous with your time and
也谢谢你们慷慨地分享时间和……
and being generous with your time and your expertise. Uh thanks also to behind
也谢谢你们慷慨地分享时间和专业知识。还要感谢幕后的……
your expertise. Uh thanks also to behind
专业知识。还要感谢幕后的……
your expertise. Uh thanks also to behind the scenes uh Basil and Jyn who were
专业知识。还要感谢幕后的 Basil 和 Jyn，他们……
the scenes uh Basil and Jyn who were
幕后的 Basil 和 Jyn，他们……
the scenes uh Basil and Jyn who were scrambling to to get the uh the the
幕后的 Basil 和 Jyn 一直忙着把……
scrambling to to get the uh the the
一直忙着把……
scrambling to to get the uh the the questions uh from the from the
一直忙着把讨论区里的问题……
questions uh from the from the
讨论区里的问题……
questions uh from the from the discussion thread into uh into uh the
把讨论区里的问题搬到……
discussion thread into uh into uh the
从讨论区搬到……
discussion thread into uh into uh the screen here. So, thank you guys for
把讨论区里的问题搬到这里的屏幕上。谢谢你们。
screen here. So, thank you guys for
搬到这里的屏幕上。谢谢你们。
screen here. So, thank you guys for working your magic. I appreciate that.
搬到这里的屏幕上。谢谢你们大显身手，真的很感激。
working your magic. I appreciate that.
谢谢你们大显身手，真的很感激。
working your magic. I appreciate that. Uh and then also thanks to everybody who
谢谢你们大显身手，真的很感激。也感谢所有……
Uh and then also thanks to everybody who
也感谢所有……
Uh and then also thanks to everybody who joined and asked questions because you
也感谢所有参与并提问的人，因为你们……
joined and asked questions because you
参与并提问的人，因为你们……
joined and asked questions because you made this a good conversation. Uh we
参与并提问的人，因为你们让这场交流如此精彩。我们……
made this a good conversation. Uh we
让这次交流很精彩。我们
made this a good conversation. Uh we really appreciate it and keep building
让这次交流很精彩。我们非常感谢，也请继续用 PyTorch 创造
really appreciate it and keep building
非常感谢，也请继续创造
really appreciate it and keep building awesome things with PyTorch. Uh just a
非常感谢，也请继续用 PyTorch 创造精彩的作品。还有
awesome things with PyTorch. Uh just a
用 PyTorch 创造精彩的作品。还有
awesome things with PyTorch. Uh just a couple of resources uh for you to think
用 PyTorch 创造精彩的作品。结束前还有几个资源供大家参考
couple of resources uh for you to think
还有几个资源供大家参考
couple of resources uh for you to think about um a as we wrap up here. Um there
结束前还有几个资源供大家参考
about um a as we wrap up here. Um there
结束前还有
about um a as we wrap up here. Um there are we released a blog with this release
结束前还有：我们随这次发布推出了一篇博客
are we released a blog with this release
我们随这次发布推出了一篇博客
are we released a blog with this release uh which has a lot of detailed uh
我们随这次发布推出了一篇博客，里面有很多详细内容
uh which has a lot of detailed uh
里面有很多详细内容
uh which has a lot of detailed uh details about the various different
里面详细介绍了各种
details about the various different
各种功能的细节
details about the various different features. There's also the release
各种功能的细节。还有发布说明
features. There's also the release
还有发布说明
features. There's also the release notes. You should be able to find both
还有发布说明。这两份资料应该都很容易找到
notes. You should be able to find both
这两份资料应该都很容易找到
notes. You should be able to find both of those really easily. We may drop
这两份资料应该都很容易找到。我们也许会附上
of those really easily. We may drop
这两份资料很容易找到。我们也许会附上
of those really easily. We may drop links to them here. I'm not I'm not sure
我们也许会在这里放上链接，我不太确定
links to them here. I'm not I'm not sure
这里的链接。我不太确定
links to them here. I'm not I'm not sure whether that will happen or not. Um also
这里的链接。我不确定会不会放。另外
whether that will happen or not. Um also
会不会放。另外
whether that will happen or not. Um also the developer communities. So
会不会放。另外还有开发者社区
the developer communities. So
开发者社区，比如
the developer communities. So discuss.pyarch.org
开发者社区，比如 discuss.pyarch.org
discuss.pyarch.org
社区网站 discuss.pyarch.org
discuss.pyarch.org and devdiscuss.pyrush.org
discuss.pyarch.org 和 devdiscuss.pyrush.org 这两个社区
and devdiscuss.pyrush.org
以及 devdiscuss.pyrush.org 社区
and devdiscuss.pyrush.org are great uh for asking really detailed
devdiscuss.pyrush.org 也很适合提出具体问题
are great uh for asking really detailed
很适合提出具体问题
are great uh for asking really detailed questions like you guys uh did here. Um
很适合提出像大家刚才那样具体的问题
questions like you guys uh did here. Um
像大家刚才提出的那些具体问题
questions like you guys uh did here. Um and you'll you'll you'll be able to get
像大家刚才提出的那些具体问题，也会有人
and you'll you'll you'll be able to get
也会有人来解答
and you'll you'll you'll be able to get the the the experts uh um across the
也会有社区里的专家
the the the experts uh um across the
社区里的专家
the the the experts uh um across the community to answer. Um also there's
社区里的专家来解答。另外还有
community to answer. Um also there's
专家来解答。另外还有
community to answer. Um also there's some events coming up that I want to
专家来解答。另外还有一些即将举行的活动
some events coming up that I want to
一些即将举行的活动
some events coming up that I want to make people aware of. Uh so PyTorch
还有一些即将举行的活动，想告诉大家。PyTorch
make people aware of. Uh so PyTorch
想告诉大家。PyTorch
make people aware of. Uh so PyTorch Conference North America will be in San
想告诉大家，PyTorch 北美大会将在圣何塞举行
Conference North America will be in San
PyTorch 北美大会将在圣何塞举行
Conference North America will be in San Jose in just a little bit more than a
北美大会将在圣何塞举行，距今只有一个多月
Jose in just a little bit more than a
圣何塞，距今只有一个多月
Jose in just a little bit more than a month. Um so that's October 20th and
圣何塞，距今只有一个多月。时间是 10 月 20 日和
month. Um so that's October 20th and
这个月。嗯，就是10月20日和
month. Um so that's October 20th and 21st. I think all of us will be here.
这个月。嗯，就是10月20日和21日。我想我们都会到场。
21st. I think all of us will be here.
21日。我想我们都会到场。
21st. I think all of us will be here. All of us here will be will be there. Um
21日。我想我们都会到场。我们在座的都会去。
All of us here will be will be there. Um
我们在座的都会去。
All of us here will be will be there. Um and um uh you know it's a great chance
我们在座的都会去。这是个很好的机会。
and um uh you know it's a great chance
这是个很好的机会。
and um uh you know it's a great chance to to to learn a ton about PyTorch and
这是个深入了解PyTorch的好机会，还能
to to to learn a ton about PyTorch and
深入了解PyTorch，还能
to to to learn a ton about PyTorch and say hello to to to fellow uh uh members
深入了解PyTorch，还能和社区伙伴打招呼。
say hello to to to fellow uh uh members
和社区伙伴打招呼。
say hello to to to fellow uh uh members of the community. Um I'm certainly
和社区伙伴打招呼。嗯，我当然
of the community. Um I'm certainly
社区里的伙伴。嗯，我当然
of the community. Um I'm certainly looking forward to it and if you're um
社区里的伙伴。嗯，我当然很期待。如果你是
looking forward to it and if you're um
很期待。如果你是
looking forward to it and if you're um part of the global audience um there are
很期待。如果你是全球观众，
part of the global audience um there are
全球观众，
part of the global audience um there are a bunch of PyTorch, you know, we've been
全球观众，各地还有不少PyTorch活动，我们一直在
a bunch of PyTorch, you know, we've been
各地还有不少PyTorch活动，我们一直在
a bunch of PyTorch, you know, we've been really proliferating uh global events uh
各地还有不少PyTorch活动，我们一直在全球举办越来越多的活动。
really proliferating uh global events uh
在全球举办越来越多的活动。
really proliferating uh global events uh this year and I imagine that will
今年我们在全球举办了越来越多的活动，我想这还会
this year and I imagine that will
今年，我想这还会
this year and I imagine that will continue. Uh so we had an event in Paris
今年，我想这还会继续。春天我们在巴黎办过一场活动，
continue. Uh so we had an event in Paris
这还会继续。春天我们在巴黎办过一场活动，
continue. Uh so we had an event in Paris in the spring which was a lot of fun. We
这还会继续。春天我们在巴黎办过一场活动，很有意思。我们
in the spring which was a lot of fun. We
春天在巴黎办的活动很有意思。我们
in the spring which was a lot of fun. We just completed events uh well a while
春天在巴黎办的活动很有意思。我们前段时间还办了几场活动，
just completed events uh well a while
我们前段时间还办了几场活动，
just completed events uh well a while ago in India and then more recently in
我们前段时间在印度办了活动，后来又在
ago in India and then more recently in
前段时间在印度，后来又在
ago in India and then more recently in China and I think we have one planned in
前段时间在印度、最近在中国办了活动。我想我们还计划在
China and I think we have one planned in
在中国办了活动。我想我们还计划在
China and I think we have one planned in Japan for later this year. So um and
在中国办了活动。我想我们还计划今年晚些时候在日本办一场。另外，
Japan for later this year. So um and
今年晚些时候在日本办一场。另外，
Japan for later this year. So um and then I think there are pie days and
今年晚些时候在日本办一场。另外，我想还有PyDays和
then I think there are pie days and
另外，我想还有PyDays和
then I think there are pie days and smaller events happening all the time in
另外，我想还有PyDays和小型活动，不断在
smaller events happening all the time in
小型活动不断在
smaller events happening all the time in lots of different places. So uh look
小型活动不断在各地举办。所以，去
lots of different places. So uh look
各地举办。所以，去
lots of different places. So uh look look at the piece.org website for uh for
各地举办。所以，去piece.org网站看看
look at the piece.org website for uh for
去piece.org网站看看
look at the piece.org website for uh for u events near you. So I think that's it
去piece.org网站查看你附近的活动。我想就这些。
u events near you. So I think that's it
你附近的活动。我想就这些。
u events near you. So I think that's it >> and last but no there is one more thing
你附近的活动。我想就这些。最后……不对，还有一件事。
>> and last but no there is one more thing
最后……不对，还有一件事。
>> and last but no there is one more thing last but not least thank you very much
最后……不对，还有一件事。最后，非常感谢
last but not least thank you very much
最后，非常感谢
last but not least thank you very much Chris for being a fantastic moderator.
最后，非常感谢Chris出色地主持了节目。
Chris for being a fantastic moderator.
感谢 Chris 担任出色的主持人。
Chris for being a fantastic moderator. We could not have wished for a better
感谢 Chris 担任出色的主持人。我们找不到更好的
We could not have wished for a better
我们找不到更好的
We could not have wished for a better moderator here and without you it would
我们找不到更好的主持人，没有你，这场活动就会
moderator here and without you it would
主持人，没有你，这场活动就会
moderator here and without you it would be a very different event. So, thank
主持人，没有你，这场活动就会大不一样。所以，感谢
be a very different event. So, thank
大不一样。所以，感谢
be a very different event. So, thank you.
大不一样。所以，谢谢你。
you.
谢谢你。
you. >> Thank you, Chris. Great job.
谢谢你。>> 谢谢你，Chris。做得真棒。
>> Thank you, Chris. Great job.
>> 谢谢你，Chris。做得真棒。
>> Thank you, Chris. Great job. >> Bye-bye.
>> 谢谢你，Chris。做得真棒。>> 再见。
>> Bye-bye.
>> 再见。
>> Bye-bye. >> Thank you.
>> 再见。>> 谢谢。